<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>合作基金</title><description>Collab Fund 是企业家推动世界前进的主要资金来源。</description><link/> https://collabfund.com<atom:link href="https://collabfund.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 08:55:02 -0400</pubDate><lastbuilddate> 2023 年 10 月 23 日星期一 08:55:02 -0400</lastbuilddate><generator>站点叶</generator><item><title>团队建设</title><description>&lt;p>;胜利是由团队完成的，我现在对协作基金的团队感到非常兴奋。两周前我们在纽约聚会。这是一场混乱。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们迎来了几位跨核心职能部门的新员工，包括投资、运营和我们的平台团队。看到 Collaborative 中的人才团结在一起真是太酷了。这体现了我们所有人都应该兴奋的使命的共鸣，也体现了我为之自豪的支持后起之秀的记录。最重要的是，这些新团队成员带来的广泛经验和观点将使我们能够更好地为我们的创始人和投资者提供未来服务。介绍完毕后，我们深入讨论了基金业绩、如何更好地支持我们不断增长的投资组合以及新兴的兴趣领域。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/a1. png&quot; alt=&quot;a1.png&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们会议的一些亮点包括：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;- 新兴的拉丁美洲创业生态系统&lt;/strong>; - 我们就我们如何最好地帮助这个快速增长地区的创始人进行了富有洞察力的讨论。我们很高兴能够继续发展与当地合作伙伴的关系，获得文化熟练程度，并为创始人提供长期支持。就背景而言，在过去 18 个月中，我们投资了该地区的许多初创公司，包括：&lt;strong>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mercadodiferente.com.br/&quot;>;Diferente&lt;/a >;&lt;/strong>;、&lt;strong>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://kanastra.com.br/en/&quot;>;喀纳斯特拉&lt;/a>;&lt;/strong>;、&lt;strong>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// ruuf.cl/&quot;>;Ruuf Solar&lt;/a>;&lt;/strong>;、&lt;strong>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.soyplenna.com/&quot;>;Plenna&lt;/a>;&lt;/strong>; 和 &lt;strong>; >;&lt;a href=&quot;https://fu.do/es/&quot;>;Fu.do&lt;/a>;&lt;/strong>;。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/ uploads/b1.png&quot; alt=&quot;b1.png&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;- 地热能令人兴奋的潜力&lt;/strong>; - 我们探索了地热技术如何能够实现永远在线、清洁的能源基荷发电。然而，我们也认识到，要实现地热的全部前景，需要有效的政策倡导和愿意支持长期投资的耐心资金。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;- GLP-1 药物如何改变行为&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;- GLP-1 药物如何改变行为&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;- GLP-1 药物如何改变行为我们对未来进行了一次发人深省的讨论，未来这些类型的药物不仅可以治疗糖尿病，还可能更广泛地影响饮食和生活方式的选择。精准医疗的未来能力看起来既极其复杂，又充满希望。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在我们的战略会议结束后，我们参观了&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.royalpalmsbrooklyn.com/&quot;>;皇家棕榈沙狐球俱乐部&lt; /a>; - 一个很棒的地方（带来&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/948151585/bring-shuffleboard-back-to-brooklyn-on-its-100th-a&quot;>;生活&lt; /a>; 部分由 Collab Fund 投资组合公司 Kickstarter 提供），并享受了一些不错的老游戏和美味的食物。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/c1.png&quot; alt=&quot;c1.png&quot; />;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;这次聚会使我们的目标更加明确，并对我们所有杰出的同事表示赞赏。在一个似乎每天都在加速变化的世界中，像这样定期聚集在一起制定战略并调整引人注目的机会对于我们继续推动风险投资走向未来绝对至关重要。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;前进！&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 08:59:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/teambuilding/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/teambuilding/</guid></item><item><title>致富的几条法则</title><description>&lt;p>;全球10位最富有的人中有13人离婚。前十名中的七人至少离婚过一次。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;相关性不是因果关系，而且样本量很小。但是，在一个生活被很多人羡慕的群体中，在一个对幸福如此重要的话题上，一个比全国平均水平差得多的统计数据很有趣，不是吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有一个致富的方式有数百万种，其中大多数涉及利用特定的利基市场和一次性机会，更不用说运气了。关于如何致富的普遍规则很难找到。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是赔钱，或者在有钱的时候失去幸福，或者成为金钱的奴隶——这些故事往往有共同点。它们非常常见，您可以将其称为法律。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;衡量财富很容易。你只要数一下就可以了。衡量财富的一些负面影响要困难得多，也更加微妙。它们是如此微妙且难以衡量，以至于许多人甚至不相信它们的存在。财富的&lt;em>;缺点&lt;/em>;？这怎么可能？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;让我提出，谈论财富的负面影响是荒谬的，这也是为什么财富并不能让人们像他们想象的那样幸福的部分原因。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当金钱的好处如此明显，但缺点又如此微妙时，你没有预料到的缺点可能比你预期的好处更令人震惊。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，我想要更多的钱。几乎每个人都这样做，尽管出于不同的原因。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这不是一份反财富清单——只是一系列容易被忽视的微妙缺点，而且如此常见，你不妨称它们为唯一真正的法则致富。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;1.生活中大部分让你快乐的事情与金钱无关，意识到一旦你有钱可能是一个痛苦的承认。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;威尔·史密斯在他的传记中写道，当他很穷的时候&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一旦他变得富有，这种乐观情绪就消失了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他有”郁闷直到你的梦想成真。一旦你的梦想成真，你意识到你的感觉和以前一样，你就会感到绝望。&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;幸福很复杂，但如果你把它简化成一个充满爱的家庭这样的事情、健康、友谊、八小时睡眠、平衡的孩子，以及成为比你自己更大的事情的一部分，你就会意识到金钱的作用是多么有限。并不是说它没有作用；而是它没有作用。只是比你想象的要小。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这样想：你愿意每年赚 10 万美元，有一个爱你的配偶、钦佩你的孩子、好朋友、身体健康、问心无愧吗？ ，或者赚了 1,000,000 美元却什么都没有？这是很明显的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，你可以贫穷而痛苦，也可以富有而快乐。但只有富人知道这种关系有多么脆弱。赚钱可能并不能改善你的婚姻，它不能让你的朋友更喜欢你，也不能让你更满足。因此，曾经对金钱可以为你做的令人安慰的乐观情绪，现在被金钱不能为你做的严酷现实所取代。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有时，梦想是感觉良好的，一旦你实现了它，梦想消失了，你实际上变得沮丧。 Malcolm Forbes：当我们成功时，我们已经拥有了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;2.你所认为的对自己成功的钦佩实际上可能是嫉妒。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;说唱歌手德雷克曾经说过，“人们更喜欢你在为某件事而努力的时候，而不是当你拥有它的时候。”&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;很难判断这种转变何时发生，富人通常认为自己受到钦佩，但实际上却受到嫉妒。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作者罗伯特·格林 (Robert Greene) 曾经写道： &lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;永远不要愚蠢地相信你通过炫耀使你超越他人的品质来激起钦佩。通过让别人意识到自己的劣势，你只会激起不愉快的钦佩或嫉妒，这会侵蚀他们，直到他们以你无法预见的方式削弱你。&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;这尤其重要当你致富的原因是通过某种形式宣传你的成功，让其他人愿意帮助和支持你时，情况确实如此。当钦佩变成嫉妒时，支持就会减少，人们对你的错误的容忍度就会减少。如果一位无名记者写了一本书间接地为萨姆·班克曼-弗里德辩护，没有人会在意——他们实际上可能会祝贺作者。但自从迈克尔·刘易斯做到了，干草叉就出现了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;梭罗说，“嫉妒是所有区别都必须缴纳的税。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;3。你越富有，当你犯错、疯狂、刻薄或健忘时，周围的人就越不可能告诉你。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;马特·达蒙 (Matt Damon) 说，“你在社交和情感上阻碍了别人的发展。”你成名的那一刻。你对世界的体验永远不会一样。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于那些变得富有的人来说，同样的情况可能也是如此，而且更为普遍。没有人会以同样的方式对待你。最糟糕的是你可能根本不知道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;艺术家达米安·赫斯特 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.idler.co.uk/article/interview-damien-hirst/&quot;>;曾经说过&lt;/a>;：&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;他们都爱你。银行爱你，会计师也爱你，因为他们拿走了你的钱。每年你都会有越来越多的人。一个人拿走 10%，然后另一个人拿走 10%，另一个人拿走 10%，这就是一场盛大的聚会。给你透支的人也是你最好的朋友，他们对你微笑，告诉你你很了不起，所以你就继续这样做。&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;有时人们是故意利用你的，从你身上榨取一些好处。其他时候，他们不应该认真对待你。泡沫的一个大问题是财富和智慧之间的反射性关联，所以一堆疯狂的想法因为一个暂时富有的人说出来而被认真对待。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;巴菲特曾经解释过：&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;当我二十一岁时，我最擅长提供财务建议，但人们不听我的。我本可以站起来说出最精彩的话，但不会受到太多关注。现在可以说出世界上最愚蠢的事情，相当多的人会认为其中有一些伟大的隐藏意义或其他东西。&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;4。有时让你成功的是担忧和焦虑，当你富有时你就无法摆脱它。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我认为很多人真正想要从金钱中得到的是能够停止的能力想着钱。有了足够的钱，他们就可以不再思考这个问题，而专注于其他事情。这是一种奇怪的关系：他们沉迷于赚钱，希望有一天他们可以完全忽视它。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种痴迷是由压力和焦虑助长的。它通常表现为职业抱负、积极投资和 A 型动机。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然后，一旦他们变得富有，他们就会意识到自己无法摆脱这种压力。这已经在他们的身份中根深蒂固。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他们每周工作 80 小时，因为他们希望最终根本不需要工作。但是，一旦他们有足够的钱退休，他们就无法削减开支，因为他们不知道除了工作之外还能做生活中的其他事情。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我采访过的很多理财规划师都说：他们最大的挑战之一是让客户在退休后花钱。即使是适当的、保守的金额。节俭和储蓄成为某些人身份的重要组成部分，以至于他们永远无法改变态度。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我认为对某些人来说这实际上很好。看着金钱复合给他们带来的快乐比花钱时更多。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但那些最终目标是停止思考金钱的人却陷入了困境。拒绝承认自己已经实现了目标可能与从一开始就没有实现目标一样糟糕。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;5.管理财富和孩子没有简单的方法。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;查理·芒格的一位富有的朋友曾经问查理·芒格，给他的孩子留下一大笔钱是否会毁掉他们的动力和抱负。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; p>; &lt;p>;“当然会的，”查理说。 “但你还是必须这么做。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“为什么？”朋友问。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“因为如果你不给他们钱，他们就会恨你，”查理说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;就像芒格的很多建议一样，我认为这种互动旨在令人难忘。这可能有 80% 是正确的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但总的来说，他是对的。对于富人来说，这是两个选择：通过继承来毁掉他们的野心，或者冒着某种形式的冲突的风险，剥夺他们的安逸生活。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沃伦·巴菲特曾经说过，他经常听到富人谈论财富是多么危险。福利社会正在造就一代依赖食品券和失业救济金的食客。但他说，“这些人给他们的孩子留下了终生可用的食品券等等”。 “他们没有福利官员，而是信托基金官员。他们没有食品券，而是支付股息的股票和债券。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然也有例外。但大多数例外——继承金钱的富家子弟并不会影响他们的野心——是因为孩子很特别，而不是因为父母一定做出了明智的决定。即使18岁的比尔盖茨继承了10亿美元，也不会阻止他的野心。史蒂夫·乔布斯和埃隆·马斯克也是如此。马克·扎克伯格 (Mark Zuckerberg) 22 岁时有人向他提供 10 亿美元现金收购 Facebook，但他没有眨眼，甚至没有考虑过。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但这些都是稀有鸟。大多数人都需要害怕无法成功。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我的朋友 Chris Davis &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3GTpG8ePCaw&amp;amp;ab_channel=TheCompound&quot;>;在一个富裕的家庭长大&lt;/a>; - 他的祖父是传奇投资家谢尔比·戴维斯 (Shelby Davis)，他将 5 万美元变成了近 10 亿美元 - 在他年轻的时候，他被告知他不会看到其中的一分钱，因为他的家人没有想要剥夺他独立自主的机会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;克里斯开玩笑说：“他们本来可以剥夺我&lt;em>;一点点&lt;/em>;。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是从来都不容易。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;6。快速的财富是脆弱的财富。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我喜欢这样的想法：你创造财富的速度就是你失去财富的速度的半衰期。一年内你的钱翻倍？当您以同样的速度失去一半时，请不要感到惊讶。闪电式扩张？闪电战失败了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;快速而脆弱的财富会发生两件事。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一是来得容易的钱往往也容易花掉。当钱来得快的时候，把钱花在无意义的事情上的情感成本就很低。只有当某件事对你来说很珍贵时，你才会小心翼翼。花掉你没有投入太多时间或精力来赚钱的快钱感觉就像是一夜情：冲动且容易后悔。老钱想要避税，新钱想要一辆兰博基尼。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一个是，财富创造得越​​快，运气带来的机会也就越快恢复。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;将这两者放在一起，每当你看到快速财富激增时（2021 年的加密货币就是一个很好的例子），你就知道它的结局将会很糟糕，因为运气会转化为风险，炫耀性消费会转化为不起眼的生活方式债务。&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;7.声誉具有双向动力，因为人们希望与成功者交往，避免失败者。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;你越成功，就越多的人愿意与你交往 - 这很好。&lt;/p>; >; &lt;p>;但这反过来也同样有效。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;职业生涯早期的人可能会搞砸，但很快就会恢复过来，进入下一家公司。一个成功的个人或公司的每一个缺陷都会在新闻中大肆宣扬，充斥着他们网络的八卦频道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;雷曼兄弟 2008 年的困境成为全国新闻头条；一家小型社区银行可能已经陷入了束手无策的境地，几乎没有任何灵魂的意识。 、商贩——想与它联系在一起。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这就像俗话说的，“猴子爬得越高，你就越能看到它的屁股。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong >;8.预期的上升速度可能快于收入的上升速度，因此较高的收入会使预期失控。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;财富是相对的。奢华是相对的。两者都只是你所拥有的和其他人所拥有的之间的比较。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我多次看到的一个怪癖是，一些最富有的人最容易出现失控的期望，因为他们变得非常了解其他富人的生活方式。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1907 年，作家威廉·道森 (William Dawson) 写到了财富感与你习惯的生活之间的关系：&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;A一个习惯于安逸生活的受过教育的人，如果被迫住在人口稠密、肮脏的公寓的一间单间里，并不得不靠微薄而又不稳定的工资维持生计，他将遭受难以言表的折磨。他会因为那些快乐的事情的记忆而受到折磨，我们被告知这是“悲伤之冠”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是，一个不知道其他生活状况的人不会意识到它的痛苦。他没有比较的标准。一个会让一个有教养的人产生自杀念头的环境，不会让他产生太多的不满。因此，穷人的幸福感比我们想象的要多得多。&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;为了阐明他的观点：道森本人相当成功，按照他那个时代的标准，他习惯于简单的手段。但道森于 1928 年去世，他一生的大部分时间都没有电或空调。他从未服用过抗生素、Advil 或脊髓灰质炎疫苗。他从来没有经历过相当准确的天气预报，也没有经历过州际高速公路。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;今天，一个普通美国人如果回到过去体验道森的生活，将会遭受他所写的同样的“难以形容的折磨”。但他的生活没有现代可比，所以他觉得很奢侈。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;生活中的一切美好都只是&lt;a href=&quot;https://collabfund.com/blog/expectations -and-reality/&quot;>;期望与现实之间的差距&lt;/a>;，当你的主要参照系是其他试图给对方留下深刻印象的富人时，这种差距很快就会缩小。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong >;9. 100 年后没有人会记得你。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所以你不妨关注现在能让你快乐的事情，而不是未来金钱可以给你买什么。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; p>; &lt;p>;有一句苏格兰谚语：活着的时候要快乐，因为你已经死了很久了。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 11:38:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/a-few-laws-of-getting-rich/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/a-few-laws-of-getting-rich/</guid></item><item><title>大胆与鲁莽之间的一线之隔</title><description>&lt;p>;科尼利厄斯·范德比尔特刚刚完成了一系列商业交易，以扩大他的铁路帝国。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他的一位商业顾问靠近告诉范德比尔特，他同意的每笔交易都违反了法律。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“天哪，约翰，”&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2DymfK7&quot;>;说&lt;/a>;范德比尔特，“你不认为你可以按照纽约州，是吗？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;读到这篇文章时我的第一个想法是：“这种态度就是他如此成功的原因。”在范德比尔特时代，法律并不支持铁路建设。所以他说“管它呢”，然后还是继续了。范德比尔特取得了巨大的成功，因此人们很容易把他的藐视法律的行为——这臭名昭著，但却对他的成功至关重要——视为圣人的智慧。这位斗志旺盛、有远见的人不让任何事情妨碍他！&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是这种分析有多危险？没有一个理智的人会推荐公然犯罪作为一种创业特征。你可以很容易地想象范德比尔特的故事结果会大不相同——一个不法之徒，他的年轻公司根据法院命令倒闭了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所以我们这里有一个问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人们可以称赞范德比尔特藐视法律他们批评安然公司也这样做，同样充满热情。约翰·D·洛克菲勒 (John D. Rockefeller) 也有类似之处：他经常规避法律——一位法官曾称他的公司“不比普通小偷好多少”——经常被历史学家描述为狡猾的商业智慧。也许是的。但叙述何时会从“你没有让过时的法律阻碍创新”转变为“你犯了罪？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;很难知道。我认为我们只能根据结果来判断过程。这是危险的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;研究企业和投资者最困难的事情是，许多推动他们成功的特质也可能很容易引发失败。但在从具体结果中学习时，我们很少会这样思考。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那些渴望向他人学习的人往往会关注尾巴。大赢家做对了什么？大输家做错了什么？通常很难从两者中找到可行的结论，因为赢家和输家经常采取类似的冒险策略，而结果却因偶然而略有倾斜。我的观点是，巨大的成功需要挑战传统智慧，但传统智慧通常是正确的并且值得遵循。我们留下的结果是，胜利者受到的赞扬超过了他们应得的，失败者受到的批评超过了他们应得的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这不仅仅是违反法律。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本杰明·格雷厄姆的大多数投资成功&lt;a href=&quot;http://jasonzweig.com/was-benjamin-graham-skillful-or-lucky/&quot;>;归功于&lt;/a>;拥有 Geico 的股票。他最初的购买以及随后以高估值持有该股票，几乎打破了格雷厄姆本人在其著名著作中制定的所有规则。我们应该从中学到什么？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们认为马克·扎克伯格是一个天才，他拒绝了出售其公司的大要约。但人们批评 Groupon 和 Yahoo!也同样热衷于拒绝他们的大笔收购要约。这里的企业家可以吸取什么教训？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Uber 在扰乱根深蒂固的出租车市场时毫不留情。但事实证明，支持一家斗志旺盛的初创公司和“#DeleteUber”之间的界限微乎其微。商学院将教授哪些案例研究？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;无数的财富（和失败）都将其结果归功于杠杆作用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最好（和最差）的管理者会像他们一样努力地激励员工可以。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“客户永远是对的”和“客户不知道自己想要什么”都是公认的商业智慧。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“鼓舞人心的大胆”和“愚蠢的愚蠢”之间的界限“鲁莽”的厚度可能只有一毫米，只有事后才能看到。但很容易将导致成功结果的过程视为值得效仿的事情，而将导致失败的过程视为需要避免的事情。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我认为我们对此无能为力。这就是其中之一。&lt;em>;就是&lt;/em>;。风险是不公平且无情的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但有一些事情值得思考。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;少关注案例研究，多关注广泛模式&lt;/strong>;。案例研究可能很危险，因为我们研究极端的例子，而考虑到极端的例子的复杂性，它们通常最不适用于其他情况。通过寻找广泛的事物模式，例如人们如何应对意外、竞争优势有多脆弱、人/企业/经济发展的速度以及什么让人们感到高兴，你将更接近于可采取行动的事情。这也是为什么&lt;a href=&quot;https://microcapclub.com/2018/01/morgan-housel-industries-teach-us-investing/&quot;>;多学科学习如此重要&lt;/a>;。&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&lt;strong>;接受策略过期的事实&lt;/strong>;。历史的讽刺之处在于，它主要是对事物变化的研究，通常被用作下一步行动的指南。唯一比低估别人的策略的风险更危险的是没有意识到整个策略只在不同的时代有效。当你接受事情会随着时间的推移而改变时，你就会对过去使用的具体策略不再感兴趣，而对广泛的主题更感兴趣，比如人们最初是如何发现这些策略的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;还有更多东西需要学习。来自那些承受风险的人，而不是那些看似征服了风险的人&lt;/strong>;。如果成功需要承担很容易变成失败的风险，而两者之间的界限几乎是实时看不见的，那么我想向那些不小心跨过界限并活下来讲述故事的人学习。从严重衰退中幸存下来的公司。从熊市中幸存下来的投资者。失败的产品经过重新设计，然后才发挥作用。在任何冒险的努力中，成功与失败之间的界限都很窄，几乎没有人能找到它，但永远不会跨过它。因此，学习如何忍受偶尔的失误并从中幸存下来，比试图完全避免它们会收获更多。这就是为什么&lt;a href=&quot;https://collabfund.com/blog/the-theory-of-maybes/&quot;>;容错空间和谦逊&lt;/a>;如此重要。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“什么我关心法律吗？”范德比尔特曾经说过。 “我没有这个能力吗？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他做到了，而且成功了。但很容易想象这些是一个结局截然不同的故事的最后一句话。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 09:07:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/the-thin-line- Between-bold-and-reckless/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/the-thin-line- Between-bold-and-reckless/</guid></item><item><title>充电、回收、重复：电池世界的可持续秘密</title><description>&lt;p>;电池世界正在发生一些令人惊奇的事情：由于智能行业举措和消费者意识，电池回收率一直在稳步上升。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;首先以为我们的汽车提供动力的铅酸电池为例。据行业报告，这些电池在美国的回收率为 99%，是铝罐回收率的 2 倍。据《今日回收》报道，这使得铅汽车电池成为单一&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.recyclingtoday.com/news/bci-study-claims-lead-batteries-most-recycled-consumer-product-in-united -states/&quot;>;大多数回收消费品&lt;/a>;。没错 - 每年大约收集和回收 1.6 亿个铅电池，从而避免超过 250 万吨铅和塑料堵塞垃圾填埋场。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/ uploads/Fig1_RecycledProducts.r2.png&quot; alt=&quot;美国顶级回收产品图表，其中铅酸电池位居榜首，占 99%&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;情况并非总是如此。就在几十年前，只有一半的铅电池被回收。但通过电池制造商、回收商和政府之间的协调努力，基础设施和激励措施的出现使铅电池回收不仅可行，而且成为常态。这需要耐心。这需要投资。但该行业将电池回收从事后的想法转变为循环经济的光辉典范。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随着我们期待未来，越来越多的锂离子电池 (LiB) 为从手机到汽车的一切设备提供动力。尽管目前的锂电池回收率低至 5-15% 左右，但铅电池的成功故事仍令人乐观。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随着电动汽车在未来几十年的普及，锂电池的浪费预计将超过 20到 2040 年每年将减少 100 万吨。这似乎令人畏惧，但如果我们能够加大回收力度，这也代表着一个巨大的机遇。许多人看到废电池的浪潮，只看到一堵废物墙。但如果我们有耐心和聪明才智来开采，今天的废品堆就是明天的金矿。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/Fig2_BatteryRecycling.r2.png&quot; alt =&quot;全球可回收电动汽车电池供应量图表（以千吨为单位）&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;回收任何复杂的产品都很困难。弄清楚物流和经济需要时间。挑战比比皆是，尤其是在收集和运输废旧电池方面。但我们有一个模板，并且有动力投资解决问题。这些电池的回收价值是巨大的。但我们以前就这样做过，企业已经在努力扩大锂电池的回收规模。这是我们对&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.redwoodmaterials.com/news/redwood-series-d/&quot;>;我们的投资&lt;/a>;感到兴奋的原因之一：&lt;a href=&quot;https: //www.redwoodmaterials.com/&quot;>;Redwood Materials&lt;/a>; 和他们目前拥有的基础设施，用于回收电动汽车和其他类型的电池，提取有价值的材料并将其重新输入电池供应链。此次 D 轮融资超过 10 亿美元，紧随 Redwood Materials &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rgj.com/story/news/money/business/2023/02/09/redwood-materials-gets -2-billion-doe-loan-for-mega-battery-facility-near-reno/69886953007/&quot;>;美国能源部提供的 20 亿美元贷款&lt;/a>;，为公司提供了充足的资金来继续投资扩大产能。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/RedwoodMaterialsFacility.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;红木材料回收设施的鸟瞰图。&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这不会在一夜之间发生。我们需要建设基础设施并扩大流程。汽车制造商、电池生产商和回收商需要在复杂的价值链上进行合作。需要坚持不懈并解决问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从不起眼的铅电池中寻找灵感似乎已经过时了。您可能不会从外表上猜到，但标志性的铅电池在设计上堪称可回收性的奇迹。它的三种主要成分——铅、塑料、酸——经过精心设计，可以在闭环完美中反复回收。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这不是事后的想法，而是核心原则。铅电池不会被丢弃，而是会重生。 &lt;strong>;典型的新型铅电池由 80% 的回收材料制成。没有性能损失，只是循环继续。值得注意的是，这些电池所需的铅 83% 都来自北美，而不是来自遥远的矿山。&lt;/strong>;塑料外壳也获得了新的生命。所有这些都在近乎完美的循环中循环。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;几十年来，铅电池已经在全国范围内编织了一个由制造、收集地点和回收商组成的网络，&lt;strong>;超过 300,000 个地点&lt;/strong>;接受铅电池用过的电池。这是一个旨在保持铅流通的生态系统。这不是一夜之间发生的。行业团体将利益相关者聚集在一起，慢慢构建智能系统并灌输负责任的电池管理。没有炒作，只有坚持。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;回收的好处不仅仅是减少浪费。 &lt;strong>;生产再生铅所需的能源比开采和冶炼新铅矿石少 70%。更少的能源意味着更少的碳排放。&lt;/strong>;回收完成了循环。根据麦肯锡公司的研究，铅电池已经显示出一条前进的道路。公司希望锂电池能够走类似的道路。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;复制锂电池的铅回收管道并不简单。不幸的是，回收锂离子电池的过程本质上比回收铅电池更加棘手。铅是铅酸电池中唯一的金属，可以通过简单的工艺将其与其他电池材料分离，从而产生高纯度的铅锭。与锂离子电池相比，其中有价值的金属数量众多、种类繁多，并且存在于化学混合物中，通常需要更复杂的分离方法。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;铅汽车电池是回收的成功案例，但更普遍的单一电池使用碱性电池为我们的手电筒和电视遥控器供电已经走了一条不太鼓舞人心的道路。这些电池的回收率仍然很低，只有通过激励非经济行为的法规才能提高（&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1878535223006020&quot;>;来源&lt;/a>;， &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/sustainable-business/2016/apr/14/drawer-full-of-them-battery-recycling-waste-eu&quot;>;来源&lt;/a>;）。一个关键问题在于构成碱性电池的金属（主要是铁、锌和锰）非常便宜。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于锂离子电池来说幸运的是，制造碱性电池的金属有锂、镍和钴。起来大头的材料成本是相当值钱的。再加上庞大且不断增长的锂离子电池市场，让我们希望锂离子电池回收能够大规模盈利。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在这一奖项和提高电动汽车可持续性目标的推动下，像 Redwood Materials 这样的初创公司正在解决以下问题：分离的技术挑战。像他们这样的工艺能够回收高达 95% 的电池材料，以降低成本进行再利用。这是从边缘拉回来的有价值的金属，以抵消昂贵的新采矿的需要。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/Fig3_CarbonFootprint.r2.png&quot; alt=&quot;图表显示使用回收材料的回收电池可减少 28% 的排放量”/>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;回收的锂离子电池材料要从开采的矿物中夺取重要的市场份额还需要一段时间。问题在于，电动汽车的采用增长太快，新电池的需求无法与旧电池的供应相匹配——从 2021 年到 2022 年，电动汽车在全球新车购买量中所占的比例从 8.7% 增加到 14%，从 4.5% 增加到美国的 % 至 7.7%（&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iea.org/data-and-statistics/data-tools/global-ev-data-explorer&quot;>;来源&lt;/a>;）。就问题而言，这是一件好事，而且它当然不应该阻碍锂离子电池回收领域的活动。据估计，到 2030 年，回收将能够满足约 7% 的锂需求以及 11% 的钴和镍需求（&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0921344922003317&quot;>;来源&lt;/a>;），十年后大约是这个数字的两倍。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最令人兴奋的是，我们现在正接近一个临界点，即结束使用寿命的锂离子电池的数量可以证明对建筑回收的投资是合理的超级工厂。到 2025 年，我们应该有足够的可回收电池材料来制造超过 100GWh 的新型锂离子电池（来源：&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mckinsey.com/industries/automotive-and-assemble/our-insights/battery-回收占据主导地位>;麦肯锡&lt;/a>;）。得益于《2022 年通货膨胀减少法案》，电池回收利用立法中名为“先进制造生产信贷”的条款得到了大力推动，该条款为国内电池制造商提供了 10 年的税收抵免。模块。根据该规定，在美国回收的电池，无论其来源如何，都有资格获得补贴。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;重要的是，这些电池材料的双流市场前景可能有利于回收商的利益。如果回收商能够实现更低的成本（包括促进绿色实践的监管激励措施），但他们无法供应整个行业，那么他们可以要求的价格可能会反映开采材料的更高成本，从而带来更高的利润。提高报废锂离子电池的价值可能会降低电动汽车的总拥有成本，从而进一步扩大电动汽车市场。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;重要的是，每吨电池材料产生的货币利润可能接近约 600 美元根据麦肯锡最近的一份报告，最早将于 2025 年实现这一目标。公司学习。展望未来，我们预计价值创造潜力将增长至与初级金属行业类似的水平，约为 30%，具体取决于价格发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/ uploads/Fig4_MonetaryValue.r1.png&quot; alt=&quot;每吨电池回收材料产生的货币价值。&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了更好的回收技术和基础设施之外，在创造新型电池方面也存在重大机遇，这些电池不仅针对特定用例进行了优化，而且更耐用、更安全。例如，&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.byterat.io/&quot;>;Byterat&lt;/a>; 为电池研究和工程提供了端到端的云平台。反过来，这有助于该行业制造更好、更耐用的电池。同样，&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zitara.com/&quot;>;Zitara&lt;/a>; 提供强大的电池管理软件，帮助更好地了解、管理和最大化电池。通过延长电池寿命，我们可以首先减少进入回收的电池数量。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;回收即将到来的锂电池浪潮是一个不小的挑战。但我们以前也曾面临过这个十字路口，并通过耐心投入将问题转化为进步。如果我们应用这些经验教训，电池回收可能会在我们最需要的时候悄然发展成为循环经济的支柱。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;激励措施使回收成为常态，而不是例外。但需要有远见才能看到废弃电池的价值，并需要坚持不懈地提取它。如果我们保持这种心态，锂电池回收就有可能悄然取得胜利，在最需要的时候支持可持续发展。如果我们有耐心，机会就在我们手中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大多数重要的事情都需要耐心和坚持。电池回收也不例外。但如果我们运用改变铅电池回收的思维方式，我们就可以在锂电池和其他技术上再次做到这一点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最重要的进步往往被忽视，正是因为它被如此广泛地采用，以至于我们认为这是理所当然的。我们忘记了为使回收不仅可行而且正常而付出了多少努力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;电池回收可能不会成为头条新闻。但这是一次无声的胜利，并且令人鼓舞地提醒我们，如果我们下定决心，我们有能力构建智能循环系统。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/recharge-recycle-repeat-the-sustainable-secret-of-the-battery-world/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/recharge-recycle-repeat-the-sustainable-secret-of-the-battery-world/</guid></item><item><title>潮水即将退去</title><description>&lt;p>;像许多美国人一样，当我还是个孩子的时候，我的家人常常在七月或八月度过为期一周的假期。与许多家庭不同，我们不是“海滩类型”。我们开玩笑说，这是因为我的弟弟讨厌脚上热沙的感觉，但这很大程度上是因为我的父母希望我们每个夏天都能体验不同的东西。这就是说，三十年后，讽刺的是，那次被人们记住和谈论最多的旅行却是“出错”最多的那次旅行。距离还很远。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1992 年，我的家人认为去新斯科舍省会很有趣。由于我和哥哥没有出过国，父母认为这是一个北上边境的好机会。结果，我们在八月初挤进车里，沿着 95 号州际公路向北行驶。接下来是一次充满创纪录高温的旅行，乔治华盛顿大桥上的大规模备份，几次错过出口，工作紧急情况迫使我父亲飞回东海岸的一半，以及一家没有空气的酒店由于加拿大这一地区的气温很少超过 80 度，仅举几个我们遇到的“问题”。然而，与我们几乎被困在芬迪湾中部的一座岛屿相比，这些都显得黯然失色。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;虽然您可能从未听说过，但芬迪湾拥有全球最大的潮差。全球范围为 16 米，而全球平均范围为 3.3 米。在单个12小时的潮汐周期中，进出海湾的水量约为1000亿吨，是同期世界所有河流总流量的两倍。 >;。因此，在退潮时，您甚至可以驾驶汽车穿过底部前往各个岛屿。不过，关键是你必须仔细观察时钟，因为如果你不及时返回，你就会被困在岛上过夜。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;你可以看到事情的走向。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;父亲在新斯科舍省与我们会合后，他决定开车穿越芬迪湾，所以第二天我们就出发去探索其中一个岛屿。尽管我最初对此表示怀疑，但这实际上是一次非常酷的体验。我们看到一些人走过，而另一些人只是在里面闲逛。令我们惊讶的是，我们是唯一过路的汽车，但是当我们到达岛上时，停车场里已经有很多汽车了。当时我并没有多想，但在短短几个小时内这会变得更有意义。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/Screenshot% 202023-09-29%20at%2010.19.57%20AM.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot 2023-09-29 at 10.19.57 AM.png&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;停车后，我们开始探索。停车场附近没什么可看的，所以我们最终偏离了汽车，比我们计划的要远一些。最终，我父亲说是时候回去了，因为他知道潮水很快就会回来。问题是我们回来时停车场已经没有车了。他们都穿越回来了。他没有意识到你需要在潮水到来之前提前返回。你不能在水涨之前偷偷溜回去。不过值得庆幸的是，我们及时回到了车上，穿越了芬迪湾。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那么，我为什么要提起芬迪湾和我们的新斯科舍省之旅呢？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; >; &lt;p>;首先，我一直觉得很有趣的是，涉及最多问题的家庭度假是迄今为止最常出现的一个。最重要的是，我们不会从负面角度谈论它。事实上，当我们中的一个人提到它时，它很大程度上会引起笑声和积极的回忆——我们如何适应炎热，我们如何找到加拿大最好的培根芝士汉堡，我们如何在高尔夫球场上开球更长时间，因为它是如此坚硬因缺雨而疲惫不堪，我妈妈如何在夜间独自穿越缅因国家森林，当然，还有我们如何差点被困在芬迪湾中部的一个岛上。让你想知道，在人们不断“追求完美”的今天——完美的家庭度假、完美的运动体验、完美的房子、完美的生活，我们是否错过了重点？我们不应该“追求完美”，而应该寻找独特的体验并拥抱这种追求带来的一切吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其次，感觉经济可能正在经历“芬迪湾”的早期阶段片刻。就像新斯科舍省的潮汐周期一样，潮汐每 12 小时进退一次，考虑到利率的持续时间，经济在超过 12 年的时间里一直处于非常有利的潮汐期徘徊在历史低位附近。然而，随着美联储加息速度比 1980 年代初以来的任何时期都快，经济潮流正在明显发生变化。到目前为止，我们刚刚看到了最早的迹象。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最明显的？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;收益率曲线是二十年来最倒挂的，汽油价格高于 4 美元正在挤压消费者， leading economic indicators have been trending lower for 17 straight months, office occupancy is cratering as leases roll, instability in the banking sector is rising as balance sheets fall under water as a result of higher rates, credit is expensive at best and unavailable at worst, housing affordability is at an all-time low, and corporate bankruptcies are rising, just to name a few.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The less obvious?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the wake of the financial crisis fifteen years ago , congress enacted legislation to strengthen and safeguard the financial system.更具体地说，为了防止另一场危机，监管机构通过多德弗兰克法案限制了银行再次过度扩张的能力。毫不奇怪，这导致许多银行限制放贷，专注于更少的业务渠道，并更广泛地承担更少的风险。 As is typically the case, in trying to solve the past crisis, the government may have sown the seeds for the next one.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Regulation simply shifted the risks to a different part of the economy. In this case, when Dodd-Frank forced most banks to pull back on lending, &lt;em>;plenty&lt;/em>; of people and/or funds stood ready to fill the gap.毫不奇怪，这主要来自市场中监管较少的部分，即以私人市场的形式。 With rates at historic lows, these new lenders provided capital to nearly anyone who asked for it.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The good news?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It led to an increase in sources of capital and new business formation.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The bad news?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Capital inevitability funded many more businesses and opportunities than were needed, or warranted.它还导致了无数基金的创建，其中许多基金是由从未经历过危机投资的人领导的。 Looking ahead, this could be a problematic combination.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So where does this leave us?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If I had to guess, we are likely in a similar situation to the one my family found ourselves in when we started making our way back to our car in the middle of the Bay of Fundy. In this case though, while a few cars have already left the island (see any private equity firms that raised large funds, funds that made large asset sales in 2021-2022, or companies that obtained long-term cheap debt), many more haven&#39;t.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, what is in store for those “still on the island”?更具体地说，那些拥有伟大概念但根本上无利可图的企业、在高估值下部署过多资本的风险基金以及认为利率将永远保持在低位的贷款人？我怀疑许多人会发现自己陷入困境，无法获得资金和其他重要资源；只是不是一晚，而是可能好几年。 Some will survive long enough to eventually get off the island, but many more will not.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While this will likely still take time to unfold in the private markets, it appears to already be well underway in the public markets with the average small-cap stock in the Russell 2000 down more than 33% from its 52-week high.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the meantime, for those who managed to get off the island in time or passed on visiting the island altogether (ie, those who took less risk, did not get overextended, and/or have plenty of cash on hand), it might make sense to spend time trying to make a distinction between those that will eventually get off and those that will not, because when those that get off do, they will likely be available for &lt;em>;very&lt;/em>; attractive prices.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 13:14:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/the-tide-is-going-out/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/the-tide-is-going-out/</guid></item><item><title>书面文字</title><description>&lt;p>;A few thoughts I have about writing:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Writing is an art, and art is subjective&lt;/strong>;.小说家威廉·莫恩说过，优秀的写作需要遵循三个规则。 “不幸的是没有人知道它们是什么。”我实际上认为有一个：写你喜欢读的东西。为自己写作是很有趣的，这一点也表明了这一点。 Writing for others is work, and it shows.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Good writing is a performance&lt;/strong>;.马克吐温曾经大声朗读他的家人并观察他们的反应。如果他看到他们感到无聊，他就会把那部分剪掉。如果他看到他们变得兴奋，他就会在该部分加倍努力。 People don&#39;t remember what you wrote as much as they remember how they felt when they read it.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;A good story is like leverage for ideas&lt;/strong>;.故事利用思想，就像债务利用资产一样。 A idea on its own might be boring, but if you tell a good story about someone interacting with that idea, you can get people to nod their heads and pay attention.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;People don&#39;t remember books, blogs, or articles&lt;/strong>;.他们记住句子。这应该是你的目标：收集令人难忘的句子。 One good line is infinitely more powerful than a few clumsy paragraphs.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Most good writing is a byproduct of good reading&lt;/strong>;.你永远不会遇到一个不把大部分时间花在阅读上的好作家。不是一些。 &lt;em>;Most&lt;/em>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Writing is an efficiency game&lt;/strong>;. Whoever says the most stuff in the fewest words wins.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;But efficient doesn&#39;t necessarily mean brief&lt;/strong>;.有900页的书，每一个字都增值。 Efficient just means every line is a delight to read.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Don&#39;t try to build up to your point&lt;/strong>;.这是造成漫无目的的最大原因，也是你失去读者的地方。 The beginning of a story should be as pleasurable to read as the big idea that comes later.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;The best books I&#39;ve read have short chapters&lt;/strong>;.即使它们是很长的书，它们也会将内容分成快速的部分，让您不断前进。 It keeps the author succinct and makes the reader feel like they&#39;re progressing.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Big words mask little thoughts&lt;/strong>;. They&#39;re an attempt to fool the reader into thinking you&#39;re smart when you have nothing smart to say.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Don&#39;t overthink it. Just start writing&lt;/strong>;.伟大的音乐家在即兴演奏中找到他们的音乐——无组织、没有计划，只是看看会发生什么。我认为好的写作也是一样的。如果你想太多，你就会陷入困境。 Start with one brave sentence and see where it goes.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 26 Sep 2023 16:23:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/the-written-word/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/the-written-word/</guid></item><item><title>有几件事我很确定</title><description>&lt;p>;You don&#39;t have to know exactly what the future holds to know that some people will handle it better than others.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Money can bring happiness but it also brings complexity, and complexity can quickly lead to unhappiness.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It&#39;s easy to mistake getting attention for being right or being admired, especially on social media.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most valuable personal finance asset is not needing to impress anyone.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A bigger problem than price inflation is expectations inflation: A constant increase in what you need to be satisfied.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The strongest-held beliefs are usually on topics with the most uncertainty. No one is as passionate about geometry as they are about religion.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have no interest in anything that&#39;s not sustainable. The key to success in so many areas of life is endurance and longevity.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The proper financial mindset is to be scared enough to save for the short run and brave enough to invest for the long run.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Projection is one of the most powerful forces, so be careful around those who tell you how honest and trustworthy they are.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Any amount of intelligence can be overridden by: ego, insecurity, immorality, bad incentives, or impatience, usually in that order.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There&#39;s a big difference between how something should work in theory vs. how it actually works in the real world, when technical facts meet human emotions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;People only communicate perhaps 1% of what&#39;s going through their head, so the world is probably 100x crazier and messier than it looks. Related: It is easier to spot other people&#39;s mistakes than your own, because we judge others based solely on their actions, but when judging ourselves we have an internal dialogue that justifies our mistakes and bad decisions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Everyone hates a spoiled child and knows that child is socially ruined, but they themselves want easy money.你看到讽刺了吗？ Money you didn&#39;t earn or work hard for quickly becomes a social liability.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The four most dangerous financial traits are: FOMO, an addiction to the appearance of certainty when none exists, impatience, and laziness.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most fields have only a few laws.许多理论、预感、观察、想法、趋势和规则。 But laws – things that are always true, all the time – are rare.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Woodrow Wilson said government “is accountable to Darwin, not to Newton.”这是一个有用的想法。 Everything is accountable to one of the two, and you have to know whether something adapts and changes over time or perpetually stays the same.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some of my best work was easy to write, and the worst stuff I&#39;ve ever written was agonizing to write.我认为在大多数领域都是相似的。如果想法好，工作就会很顺利。 Writers&#39; block – or its equivalent in other jobs – usually means the idea is wrong.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You only know someone well if you can correctly predict how they will react in stressful situations.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It&#39;s common to think that people admire you for your success, but what you might actually be fostering is envy, which will come back to haunt you.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I love Brent Beshore&#39;s observation that, “I am 100% happy to watch you get really rich doing something that I have no interest in doing.” It&#39;s not always a competition.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not caring about temporary things, and obsessing over permanent things, is underrated.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 14:55:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/a-few-things-im-pretty-sure-about-0923/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/a-few-things-im-pretty-sure-about-0923/</guid></item><item><title>问 Netflix 联合创始人马克·兰道夫的三个问题</title><description>&lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://marcrandolph.com/&quot;>;Marc Randolph&lt;/a>; is the co-founder and first CEO of Netflix. We recently asked him three questions about business and life.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;What aren&#39;t people talking about enough?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Discussions about mental health in the workplace, including burnout, stress, and the need for a healthier work-life balance, are still not as common as they should be.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And we need to start, because the situation is getting worse. Slack 不断地引起我们的关注。手机让我们可以随时联系并做出响应。 And the recent (and pronounced) shift to working from home has further blurred the line between work and personal time.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We all joke about Gen Z&#39;s insistence on “having a life” but I must confess that they have it right. I shouldn&#39;t be surprised that my most popular social media posts – by an order of magnitude - are not the ones about startup tactics, but instead are the ones about finding a better work life balance, digital sabbaths, establishing boundaries between office and home, and similar subjects.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These topics matter. Endless product sprints, rivers of text messages, and dashboards full of productivity metrics all push, push, and push us to behave in unsustainable ways.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Something must change, and as business leaders this is on us. It&#39;s not enough to simply pay lip service to the &lt;em>;idea&lt;/em>; that balance is important. Since culture is observational, not aspirational, we need to model the behavior we want to see.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have often written about the fact that for years – including the years I was building Netflix – I left home promptly at 5:00 every Tuesday for a date night with my wife.如果出现危机，我们将在 5:00 之前结束。 If you desperately need to talk to me, we can talk on the way to the car.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And while this behavior may have saved my sanity (and my marriage), the real benefit is that the rest of the company could see that I meant it when I told them that I expected them to carve out time for themselves.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Is this easy?不，但这有必要吗？是的。 Because when all is said and done, the only people who are going to remember all those nights and weekends you spent at the office are your children.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;What have you changed your mind about lately?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Don&#39;t get me started.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A few years ago, I decided I would try to change my mind about something at least once a month – and that turned out to be way too easy.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I started with politics – we are a polarized nation and I&#39;ve got plenty of opinions about why the other side&#39;s policies are so awful.但如果美国在大多数问题上的分歧接近 50/50，我就不可能相信 1.6 亿人是完全错误的。或者愚蠢。 Or misguided.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I needed to approach my beliefs the way I did when I was debating in high school. I had to prepare myself to be able to articulate and defend a certain side of an argument, but I had to do so without knowing until right before the debate which side I would need to argue for.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The more I did this, the more I realized how shallow so many of my opinions were, and that this way of thinking could not only be applied to big topics like educational reform, homelessness, gun control, immigration, environmental policies, criminal justice, and racial equality, but to smaller and equally heated topics like – to name a recent one - password sharing on Netflix. (I&#39;m not joking about the password sharing thing – It&#39;s gotten so I&#39;m scared to wade into my TikTok comments).&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It&#39;s been liberating, because I no longer spend my time building the case for why I&#39;m right. I now spend most of my cycles trying to figure out why they think &lt;em>;they&lt;/em>; are.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It has changed my perspective on almost every topic I&#39;ve looked at.但这个练习最让我惊讶的是，几乎在所有情况下，改变主意并不意味着从一侧翻转到另一侧，而只是意味着靠近中心。 It meant acknowledging that these were complicated and nuanced answers that didn&#39;t have &lt;em>;any&lt;/em>; right answer. Or more frequently, would require partially unsatisfactory outcomes for both sides to agree on, accept, and move on.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I&#39;ve still got a way to go.我仍在努力弄清楚为什么人们如此强烈反对密码共享打击。 。 。 but I promise I&#39;m working on it.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;What&#39;s a piece of commonly accepted advice you think is wrong?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“There&#39;s no such thing as a bad idea.”这一定是有史以来最糟糕的建议。因为我了解到事实恰恰相反。 &lt;em>;All&lt;/em>; ideas are bad. In fact, there&#39;s no such thing as a &lt;em>;good&lt;/em>; idea.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And it&#39;s not just wrong . 。 。这很危险。 Because by assuming that all ideas are good, it encourages hundreds of hours of wasted effort studying the problem, writing plans, putting together task forces, etc. – all without any feedback from the real world about whether it&#39;s actually a good idea or not.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Our job as entrepreneurs is to take those (bad) ideas and figure out a quick, cheap and easy way to find out why they are bad. That&#39;s the only way to begin the process of testing and iteration that – if we&#39;re lucky – will eventually bring us to something that works.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I can&#39;t think of a single successful company that has become successful doing their original idea.相反，这个想法只是一个起点。他们采纳了最初的想法；想出了一些便宜、快速、简单的方法来尝试；观察发生的事情；然后尝试了别的东西。 And probably did that for years.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At Netflix it took us more than 18 months, and hundreds of failed experiments to finally land on the business model that was a good idea. And they are still experimenting.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 12 Sep 2023 12:21:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/three-questions-for-netflix-co-founder-marc-randolph/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/three-questions-for-netflix-co-founder-marc-randolph/</guid></item><item><title>尊重和钦佩</title><description>&lt;p>;I like the idea of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.berkshirehathaway.com/letters/2022ltr.pdf&quot;>;reverse obituary&lt;/a>;: Write down what you want your obituary to say, then figure out how to live up to it.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Everyone&#39;s will be different, but I suspect most people would want their obituary to say: You were respected.你被钦佩了。你很有帮助。您是一位好父母、好配偶、贴心朋友。您是社区的财富。您为您的行业做出了贡献。 You were wise, funny, and smart.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now realize what&#39;s not in there.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Virtually no one in this exercise would think about their obituary mentioning how much horsepower their car has, how many square feet their home is, or how much they spent on jewelry and clothes.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I like nice things.我有一些奇特的东西。 But I&#39;m always struck by the contrast here of what people want vs. what they aspire to.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just after my son was born I &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fool.com/investing/general/2015/10/13/financial-advice-for-my-new-son.aspx&quot;>;wrote a few things&lt;/a>; I thought he&#39;d find helpful as an adult. One of them was:&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;You might think you want an expensive car, a fancy watch, and a huge house.但我告诉你，你不知道。你想要的是别人的尊重和钦佩，你认为拥有昂贵的东西就能带来这些。 It almost never does – especially from the people you want to respect and admire you.&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;Eight years later I still believe this to be true, and I might even double down.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Let me first distinguish nice stuff from fancy stuff.有人曾经说过，高端丰田比入门级宝马更好，因为好的丰田充满了让驾驶更愉快的东西，而入门级宝马大多只是地位和吹牛的资本。用钱买好东西真是太好了。 Fancy stuff is a different animal.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This isn&#39;t universal, but there are cases when people&#39;s desire to show off fancy stuff is because it&#39;s their only, desperate, way to gain some sense of respect and admiration.他们没有任何智慧、智慧、幽默、同理心或爱的能力来赢得人们的尊重。 So they rely on the only remaining, and least effective, lever: Look at my car, beep beep, vroom vroom.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Former football player Chad Johnson &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ShannonSharpe/status/1620223077702586370?s=20&amp;amp;t=iqXe7T24ijApj57thXkneA&quot;>;once explained&lt;/a>; why some people think he&#39;s cheap: There&#39;s no need to show off your material wealth when your name is so big that people already respect and admire you for your talents alone:&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;If you can get to a point in your career where your name becomes bigger than anything you can purchase, there&#39;s your value.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is nothing I can buy that is bigger than my name alone.所以[购买珠宝]毫无意义。 &lt;em>;I&#39;m me&lt;/em>;. It&#39;s pointless.&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;My guess is that if your favorite comedian, or actor, or athlete turned out to be broke, you wouldn&#39;t care. It wouldn&#39;t impact how much you admire them, because you admire them for talents that money can&#39;t buy.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even when Amazon was huge and successful, Jeff Bezos &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tc0a28KrWKo&amp;amp;ab_channel=Way&quot;>;used to drive a&lt;/a>; Honda Accord.如今他拥有一艘价值5亿美元的游艇。他是否因此而受到更多的尊重和钦佩？一点也不。他可以骑一辆赫菲自行车，人们会认为他是我们这个时代最伟大的企业家，因为他就是。 Steve Jobs &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cultofmac.com/125861/steve-jobss-quest-for-perfection-could-make-even-buying-a-sofa-into-a-decade-long-ordeal/&quot;>;didn&#39;t have any furniture&lt;/a>;.没关系。他是个天才。他是史蒂夫·乔布斯。 Material stuff makes no difference when you&#39;re respected and admired for internal traits.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The same is probably true for the people you admire most.我爱并钦佩我的父母，让我告诉你这不是因为他们的衣服。难道没有太多值得学习的地方吗？ Shouldn&#39;t gaining respect and admiration through what you do instead of what you own be the goal?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Once you see people being respected and admired for reasons that have nothing to do with the stuff they own, you begin to wonder why you have such a strong desire for those possessions.我倾向于将物质欲望视为一个松散的代表，与你必须为世界提供的其他东西相反。 The higher my desire for fancy stuff, the less real value I have to offer.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I think if you keep it in mind, a lot of higher priorities come into view.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 06 Sep 2023 12:02:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/respect-and-admiration/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/respect-and-admiration/</guid></item><item><title>智能与智能</title><description>&lt;p>;Here&#39;s an important distinction to make in life.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some people are intelligent but don&#39;t have a lick of smarts. Their ability to succeed in the world might surprise you on the downside.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Others lack intelligence but gush smarts. Their potential will surprise you on the upside.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On rare occasions you meet people who are both intelligent and smart. They run laps around everyone.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I&#39;d define intelligence vs. smart like this: Intelligent people understand technical details, smart people understand emotional details.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Or maybe:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Intelligence&lt;/strong>;: Good memory, logic, math skills, test-taking ability, rule-following.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Smart&lt;/strong>;: High degree of empathy, bullshit detection, organization, communication skills, persuasion, social awareness, understanding the consequences of your actions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Both are important. But there&#39;s a critical difference in how each is valued.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Schools are good at teaching and measuring intelligence, so that&#39;s what people tend to value and aspire to. But in almost any field, smarts is what gets rewarded long term.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You cannot measure empathy like you can SAT scores, so it&#39;s not surprising that one is given more weight on resumes. But who is more likely to succeed in life – a person whose main skill is memorizing formulas, or someone who can instantly relate to the emotions of coworkers, customers, spouses, and friends?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It&#39;s so obvious.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And it&#39;s why the world is filled with intelligent jerks who have gone nowhere, and middling students who struggled through calculus but go on to live successful, happy lives.大多数人会做出的最重要的决定是是否结婚、何时结婚以及与谁结婚。但学校里从来没有教过这一点——怎么可能呢？你无法将其提炼为一个公式，或者一个放之四海而皆准的答案。 It&#39;s a decision that requires lots of smarts and very little intelligence.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The core here is realizing that people are not spreadsheets.他们是情绪化、荷尔蒙旺盛、信息误导、追求地位、缺乏安全感的生物，竭尽全力度过这一天。 So if you have to choose between understanding how the world &lt;em>;should&lt;/em>; work in theory vs. how it &lt;em>;actually&lt;/em>; works in practice, lean towards the latter.就像历史学家威尔·杜兰特曾经说过的那样：“逻辑是人类的发明，可能会被宇宙忽视。” That is so smart.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Here&#39;s an extreme example.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;George Soros says that whenever he sees a bubble, he rushes in to buy it.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you&#39;re an intelligent person, that might seem crazy. Why would you purposefully want to buy an overvalued investment?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But if you&#39;re a smart person, maybe it makes sense.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You know that bubbles are likely to grow larger and last longer than most people imagine. You understand what&#39;s going through people&#39;s minds, and you know investors will keep frantically buying for some time not because the numbers make sense, but because their neighbor got rich and they&#39;ll spiral down a black hole of jealousy and bad decisions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“That&#39;s not irrational,” says Soros. (But please don&#39;t try this; you&#39;re probably not as smart as Soros).&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Derek Thompson of the Atlantic makes a beautiful point that baseball has become boring over the last 20 years.为什么？因为每个团队都变得聪明起来：他们通过挖掘数据来确定如何获得最多的三振，从而制定策略。如果你想赢得比赛，那就是明智之举！但这让比赛变得无趣。它带走了一部分灵魂，一部分乐趣。现在这项比赛正面临着兴趣和上座率下降的危机。 It took smarts to see that coming.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Here are a few other “smart” traits that are hard to measure.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Accepting that people who have lived different lives than you want different things and will see the world differently. What looks like debates are often just people with different lived experiences talking over each other.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Henry Ford said, “If there is any one secret of success it lies in the ability to get the other person&#39;s point of view and see things from their angle as well as your own.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The purely intelligent person will find this hard to grasp, because if you think there is one right answer to every problem, you insist on banging through more debate until the other side agrees with you.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It takes smarts to accept that for most problems in the world, the “right” answer is the one that best promotes your individual wellbeing &lt;em>;and&lt;/em>; fits your experience of how the world works. And since everyone has different needs and experiences, the only way to move forward and get things done is to tolerate and work with some views even when you disagree with them.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The outcome, if you can pull this off, is the skill of getting along with people you disagree with. It is indispensable.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;An awareness that being nice doesn&#39;t mean being weak – it&#39;s actually a selfish strategy for gaining cooperation over time.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The hedge fund Long Term Capital Management was collapsing in 1998, threatening to take down all of Wall Street in its wake.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In response, 14 Wall Street banks stepped in to collectively bail the fund out and halt the panic.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every big bank participated in the bailout – except Bear Stearns, whose CEO Jimmy Cayne allegedly responded, “No fucking way,” to the request.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ten years later, Bear Stearns itself teetered on the edge. And guess how many other Wall Street banks were willing to lend Jimmy Cayne a hand?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Charlie Munger once pointed out that Benjamin Franklin didn&#39;t say honesty is the best morals – he said it&#39;s the best &lt;em>;policy&lt;/em>;. It&#39;s what&#39;s going to &lt;em>;help&lt;/em>; &lt;em>;you, and put you in the best position, earning you the most money&lt;/em>;, in the long run.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There&#39;s a corollary there with kindness.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are two reasons to be kind to everyone.一是道德，二是自私。从道德上讲，你应该这样做，因为你有同理心。 Selfishly, you should do it because it&#39;s easy to underestimate how many people you may eventually rely on to help you, and you&#39;ll only gain their cooperation if you remain in their good graces.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Multi-disciplinary thinking&lt;/strong>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I serve on the board of directors of Markel. Someone recently asked me what I&#39;ve learned from Markel&#39;s CEO Tom Gayner – truly one of the most accomplished investors of recent decades.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My response is that no matter what we&#39;re talking about, Tom has a perfect analogy from something totally unrelated.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If we&#39;re talking about insurance reserves, Tom will say something like, “You know, this reminds me of that scene from the &lt;em>;Sound of Music&lt;/em>; …”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If we&#39;re talking about market valuations, Tom might say, “It&#39;s kind of like Winston Churchill used to say …”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In each case, the analogy gets right to the heart of the topic at hand.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is more than mere entertaining chat.我认为汤姆是一位优秀的投资者，因为他了解世界是如何运作的——将各个领域之间的点联系起来——这比仅仅了解金融要广泛得多。 People who understand finance might be intelligent, but understanding how the world works requires smarts.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Too many intelligent people become siloed in their field, oblivious to how interconnected the world is.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;True independent thinking.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kevin Kelly has this great idea that you&#39;re only thinking independently if your views on certain topics can&#39;t be predicted from your views on other topics.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many views can be predicted, because true independent thinking is so rare.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tell me your views on immigration and I can probably guess your views on abortion.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tell me who you voted for president and I can probably guess whether you think today&#39;s economy is strong or weak.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When your views on certain topics can be predicted from unrelated statements, there&#39;s a good chance you&#39;ve outsourced part of your thinking to tribal affiliations.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;True independent thinking is rare because most people would rather be comfortable than right, and there is comfort in knowing you are a good-standing member of your tribe.独立思考并不意味着你是对的，因为大众通常非常接近准确。 Going against the tribe can also be interpreted as arrogance – suddenly you might look like Jimmy Cayne.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But poet Rudyard Kipling writes, “If you can talk with crowds and keep your virtue, Or walk with Kings, nor lose the common touch,” you&#39;re on your way to greatness.测试这一点的一种方法是，是否有人在某些话题上你同意，但在其他话题上你不同意。如果有人在每个话题上你都同意他的观点，那么要小心了。 If there is someone whose views you disagree with on every topic, be even more careful.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I think my own dog – who is such a good girl – is crazy half the time, so I shudder when people can&#39;t find any faults in their favorite politician or investing guru.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Recognizing that the best story wins.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not the best answer.不是准确的答案。这不是人们需要听到的答案。 The winner is just whoever gets people to pay attention and nod their heads in agreement.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you&#39;re merely intelligent, you might focus all of your effort on finding precise truth. If you&#39;re smart, you&#39;ll focus just as much effort on delivering an effective message around that truth, realizing that the most powerful truth does no good if you can&#39;t get people to pay attention to it.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A doctor once told me there&#39;s a difference between an expert in medicine and an expert in healthcare.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An expert in medicine knows all the right answers out of the textbook. They can diagnose with precision and are up to date on all the latest treatments.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An expert in healthcare understands that medicine from the patient&#39;s view is intimidating, confusing, expensive, and time-consuming. Nothing you diagnose or prescribe matters until you&#39;ve addressed that reality with patients, because even a perfect solution makes no difference to the patient who doesn&#39;t follow it.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It&#39;s similar in investing.对冲基金经理凯尔·巴斯对此进行了很好的总结，他说：“保持信念很容易。留住投资者更加困难。”最成功的投资者往往是沟通专家，因为在不可避免的业绩不佳时期，你必须迫使投资者坚持你。巴菲特。红杉。甚至先锋； they are so skilled – intentionally so – at delivering an effective message beyond the numbers.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Warren Buffett – amazing writer.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Charlie Munger – amazing writer.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Seth Klarman – amazing writer.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;John Bogle – amazing writer.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Joel Greenblatt – amazing writer.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Howard Marks – amazing writer.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I don&#39;t think this is a coincidence.这些投资者的写作能力让他们能够有效地讲述自己的故事、设定期望并让投资者放心。 That made their investors more likely to stick around when times got rocky.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It&#39;s hard to teach that.讲故事是一种软性的情感技能。在情报中找不到它。 It&#39;s found in smarts.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 22 Aug 2023 12:49:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/intelligent-vs-smart/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/intelligent-vs-smart/</guid></item></channel></rss>