<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>合作基金</title><description>Collab Fund 是推动世界前进的企业家的主要资金来源。</description><link/> https://collabfund.com<atom:link href="https://collabfund.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 08:25:09 -0400</pubDate><lastbuilddate> 2023 年 6 月 16 日星期五 08:25:09 -0400</lastbuilddate><generator>网站叶</generator><item><title>可持续材料的演变：值得关注的六大趋势</title><description>&lt;p>;可持续材料——源自可再生资源而不是化石燃料的材料——为地球和所有以地球为家的人创造更光明、更健康的未来奠定了基础。它们也是我们气候基金的核心焦点，&lt;a href=&quot;https://collabfund.com/blog/collab-sos-a-new-fund-and-a-call-to-action/&quot;>;Collab SOS&lt;/a>;，涵盖从纺织品和生物塑料到绿色化学品和建筑材料的方方面面。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自我们推出该基金以来的一年里，该行业发展迅速，以满足瞬息万变的世界的需求。监管顺风和大公司的买入已经被更高的资本成本和投资者的不安所平衡。然而，科学突破——包括基于人工智能的建模的改进以及可再生能源和基因编辑成本的下降——加速了进步并开辟了扩大规模的新途径。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以下是一些主要趋势我们最近几个月注意到：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;1.原料多样化&lt;/strong>; 公司正在放弃糖等精炼原料，并在生产有价值的材料时越来越多地选择原料。我们现在看到越来越多的公司使用农作物废弃物、食物废弃物、织物废弃物、城市废弃物和 CO2 或 CH4 气体废弃物（例如，工业燃烧产生的烟气或废水处理厂产生的气体）。这些原料不仅成本更低，而且这些重新设计的工作流程通常可以相对减少温室气体排放和土地使用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;2.结合生物学和绿色化学&lt;/strong>; 公司正在不断发展，不再局限于尝试纯粹通过发酵来生产产品。相反，他们利用自然界提供的分子，使用生物宿主优化最佳分子的生产，然后利用化学产生最终目标。这种方法通常会降低发酵和下游加工的成本，并成倍地增加可能的化学目标和应用的数量。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;3.优化下游加工成本&lt;/strong>; 在当前资本成本高企的环境下，公司更加关注成本优化。这涉及寻找丰富且负担得起的原料并简化下游流程，这些流程通常是能源密集型且产量有限。通过正面解决这些成本驱动因素，可持续材料公司可以提高竞争力并为广泛采用铺平道路。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;4.拥护成分胜于品牌&lt;/strong>; 公司更注重 B2B 上市战略，而不是创建自己的消费品牌。在 Collab，我们看到通过构建端到端流程（或尽可能接近）捕获尽可能多的垂直价值有很多价值。然而，团队技能，尤其是在早期阶段，通常更适合创建成分而不是垂直品牌。这种策略可以实现更快的规模化。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;5.探索可调材料&lt;/strong>; 公司不再只提供一种材料。今天，他们有能力根据特定特性调整材料。这通常是通过探索潜在的酶活性和创新的绿色化学平台来完成的。我们在生产替代皮革的公司和生产织物处理（例如用于防水的 PFAS 替代品）的公司中尤其看到了这一点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;6.成熟的无细胞系统和应用&lt;/strong>; 允许在活细胞范围之外发生生物反应的无细胞技术正在迅速成熟。价格合理、新颖且可调节的树脂可延长酶的寿命和稳定性，使企业重新焕发活力，现在公司可以将这项技术应用于生产可持续材料和化学品。这些系统曾经主要用于制药，现在可用于更广泛的应用，包括利用二氧化碳制造纤维、回收难以加工的塑料以及合成复杂的化学品。无细胞系统允许精确调节、优化和提高生物合成途径的产量，并具有创建具有独特、定制特性的材料的额外能力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该行业正在经历一个以快速进步和演变为标志的转型期策略。第一波生物材料从未完全达到炒作的效果，但我们对这群最新的创新者的未来非常乐观。上述趋势凸显了该行业创新和应对关键挑战的决心。作为更可持续的未来的投资者和倡导者，我们必须继续监测这些趋势，并与引领创新的公司合作。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 08:23:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/sustainable-materials-six-trends/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/sustainable-materials-six-trends/</guid></item><item><title>问题：预测不确定时期的极端天气</title><description>&lt;p>;极端天气事件比以往任何时候都更加频繁和严重。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022 年，气候驱动的天气事件在全球范围内造成了 115B 美元的保险财务损失——比之前的 10 年平均水平高出惊人的 42% .&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;飓风、旋风、洪水、野火和干旱等气候灾害激增带来的不确定性提出了一个重大问题：如果保险公司、企业和政府无法预测与气候相关的破坏性威胁，他们无法做出正确的决定来保护他们的资产。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这对于金融服务业和保险市场以及他们所服务的客户来说是一个主要问题和机遇。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/unnamed-011cd1.png&quot; alt=&quot;unnamed-011cd1.png&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;存在气候风险预测的现有解决方案，例如&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rms.com/&quot;>;Moody&#39; RMS&lt;/a>;，但大多数都依赖于历史数据。这些模型从“历史损失率”——给定时期的损失总值除以同期的总风险敞口——推断，试图预测未来。但气候变化正在改变天气事件的频率和强度，这使得历史推断不充分。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;预测未来气候变化的模型基于一系列假设和不确定性，很难准确预测捕捉大气、海洋和陆地表面之间的所有复杂相互作用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这就是 &lt;a href=&quot;https://reask.earth/&quot;>;Reask&lt;/a>; 的用武之地。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这就是 &lt;a href=&quot;https://reask.earth/&quot;>;Reask&lt;/a>; 的用武之地。&lt;/p>; p>; &lt;p>;由 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/thomasloridan/&quot;>;Thomas Loridan &lt;/a>; 和 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/ in/jamie-rodney-2b4a2782/&quot;>;Jamie Rodney&lt;/a>; 与一群先驱数学家、气象学家和计算机科学家一起，Reask 避开了历史损失率外推法，转而支持自下而上的物理天气建模——使用根据当前条件和物理定律预测天气的数学模型。这些模型将各种大气参数（例如温度、湿度、风速和风向、大气压力等）作为输入，并应用物理学原理来模拟天气随时间的演变。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reask 的秘密武器是一组利用 AI 模拟的专有天气模型，可将风险因素分配到平方公里。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种方法有几个好处：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;精确度&lt;/strong>;：重新询问直接计算高度准确的变量，如风速，并捕捉风险的完整分布，超越简单的风险评分，而是让客户得出一个价格。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;清晰度&lt;/strong>;：Reask总是使用物理变量来评估风险。创建的任何输出都可以直接与已知的大气系统物理学相关，而不是纯粹的统计数据。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;全球&lt;/strong>;：Reask 模型本质上是全球性的，捕捉气候的物理学，并且允许客户有史以来第一次评估如何在金融资产组合中分散和管理气候风险。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;可以利用 Reask 的 API 为瑞士等传统保险和再保险公司提供支持Re，以及 &lt;a href=&quot;https://ourkettle.com/&quot;>;Kettle&lt;/a>; 和 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.arbol. io/&quot;>;Arbol&lt;/a>; 更有效地承保风险。 &lt;a href=&quot;https://descartesunderwriting.com/&quot;>;Descartes &lt;/a>;等公司也可以使用这些数据来开发参数化保险产品，从而迅速为受破坏性天气事件影响的人们提供救助。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，模型的特殊性和 Reask 预测能力的全球性使更广泛的金融机构和大型资产持有者能够了解他们的整个投资组合面临的风险，以便他们能够保护自己、他们的员工和更广泛的&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随着美国飓风季节的临近，我们很高兴看到 Reask 的解决方案可用，我们很高兴支持 Reask，因为我们共同领导了他们的种子轮融资与我们在 Mastry Ventures 的朋友一起。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;您可以在&lt;a href=&quot;https://reask.earth/news/&quot;>;此处&lt;/a>;关注公司的进展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而且，如果您正在研究应对气候变化的方法，我们希望收到您的来信！&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 15 Jun 2023 09:15:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/reask-predicting-extreme-weather-in-uncertain-times/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/reask-predicting-extreme-weather-in-uncertain-times/</guid></item><item><title>复合乐观</title><description>&lt;p>;让我分享一些关于乐观主义的小理论，以及为什么进步很容易被低估。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我将分四个部分进行解释。&lt;/p>; &lt;hr />; &lt;p>;哥斯达黎加的一只鳄鱼&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbsnews.com/news/crocodile-virgin-birth-costa-rica/&quot;>;最近被发现怀孕&lt;/a>;——而这一切都是她自己做的，没有男性的帮助。她的胎儿在基因上与她 99.99% 相同。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是鳄鱼无性繁殖的第一例记录在案的案例。其他一些动物——一些鸟类和蛇——也可以做到这一点，但这种情况极为罕见。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是有充分理由的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大约 100 年前，一位名叫Herman Muller 提出了一个理论，该理论最终被称为 Muller&#39;s Ratchet。它说，当没有基因重组时，危险的突变往往会堆积起来，最终可能导致一个物种灭绝。在缺乏多样性的情况下——男性和女性混合基因——危险的突变往往会持续存在，因为没有新的、更好的变异来与基因库中的坏东西竞争。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这就是为什么如此很少有物种进行无性繁殖。&lt;/p>; &lt;hr />; &lt;p>;David Senra 的精彩&lt;em>;创始人&lt;/em>; 播客 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PI6QcwnfNe8&amp;amp ;ab_channel=Acquired&quot;>;最近&lt;/a>; 讲述了一个关于史蒂夫·乔布斯的故事：&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;史蒂夫在 20 多岁时去见了 [Polaroid 创始人] Edwin Land。史蒂夫说：“拜访埃德温·兰德就像拜访圣地……他是我的英雄。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;杰夫·贝索斯从山姆·沃尔顿那里汲取了很多想法。史蒂夫和杰夫都从索尼那里汲取了很多想法。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;你总能找到这些人，“哦，我认为这是史蒂夫乔布斯的想法。”不，不。这是 [Sony 创始人] Akio Morita 的想法，或 Edwin Land 的想法。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;观看史蒂夫·乔布斯 (Steve Jobs) 的演讲，他说：“我们正在技术与文科的交汇处建设。” Edwin Land 说的正是这些话！&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果不研究前人，向他们学习并钦佩他们，你永远找不到任何人登上行业的顶峰。&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;这是千真万确的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;托马斯·爱迪生从迈克尔·法拉第那里汲取了很多创意。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;比尔·盖茨从一位名叫亨利·爱德华兹·罗伯茨的计算机发明家那里汲取了创意。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沃伦·巴菲特向本·格雷厄姆和菲尔·费雪学习。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;埃德温·兰德本人深受哈佛物理学教授乔治·惠莱特的影响，他 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www .nytimes.com/2001/03/03/business/gw-wheelwright-iii-97-dies-co-founder-of-polaroid.html&quot;>;成为宝丽来联合创始人&lt;/a>;。&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;问题是：George Wheelwright 是否知道他会影响 Edwin Land，Edwin Land 会影响 Steve Jobs，后者会设计出 25 亿人会使用的手机？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Michael Faraday 知道吗，他已经去世了1867 年，他知道他的想法会直接影响灯泡，从而有效地导致从现代电网到夜生活的一切事物的产生吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本·格雷厄姆知道他 1950 年代的金融课会带来 45,000每年徒步去奥马哈听他的学生演讲？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然不是。很难知道一个想法、一项发明或一种哲学会影响什么，以及受其影响的人会继续创造什么。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Visa 创始人 Dee Hock 说，“一本书远远超过作者所写的；它是您可以想象和阅读的所有内容。”作者可能会写一些枯燥或明显的东西，但它可以激发读者去做一些令人难以置信的事情。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;想法复合。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;发明复合。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;教育“ &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ted.com/talks/matt_ridley_when_ideas_have_sex&quot;>;做爱&lt;/a>;。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大多数新想法和发明本身都很乏味。但是，当你将其中的几种混合在一起时，你就会产生魔力。塑料很棒。电子设备很整洁。金属很特别。但以正确的方式将它们混合在一起，你就会得到一部 iPhone，这简直就是魔法。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;正是这些想法的结合、结合和融合，创造了现代世界。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;它是&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ridley 在他的&lt;em>;理性乐观主义者&lt;/em>;一书中解释了重组的好处：&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;发生在一个生物身上的突变可以与发生在另一个生物身上的突变联合起来。如果几十亿年前微生物没有开始交换基因，动物也没有通过性交继续这样做，那么所有构成眼睛的基因就不可能在一只动物身上聚集在一起；也不是制造腿、神经或大脑的基因。每个突变都会在自己的谱系中保持孤立，无法发现协同作用的乐趣。&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;Ridley 曾进一步解释过这一点：&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;我不是对某些群体的智商是否高于其他群体的争论感兴趣。这完全无关紧要。与社会相关的是人们交流想法的程度以及他们合作的程度，而不是个人的聪明程度。&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;小想法混合成大想法 – 这就是&lt;/p>; &lt;hr />; &lt;p>;我认为悲观主义比乐观主义更容易和更普遍的部分原因是复合增长不直观。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这很难想象一下，比如说，我们的收入在未来几代人中翻一番。这似乎是一个巨大的飞跃，就像我们必须煮沸海洋才能完成它一样。但在 30 年内将平均收入翻一番，每年的增长率约为 2.3%。这一点也不疯狂。这实际上是可以实现的。它一开始就显得如此雄心勃勃的原因是复合增长很容易被低估。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果你看看长期复合的最终结果，它会令人震惊。但要完成它所需要的只是长时间串在一起的一点点增量增长。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所有的进步都是这样的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;技术进步很容易被低估，因为它是如此例如，一个发明了宝丽来胶片的人的哲学将如何继续激发 iPhone 的灵感，这违反直觉。或者 18 世纪的物理学家如何编写一本笔记本，为现代电气系统奠定基础。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果您认为进步是由个人的天才推动的，那么当然很难想象未来那里的情况要好得多，因为没有人比平均水平聪明几个数量级。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是当你把它看作是一个人提出一个小想法，另一个人复制这个想法并稍微调整它时，另一个采用这种洞察力并稍微操纵它，另一个采用该产品并将其与其他东西结合起来——增量的、微小的部分、小的想法混合、连接、混合、变异和复合在一起——它突然变得更容易想象了。&lt;/p >;</description><pubDate> Tue, 13 Jun 2023 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/compounding-optimism/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/compounding-optimism/</guid></item><item><title>硅谷的巴西</title><description>&lt;p>;对于全球科技公司和创业生态系统来说，今年是非常艰难的一年。然而，硅谷的巴西设法阐明了巴西的创新机会以及那些在该国建设和投资的人的承诺。拉丁美洲继续成为充满活力的创新景观，巴西正在迅速确立自己的中心地位。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Simon Rodriguez &lt;a href=&quot;https://technopoly.substack.com/p/is- brazil-losing-its-lead&quot;>;将这种情绪概括为&lt;/a>;“问任何人，巴西比讲西班牙语的拉美领先 X 年，其中 X 取决于回复者的国籍”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbvaspark.com/contenido/en/news/land-of-unicorns-and-fintech-empire-this-is-sao-paulo-the-largest-innovation-ecosystem- in-latin-america/&quot;>;BBVA 报告&lt;/a>;，“圣保罗的创业生态系统价值 1080 亿美元。相比之下，&lt;a href=&quot;https://openinnovation.bbva.com/es/noticias/en-el-zocalo-del-emprendimiento-el-bum-emprendor-y-fintech-de-ciudad-de-mexico/ “>;墨西哥城&lt;/a>;（拉丁美洲第二大城市）的估值为 220 亿美元。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，圣保罗在全球金融科技排名中排名第四。在“现金为王”的地区，巴西正在引领数字支付。巴西中央银行于 2020 年推出了该国的即时支付系统 PIX，该系统已拥有超过 1.3 亿注册用户（占巴西人口的 60%）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为了探索巴西的技术进步，来自斯坦福大学和伯克利大学的学生拥有令人难以置信的名为&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brazilatsiliconvalley.com/&quot;>;巴西硅谷&lt;/a>; (BSV) 的年度盛会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;顾名思义，其目的是弥合巴西和硅谷之间的差距。今年，BSV 有超过 600 名创始人、投资者、技术专家和政策制定者参加。我的非官方估计是，至少有 550 名与会者从巴西踏上了漫长的旅程——至少有两次飞行，飞行时间至少为 15 小时。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这么说吧，我的 portuñol 派上用场了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;在农业科技会议期间：&lt;em>;食品系统创新如何帮助解决气候危机&lt;/em>;，BSV 工作人员在会议结束后使用语音转文本功能生成了 Chat-GPT 摘要会议记录. &lt;em>;当然&lt;/em>;，摘要是通过 Whatsapp 发送的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;今年的 BSV 阐明了几个关键的投资主题：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;● &lt;strong>;垂直化软件&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;+ 金融科技&lt;/strong>;：创造和扩展本地软件解决方案的机会无穷无尽。巴西受益于支持性政策及其中央银行在实施数字支付系统 PIX 方面的作用。 a16z 的合伙人 Angela Strange 强调了她的观点，即每家公司都将是一家金融科技公司，因为金融服务将是一个横向平台。她引用了 &lt;a href=&quot;https://fu.do/es/&quot;>;Fudo&lt;/a>;*、&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uber.com/&quot;>;Uber&lt;/a>;、&lt; a href=&quot;https://www.lyft.com/&quot;>;Lyft&lt;/a>;*，以及其他值得注意的例子。我们还认为 &lt;a href=&quot;https://kanastra.com.br/&quot;>;Kanastra&lt;/a>;* 是令人兴奋的金融科技基础设施游戏的一个很好的例子。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;● &lt;strong>;Agtech +气候：&lt;/strong>;农业综合企业占巴西国内生产总值的近 30%、该国出口的 40% 和劳动力的 20%。巴西在技术创新和调整现有农业实践方面处于领先地位，可以引领气候变化倡议。投资者正在寻找基于自然的解决方案、硬件和软件方案，以及不过分依赖政府补贴的合理商业模式（例如通过 &lt;a href=&quot;https://collabfund.com/blog/the-villain-test /&quot;>;小人测试&lt;/a>;)。突出显示的公司包括 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.plenty.ag/&quot;>;Plenty&lt;/a>;、&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bcdbio.com/&quot;>;BCD Bioscience&lt;/a>;*和 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.strellabiotech.com/&quot;>;Strella Biotech&lt;/a>;。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;● &lt;strong>;AI&lt;/strong>; 两个关键信息在整个活动中引起共鸣：1）我们不知道我们不知道什么，以及 2）人工智能的变革潜力，这将影响我们生活的几乎每个方面。 Alexander Wang 和 Peter Norvig 呼吁谨慎推出人工智能技术，并深思熟虑其全球影响。 Khosla Ventures 的 Vinod Khosla 和 Atlantico 的 Julio Vasconcellos 传播了对技术的乐观和热情。他们引用了&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@vkhosla/reinventing-societal-infrastructure-with-technology-f71e0d4f2355&quot;>;用技术重塑社会基础设施&lt;/a>;）。查看 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mercadodiferente.com.br/&quot;>;Diferente&lt;/a>;* 是如何&lt;a href=&quot;https://exame.com/bussola/diferente-lanca-ia- que-cria-receitas-com-itens-da-cesta-de-organicos/&quot;>;使用人工智能&lt;/a>;进行库存管理和食谱推荐。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;● &lt;strong>;筹款市场&lt;/strong >;：全面感受到市场明显放缓，轮次结束时间更长，估值压缩，区域退出流动性短缺。然而，这些条件也使其成为构建的好时机，因为我们已经看到团队非常专注于单位经济、资本效率和确定 PMF。麦肯锡在活动期间发布了&lt;a href=&quot;https://latamdigitalreport.mckinsey.com/&quot;>;2023 拉丁美洲数字报告&lt;/a>;。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有一件事在会议期间没有提到——政治。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为委内瑞拉人，看到巴西人聚在一起讨论长期趋势、创新机会以及国家政策的正确方向，我感到耳目一新。毕竟，技术发展是一股能托起所有船只的涨潮。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在 BSV 之后的一周，里约热内卢举办了&lt;a href=&quot;https://rio.websummit.com/&quot;>;网络峰会&lt;/ a>; – 一项吸引了 20,000 多名与会者的技术活动。此后，许多主要利益相关者聚集在纽约市，参加由 Itau、BTG 和美国银行主办的活动。我有幸参加了在纽约举办的 Itau 女性领袖大会，以表彰 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ingridsilvaballet.com/&quot;>;Ingrid Silva&lt;/a>;。虽然事件的增加并不一定等于创新的激增，但不可否认的是，它表明人们对巴西作为全球首要技术发展中心的兴趣不断升级。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有关与以下方面相关的本地和国际技术事件的精彩内容巴西创业生态系统，查看 &lt;a href=&quot;https://substack.com/profile/38241540-julia-de-luca&quot;>;Julia de Luca&lt;/a>; 和 &lt;a href=&quot;https://abreu. substack.com/&quot;>;Lucas Abreu&lt;/a>; 的时事通讯。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现在就计划明年加入我们的 BSV，&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.latitud.com /en/vamoslatamsummit&quot;>;圣保罗的 Vamos Latam 峰会&lt;/a>;，或纽约市的&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brazilclimatesummit.com/&quot;>;巴西气候峰会&lt;/a>;。&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;来自委内瑞拉风投公司的高度赞赏。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Luisa&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;*表示 Collab Portfolio Company&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 05 Jun 2023 16:46:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/brazil-at-silicon-valley/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/brazil-at-silicon-valley/</guid></item><item><title>注意</title><description>&lt;p>;夏洛克·福尔摩斯在&lt;em>;血字的研究&lt;/em>;一书中说：&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;我认为一个人的大脑本来就像一个空荡荡的小阁楼，你必须用你选择的家具储存它。一个傻瓜把他遇到的所有种类的东西都吸收了，这样可能对他有用的知识就被排挤了，或者充其量是与许多其他东西混在一起，以至于他很难整理自己的知识...关注是很难的、被忽视的，最重要的是，这是一种消极技能——它是关于你故意忽略的和你积极寻找的一样多。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Francis Crick，他发现了双螺旋结构DNA，曾被问及获得诺贝尔奖需要什么条件。他回答说：“哦，这很简单。我的秘诀是我知道该忽略什么。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作者约翰·巴里 (John Barry) 写道：&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;据报道，爱因斯坦曾经说过，他自己的主要科学才能是他能够观察一个物体大量的实验和期刊文章，选择极少数既正确又重要的，忽略其余部分，并在正确的基础上建立理论。&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;我最好的阅读策略遇到的是&lt;a href=&quot;https://collabfund.com/blog/how-to-read-lots-of-inputs-and-a-strong-filter/&quot;>;宽漏斗和严密过滤器&lt; /a>;。愿意阅读任何看起来有点有趣的东西，但如果它不适合你，请毫不留情地迅速放弃它。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;选择进入阁楼的内容。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我发现的其他一些事情有助于选择要关注的内容：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;在阅读文章、书籍或报告时，问：“一年后我还会关心这个吗？ ”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;五年？十岁？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大多数时候您会发现自己不会在意一周内阅读的内容。这是新闻——也许它很有趣，但它有一个有效期。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有两种类型的知识：过期的和永久的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;过期的知识是季度收入、选举民意调查、市场信息和政治。它引起了比应有的更多关注，原因有二。第一，有很多，渴望抓住我们短暂的注意力。第二，我们追逐它，急于在它失去相关性之前挤出洞察力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;永久性知识往往是帮助您理解过期信息的原则和框架。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我读过每天的报纸和书籍。我不记得我在报纸上读到的一件事，比如 2011 年。但我可以告诉你一些很棒的细节 &lt;a href=&quot;https://collabfund.com/blog/23-books-that-c​​hanged- my-life/&quot;>;我在 2011 年读过的书&lt;/a>;以及它们如何改变了我的思维方式。我会永远记住他们。我会继续看报纸。但是，如果我读更多的书，我可能会开发出更好的过滤器和框架，以帮助我更好地理解新闻。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;询问您将在多长时间内关心您阅读的信息会促使您专注于永恒的事物，很少关心暂时的事物——一种长期思考的好心态。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;记住故事，突出事实，跳过废话&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有一个我爱的台词：人们不记得书本；他们记得句子。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;更具体地说，他们记得故事。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;即使在您读过的最好的书中，您还记得什么？几句话，几个故事。这些句子和故事可能会改变您的生活，但它们是您从一本书中学到的全部内容。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我在阅读时努力记住这一点。对于几乎每一篇博文和大多数非小说类书籍：没有必要对每一个字都精打细算。如果我能记住一些伟大的故事和史诗般的台词，那就是一个胜利。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;太多的读者陷入了细节，他们无论如何都不会记住，而他们本可以写出一些令人难忘的台词离开一本书并转到下一本书。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;当您钦佩的人不同意您热衷的话题时，请密切注意。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;查尔斯·达尔文按照查理·芒格的说法，他并不是特别聪明，但却成为了一流的科学家，因为他一生都在努力证明自己是错误的。 “从达尔文那里学到的最重要的事情之一就是极端客观性的价值，”芒格曾经说过。 “他一得到想法就试图否定他的想法。他很快在笔记本上记下了任何与一个备受喜爱的想法不符的东西。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是一个了不起的技巧，对于大多数人来说，否定自己信仰的方法是关注那些不同意你的人.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但这很难，因为很容易假设那些不同意你的人不如你聪明或见多识广。很多好想法都被忽略了，或者被故意拒绝了，因为它们出自你不敬佩的人之手。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果你没有幸运地拥有完美的同理心，那么敞开心扉接受你的观点的诀窍就是不同意就是找到那些在你尊重的话题上有观点的人——勾选你脑海中的方框，上面写着“这个人并不疯狂”——然后听取他们关于你不同意的话题的看法。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当这两件事是一致的——你钦佩的人在一些基本问题上不同意你——密切注意。这很有可能是您希望存储在脑海中的信息。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 31 May 2023 16:28:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/paying-attention/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/paying-attention/</guid></item><item><title>期望债务</title><description>&lt;p>;我住在西雅图，亚马逊是我们的巨头。我三分之一的邻居都在公司工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当亚马逊在 2021 年登上世界之巅时——名声在外，股价在飙升——你能感受到自豪和繁荣。你几乎可以闻到它的味道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我曾经听说 90% 的文化只是“获胜”——当一家公司获胜时，每个人都会快乐、富有、得到晋升，他们认为他们的工作有助于&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那是 2021 年的亚马逊。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然后 Jeff Bezos 离开了，股价下跌了 50%，10,000 名员工被解雇，还有数十万人担心他们“ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;那&lt;/em>;现在是我家附近飘荡的气味。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;它是如此清晰，如此明显，情绪是如何转变的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; p>; &lt;p>;那么问题来了：您如何称呼亚马逊在 2021 年的世界顶级地位？是礼物吗？努力工作的奖励？资本主义的自然波动？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;是的，所有这些。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但还有另一种方式来看待它：预期债务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;预期如此之高在 2021 年，投资者和员工必须取得非凡的成就才能实现收支平衡。 When results were merely good, they felt terrible.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Expectations are like a debt that must be repaid before you get any joy out of what you&#39;re doing.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The hard thing is that every company and every employee wants to have what Amazon had in 2021 – winning, wealth, prestige, reputation. But look at what it led to now, after the expectations debt was repaid.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Was it worth it? Hard to say.&lt;/p>; &lt;hr />; &lt;p>;The Nikkei – the Japanese stock market equivalent of the Dow Jones – recently closed at its highest level since 1990.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are two ways to look at that: As a win, or as an example of one of the worst-performing stock markets of modern times.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But here&#39;s what&#39;s most interesting about the Japanese stock market.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Returns over the last 33 years were terrible.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But returns from 1965 to 1990 were &lt;em>;extraordinary&lt;/em>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Nikkei and the S&amp;amp;P 500 have had very similar returns over the last 57 years.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/Screenshot%202023-05-25%20at%208.02.46%20AM.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot 2023-05-25 at 8.02.46 AM.png&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the Nikkei earned all of those returns during one massive 25-year surge, while the S&amp;amp;P 500 has been comparatively more even.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/Screenshot%202023-05-25%20at%2010.21.50%20AM.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot 2023-05-25 at 10.21.50 AM.png&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I don&#39;t think it&#39;s fair to say the Japanese stock market stagnated over the last 33 years. What really happened is that 50 years of returns were stuffed into a 25-year period in the late 20th century, and the past three decades of misery has just been repaying that excess.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Here again, high expectations in 1990 were like a debt that had to be repaid before investors could benefit.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No one got a statement for that debt; it didn&#39;t show up on anyone&#39;s balance sheet; no one knew what the interest rate would be. But it was very real debt that anchored investors down, destroyed wealth, and took a third of a century to pay down.&lt;/p>; &lt;hr />; &lt;p>;An asset you don&#39;t deserve can quickly become a liability.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Maybe your portfolio surged during a bubble, your company hit a monster valuation, or you negotiated a salary that exceeds your ability. It feels great at the time. But reality eventually catches up, and demands repayment in equal proportion to your delusions – plus interest.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These debts are easy to ignore because they are often repaid in the form of self-doubt and crushed morale. But they are very real, and when you understand their power you become careful what you wish for.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Companies should want the valuation they deserve, and not a penny more.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Workers should want a salary that matches their skill, and nothing more.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Families should want a lifestyle they can sustain, and nothing higher.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;None of those are about settling or giving up. It&#39;s about avoiding a certain kind of psychological debt that comes due when reality catches up.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There&#39;s a stoic saying: “Misfortune weighs most heavily on those who expect nothing but good fortune.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Expecting nothing but good feels like such a good mindset – you&#39;re optimistic, happy, and winning. But whether you know it or not you&#39;re very likely piling up a hidden debt that must eventually be repaid.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 25 May 2023 11:41:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/expectations-debt/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/expectations-debt/</guid></item><item><title> “Mars is for Quitters” —Sara Ledterman</title><description> &lt;p>;Joining Forces with Harvard University&#39;s Wyss Institute to Create Better Materials for Earth.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The goal of this alliance is to invent and commercialize the next great, worldchanging material – one that&#39;s as cheap, versatile, and high-performance as the last worldchanging discovery, plastic, but without the negative side effects. By leveraging synthetic biology, we plan to fuel sustainable options that surpass even Goretex in their efficacy and commercial success.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Developing new materials that are both better for our planet and better for consumers presents a massive economic and ecological opportunity. Yet, despite the incredible potential, there&#39;s been surprisingly little change in materials over the past several decades. Plastic, metal, wood, glass, and synthetic fibers comprise nearly everything we consume.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason? Fossil fuels. All of these materials rely on hydrocarbons for production and processing, which make them terrible for the environment, but also more accessible, cost effective, and difficult to replace.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While the field is still emerging, there are a few notable companies that have been at the forefront of commercializing sustainable materials using synthetic biology:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ginkgo Bioworks&lt;/strong>;: Ginkgo Bioworks designs and manufactures a variety of products, including flavors, fragrances, and materials.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Solugen&lt;/strong>;: Solugen produces sustainable chemicals, such as hydrogen peroxide and solvents, from plant-based sources. The company&#39;s technology platform uses enzymes and renewable feedstocks to create products that are more sustainable and cost-effective than their traditional petroleum-based counterparts.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zymergen&lt;/strong>;: Zymergen (acquired by Ginkgo) designs and manufactures novel materials, such as adhesives, coatings, and films, that are more sustainable and high-performing than their traditional counterparts.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These companies serve as a preview of the types of opportunities we anticipate emerging in the next decade and beyond. Synthetic biology is a rapidly emerging field that combines biology, engineering, and computer science to design and construct new biological systems. By harnessing the power of living organisms, synthetic biology has the potential to revolutionize the way we produce materials, food, and energy.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That&#39;s why we&#39;re teaming up with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://wyss.harvard.edu/&quot;>;Wyss Institute for Biologically Inspired Engineering at Harvard University&lt;/a>;. Established in 2009, the Wyss Institute is a world class R&amp;amp;D center focused on ground-breaking technologies that emulate nature. Together, we&#39;re excited to announce the launch of the &lt;strong>;Laboratory for Sustainable Materials Research and Innovation&lt;/strong>; to create new intellectual property (IP) and bring novel sustainable materials to the market. Our joint efforts will explore the development of biomimetic materials that replicate the properties of natural substances, as well as bio-based materials derived from renewable resources.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These materials hold the promise of reducing our reliance on fossil fuels, decreasing greenhouse gas emissions, and minimizing waste in production processes. Additionally, these innovations have the potential to create entirely new markets and disrupt existing ones, offering attractive financial returns for investors.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://wyss.harvard.edu/&quot;>;Wyss Institute&lt;/a>; is the perfect home for such an ambitious new lab. The Wyss Institute at Harvard University is a world leader in the field of biologically inspired engineering. By emulating nature&#39;s design principles, the Institute develops innovative solutions for a variety of industries, including healthcare, energy, and manufacturing. With its multidisciplinary approach and state-of-the-art facilities, the Wyss Institute is uniquely positioned to contribute its synthetic biology expertise to the partnership.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The consumer product goods (CPG) and heavy industries sectors are both major contributors to global greenhouse gas emissions and resource depletion. By investing in and commercializing sustainable materials, our partnership with the Wyss Institute aims to drive a paradigm shift in these industries.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We can&#39;t wait to update you on all the exciting technologies that will emerge from this pioneering alliance. Together, we believe Collab and the Wyss Institute will drive a new wave of materials innovation while establishing an exciting new model that accelerates the journey from scientific discovery to market realization by uniting academia and venture capital. This alliance aims to invest in and develop cutting-edge sustainable materials using synthetic biology, with the ultimate goal of generating outstanding financial returns and creating a far-reaching positive environmental impact in consumer product goods and heavy industries.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you&#39;re a visionary researcher, scientist, or entrepreneur pursuing innovative ideas in the realm of biomaterials, please reach out. We&#39;d love to hear from you and explore opportunities to collaborate towards a sustainable future.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;– Sophie and Craig&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;(PS We are excited about space and its potential, but are devoting our time and energy on solving problems for Earth)&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 23 May 2023 08:19:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/mars-is-for-quitters/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/mars-is-for-quitters/</guid></item><item><title> The Spectrum of Financial Dependence and Independence</title><description> &lt;p>;&lt;em>;“I did not intend to get rich. I just wanted to get independent.” – Munger&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Place yourself, your business, and other people you know, on this list.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Level 0: Complete financial dependence on the kindness of strangers who have no vested interest in your success&lt;/strong>;. Panhandling when unable to work, or companies reliant on raising money from first-time investors who don&#39;t care if you fail.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Level 1:&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;Complete financial dependence on people who want you to succeed because they like you and their reputation is attached to your success.&lt;/strong>; Children under age 15 – supported by their parents and generally too young to work – fall into this category. So do companies backed by friends and family who don&#39;t intend on getting their money back.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Level 2: Complete financial dependence on people with a vested interest in your financial outcome&lt;/strong>;. Unprofitable-but-promising businesses backed by investors who could earn a meaningful return on their investments, and are thus likely to keep supporting you.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Level 3: Ability to partially support yourself by&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;adding value for others while still somewhat reliant on external support&lt;/strong>;. Young people who work but rely on their parents to support what they consider basic lifestyle necessities. Or companies that could realistically be profitable if they changed their cost structure, but continue to raise money from investors to fund growth.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Level 4: Ability to fully support yourself by adding value for others, but value that is marginal and easy to replace&lt;/strong>;. This is a common category for both people and businesses. It is grinding and tenuous. It smells like independence, but a boss or customer still owns your day and can dictate your future. Your future relies on their decisions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Level 5:&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;Enough savings to cover run-of-the-mill problems&lt;/strong>;. You can endure hassles that every person or company should expect to experience on a regular basis, without getting wiped out.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Level 6: Enough savings to cover large, unforeseen problems&lt;/strong>;. You still rely on your boss or your customers to get by month to month, but if a crisis struck you&#39;d probably be OK for a reasonable period of time.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Level 7: Retirement savings, education savings, and avoidance of consumer and auto debt&lt;/strong>;. You still rely on bosses and customers, but you can foresee a time when your current savings will open up a new level of independence for you and your family. This is the most realistic goal for most people.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Level 8:&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;The ability to pick a job, or specific customers, that avoids the most egregious examples of bullshit and unnecessary hassle in your life.&lt;/strong>; You still rely on bosses and customers, but have the freedom to say, “No, not you. I&#39;ll find someone else,” when you get too frustrated.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Level 9:&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;Becoming comfortable enough with your social status that you don&#39;t feel the need to flash your peacock feathers with expensive consumer goods whose only value is in signaling&lt;/strong>;. The inability to do this is a hidden form of debt and dependence that exists, and it piles up on people who mistakenly think they&#39;re wealthy enough to be independent.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Level 10: The ability to say no to banks, whose debt you don&#39;t need, including mortgages.&lt;/strong>; Debt can be cheap capital but it keeps you beholden to others, owning a piece of your future decisions and cash-flow needs.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Level 11:&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;Few realistic situations would cause you, your company, or your family to be pushed back below Level 5.&lt;/strong>; You could support yourself for a year or more off your liquid savings. It&#39;s the first true stage of independence. You can now say “No” to almost anyone, with high odds of recovering from the repercussions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Level 12: Interest and dividends cover more than half of your living expenses&lt;/strong>;. Most of this independence is owed to a slim lifestyle, rather than huge assets. You realize that lifestyle desires compound faster than almost any asset.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Level 13: Your assets and their reasonable return expectations will cover basic living expenses for longer than your life expectancy&lt;/strong>;.恭喜。 You are no longer reliant on bosses or clients. You can deal with them if you want, and you probably will. But only if you want, when you want, with who you want. Which feels good.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Level 14:&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;Your assets cover above-basic living expenses with assets and their reasonable return expectations&lt;/strong>;. You can define “above-basic” however you want. Varies by person. Remember what Chris Rock says: “If Bill Gates woke up with Oprah&#39;s money he&#39;d jump out the window.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Level 15:&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;Independence lets you do and say what you please, unconcerned with other people disagreeing with you&lt;/strong>;, since you don&#39;t rely on the support or opportunities they could offer.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Level 16:&lt;/strong>; Meaningful philanthropy is the only reasonable way your assets won&#39;t compound faster than you spend.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This, to me, is one of the most important topics in finance.每个人都不一样。 But while almost everyone can adapt to their stuff, having control over your time through independence will always feel great when you have it and always be a miserable burden when you don&#39;t.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 16 May 2023 03:49:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/the-spectrum-of-financial-dependence-and-independence/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/the-spectrum-of-financial-dependence-and-independence/</guid></item><item><title> Vicious Traps</title><description> &lt;p>;There are times in nature when two plus two equals ten – when two little things combine to form one huge thing.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A little cool air from the north is no big deal. A little warm breeze from the south is pleasant. But when they mix together over Missouri you get a tornado.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two calm water currents are not a problem. But if opposing currents meet, you get a deadly whirlpool.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bleach and ammonia are common household products. Mix them together and you get lethal chloramine gas.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In each case it&#39;s easy to underestimate risk – or at least be surprised at what happens – because the initial ingredients seem harmless. The idea that two innocent small things can combine to form one big dangerous thing isn&#39;t intuitive.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This same thing happens with personality traits.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Years ago someone told me that bubbles happen when confidence (a good trait), optimism (a good trait), trust (generally good) mix to form greed and delusion. The reason bubbles are so common is that the inputs are mostly innocent, even if the output is lunacy and destruction.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So many things are like that. Some of the most vicious traps occur when two admirable traits mix in the wrong way and create something dangerous. They&#39;re the hardest flaws to identify and fix.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Take patience and confidence. They both sound great. But mixed together they often form stubbornness, which is a disaster&lt;/strong>;. Confidence that you&#39;re right gives you permission to ignore signs that you&#39;re wrong, and patience gives you permission to extend that denial indefinitely.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Charlie Munger once said:&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;Failure to handle psychological denial is a common way for people to go broke. You&#39;ve made an enormous commitment to something. You&#39;ve poured effort and money in. And the more you put in, the more that the whole consistency principle makes you think, “Now it has to work. If I put in just a little more, then it&#39;ll all work.” People go broke that way, because they can&#39;t stop, rethink, and say, “I can afford to write this one off and live to fight again. I don&#39;t have to pursue this thing as an obsession in a way that will break me.”&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;In general: People who are panicking know they&#39;re panicking. People who are being dishonest know they&#39;re being dishonest. But those in a patience-confidence trap have no idea, because both traits on their own seem so positive.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Or curiosity and boldness. They are wonderful on their own, but combined can easily create impulsiveness&lt;/strong>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It&#39;s almost impossible to be successful in business without being both curious and bold – new ideas plus the ability to act on them. Think of what happens when you&#39;re not curious and bold: Either dull and bold – I don&#39;t even know what that looks like – or curious and timid, which is … an academic maybe?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But without some sort of brake, curiosity and boldness are so easy to spin into impulsiveness.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Part of this is realizing the &lt;a href=&quot;https://collabfund.com/blog/natural-maniacs/&quot;>;first rule of very successful people&lt;/a>;: Those who think in unique ways you admire are likely to also think in unique ways you don&#39;t admire. A lot of people who are admired for thinking, “&lt;em>;I wonder what would happen if we tried something different&lt;/em>;” are the same people who become despised for doing something different that doesn&#39;t work, or loses money, or hurts other people.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Elon Musk with Twitter is an example (so far).&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huge and successful companies expanding into fields they have no experience in is another (AIG, General Electric).&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dig into any successful business and you&#39;ll likely find two people: One who comes up with crazy ideas, and another who kills most of those ideas while giving the sensible ones a shot.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You would never have heard the name Walt Disney if it weren&#39;t for his brother Roy&#39;s ability to tame wild ambition into viable business ventures. Walt had such a singular focus on creating good animation that, if left to his own devices, he&#39;d push every project past its breaking point. His early ventures went bankrupt before Roy joined and hit the brakes.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Walt, as you might imagine, often viewed Roy&#39;s balance as anchoring his ambition. That&#39;s why curiosity and boldness are so dangerous – they feel like the right traits, even when they&#39;re the biggest risk to your success.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;How about humility and ambition? Excellent traits, but together they can create successfully disguised arrogance.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When you&#39;re humble (“I am fortunate, and could not have achieved this without other peoples&#39; help”) but ambitious (“I am talented, and can achieve more than I already have”), the mental conflict often settles with hidden arrogance (“I am special, but I can&#39;t say that out loud).&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;False modesty might be more dangerous than explicit ego because it hides – even inside your own head – your intentions and motivations.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The right balance is knowing what you&#39;re good at and not being afraid to say it while being just as eager to share what you&#39;re not great at.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But that&#39;s rare – especially in the social media age – where performative humility is everywhere, often the consequence of two innocent traits coming together, which makes it so hard to acknowledge. It&#39;s a vicious trap.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 04 May 2023 16:04:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/vicious-traps/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/vicious-traps/</guid></item><item><title> Raise Your Hand If You Like To Win</title><description> &lt;p>;We are excited to kick off a search for two new team members to join us as part of our two-year Associate program. Here at Collab Fund, the first question we ask ourselves when evaluating a new investment opportunity is: If this startup becomes massively successful, will it make the world a better or more interesting place?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/CFAssociateProgram2023-06e71b.png&quot; alt=&quot;CFAssociateProgram2023-06e71b.png&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We are focused on investing in businesses that are pushing the world forward, while also aiming to outpace the market and produce alpha returns over the next decade and beyond. To do this, we ask ourselves a second but vital question: Would a &#39;villain&#39; invest in this company if their motive was one of pure self-interest? We call this &lt;a href=&quot;https://collabfund.com/blog/the-villain-test/&quot;>;the villain test&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We believe that the greatest returns (financial and social) in venture often come from contrarian thinking and the best path to seeing things differently is by surrounding yourself with different and unique perspectives.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Our ideal candidates for the position include being:&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>;Entrepreneurial&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;Hard working&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;Optimistic&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;Intellectually curious&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;Self-starting&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;Excited to live in New York&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;p>;The Associates will work closely with our Partners and the entire Collab team on both sourcing and evaluating new investments as well as supporting existing portfolio companies.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to offering all the things you&#39;d expect (comprehensive and competitive compensation and benefits package including bonus, paid holiday leave, sick leave, health and dental insurance, team offsites, and 401k) we offer the opportunity to work at a firm constantly pushing the status quo. We have created a culture where we wake up feeling inspired and motivated to contribute fully everyday, not because we have to, but because we want to.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Here&#39;s some additional miscellaneous stuff you may (or may not) care about:&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>;Founded in 2010, our venture funds invest in early (pre-seed) through early growth stage (Series B and C) companies&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;Our primary focus is investing at the early stages (seed+)&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;We&#39;ve also raised various thematic funds with specific mandates focused on areas including (i) &lt;a href=&quot;https://collabfund.com/blog/collaborative-fund-and-sesame-workshop-launch-collabsesame/&quot;>;kids&lt;/a>;, (ii) &lt;a href=&quot;https://collabfund.com/blog/consumer-startups-are-a-great-investment-heres-why/&quot;>;consumer&lt;/a>; and (iii) most recently, &lt;a href=&quot;https://collabfund.com/blog/collab-sos-a-new-fund-and-a-call-to-action/&quot;>;sustainability&lt;/a>;&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;p>;How do you apply? The first step is to fill out &lt;a href=&quot;https://forms.gle/eaE8mjQ4cdYt6XZV9&quot;>;this form&lt;/a>; by May 31st and we will let you know by June 15th if you have been selected for an interview. We expect the process to be finalized by the end of August, with new hires available to start work in New York in September.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And if it isn&#39;t the perfect fit for you but you know the ideal candidate, please email me directly at andrew [at] collabfund.com. If we end up hiring the person you recommend, we will give $1000 to the charity of your choice.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If this sounds interesting to you, we would love to connect!&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;—Andrew Montgomery&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 01 May 2023 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/associate-program/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/associate-program/</guid></item></channel></rss>