<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>合作基金</title><description>Collab Fund 是企业家推动世界前进的主要资金来源。</description><link/> https://collabfund.com<atom:link href="https://collabfund.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 22:26:31 -0500</pubDate><lastbuilddate> 2023 年 11 月 6 日星期一 22:26:31 -0500</lastbuilddate><generator>站点叶</generator><item><title>我的新书：一如既往</title><description>&lt;p>;我的新书&lt;em>;一如既往：永不改变的指南&lt;/em>;今天出版。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;您可以在 &lt;a href=&quot;https:// 上购买。 www.amazon.com/gp/product/0593332709&quot;>;亚马逊&lt;/a>;和&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/same-as-ever-morgan-housel/1143292859&quot;>;巴恩斯&amp;amp;高贵&lt;/a>;。 （印度&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.in/Same-Ever-Timeless-Lessons-Opportunity/dp/1804090948&quot;>;此处版本&lt;/a>;，英国&lt;a href=&quot;https://www .amazon.co.uk/Same-Ever-Timeless-Lessons-Opportunity/dp/1804090638&quot;>;此处版本&lt;/a>;）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;书籍很难，从开始到结束需要多年的努力。但我很高兴你能读到这篇文章。我认为这是我写过的最好的作品。写起来很有趣！我希望您阅读它的乐趣就像我喜欢写作它的一半一样。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我的第一本书，&lt;em>;金钱心理学&lt;/em>;，实际上是关于你个人的行为方式的。 &lt;em>;一如既往&lt;/em>;是关于我们作为一个集体的行为方式以及我们一遍又一遍地做的事情。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是 23 个短故事，讲述了在不断变化的世界中永不改变的事物。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;我的整个职业生涯都在思考这本书。我一直对预测持怀疑态度，因为世界在预测下一次经济衰退、下一次选举或下一次技术方面的记录非常糟糕。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这应该会让你想到一个问题：什么永远不会发生改变？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们&lt;em>;确定&lt;/em>;什么将成为我们未来的一部分？&lt;/p>; &lt;hr />; &lt;p>;我曾经和一个人共进午餐与沃伦·巴菲特关系密切的人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这个人——我们称他为吉姆（化名）——2009 年末与巴菲特一起开车在内布拉斯加州奥马哈行驶。此时全球经济陷入瘫痪，奥马哈也不例外。商店关门了，企业都用木板封起来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吉姆对沃伦说，“现在情况太糟糕了。经济如何从中反弹？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沃伦说，“吉姆，你知道 1962 年最畅销的糖果是什么吗？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“不知道。”吉姆说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“士力架，”沃伦说。 “你知道今天最畅销的糖果是什么吗？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“不知道，”吉姆说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“士力架，”沃伦说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;然后沉默。谈话到此结束。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;历史充满了任何人都无法预料到的惊喜。但它也充满了如此多永恒的智慧。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果你穿越到 500 年前或 500 年后，你会惊讶于技术和医学发生了多么大的变化。地缘政治秩序对你来说毫无意义。语言和方言可能完全是外来的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是你会注意到人们陷入贪婪和恐惧，就像他们在当今世界一样。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;你会看到人们被说服以您熟悉的方式应对风险、嫉妒和部落关系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;您会看到过度自信和短视，这让您想起人们今天的行为。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;您会发现人们寻找幸福生活的秘密，并试图在没有任何确定性的情况下以完全相关的方式找到确定性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当传送到一个陌生的世界时，你会花几分钟观察人们的行为并说， “啊。我以前见过这个。和以前一样。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我希望你喜欢阅读它。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 01:44:00 -0500</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/my-new-book-sa​​me-as-ever/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/my-new-book-sa​​me-as-ever/</guid></item><item><title>狂野的思想</title><description>&lt;p>;2021 年东京奥运会期间，世界上最好的马拉松运动员埃柳德·基普乔格 (Eliud Kipchoge) 被关在候补室里。他和另外两名跑步运动员——比利时的巴希尔·阿卜迪和荷兰的阿卜迪·纳吉耶——在马拉松比赛结束后等待领取奥运奖牌，这是基普乔格第二次获胜。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;颁奖典礼的后勤工作意味着跑步者必须在狭窄、沉闷的房间里等待几个小时，除了坐着之外无事可做。 Abdi 和 Negeeey 后来解释说，他们做了其他人都会做的事情 - 他们拿出手机，找到 Wi-Fi 网络，漫无目的地滚动社交媒体。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kipchoge 没有。&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;Abdi 和 Negeeey 说他只是坐在那里，盯着墙壁，完全沉默和满足。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;几个小时。&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“他不是人类，”阿卜迪开玩笑说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;他不是人类&lt;/em>;。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他不像普通人那样思考、行动或表现。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; >; &lt;p>;该短语的一些变体可以用于您的大多数榜样。你喜欢他们，因为他们做的事情别人永远不会考虑，甚至无法理解。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其中一些特质非常棒，你应该尊敬他们，甚至尝试效仿。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; >; &lt;p>;其他人则不然。 &lt;em>;很多&lt;/em>;并非如此。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人类生存条件中固有的一点是，那些以你喜欢的独特方式思考世界的人几乎肯定也会以你喜欢的独特方式思考世界。不会喜欢。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这很容易被忽视，并且导致我们对于我们应该尊敬谁以及我们应该从非常成功的人身上期望什么做出错误的判断。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;关键是，必须将独特的思想作为一个整体来接受，因为他们做得好的事情和我们钦佩的事情不能与我们自己不想要或看不起的事情分开。&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;让我告诉你一个关于战斗机飞行员的简短故事，每个人都需要他，但没有人能够忍受。&lt;/p>; &lt;hr />; &lt;p>;约翰·博伊德可能是有史以来最伟大的战斗机飞行员。&lt;/p>; &lt;他对他的领域的革命性超过了之前或之后的任何人。他写的一本手册《空中攻击研究》将数学融入到战斗演习的科学中，就像工程师在建造飞机时使用的数学一样。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他的见解简单而有力。在其中，博伊德意识到战术优势不在于飞机能飞多快或多高，而在于它能以多快的速度改变航向并开始爬升——这一发现不仅改变了飞行员的思维方式，还改变了飞机的制造方式。他简直就是一个飞行专家。博伊德在 20 多岁时写的手册成为战斗机飞行员的官方战术指南。它至今仍在使用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;博伊德被认为是军事史上最有影响力的思想家之一。正如《纽约时报》曾经&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2003/03/09/books/40-second-man.html&quot;>;所写的那样，他也被描述为&lt;/a>;，“即使在空军中，也是一个虚拟的非人。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那是因为博伊德虽然聪明，但他是个疯子。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他很粗鲁。不稳定的。忤。不耐烦。他对上级大喊大叫，令同事们大吃一惊，还曾因纵火没有适当暖气的机库而差点被送上军事法庭。在会议上，他会嚼掉手上的老茧，并将死皮吐到桌子上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;空军喜欢并且需要博伊德的见解。但他们无法忍受博伊德这个人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;博伊德的典型特征是，他以与其他飞行员完全不同的视角来思考驾驶飞机。就像他使用了与其他人不同的大脑部分，玩着不同的游戏。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同样的性格使他自然而然地对既定习俗漠不关心。因此，他的上级会在同一份绩效报告中对他的贡献赞不绝口，但随后又试图阻止他的晋升。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一篇评论说，“这位才华横溢的年轻军官是一位独创性的思想家”，但接着又说，“他是一个紧张而缺乏耐心的人，对严密的监督反应不佳。他对那些试图阻碍他的计划的人极其不能容忍。”当博伊德正在撰写有关战斗机演习的权威书籍时，两名上校否认了他的晋升。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;博伊德最终获得了晋升。他太有才华了，不可能没有。但在他的整个职业生涯中，没有人知道该拿他做什么。他惹恼了很多人。他在各方面都是独一无二的——好的、坏的、可怕的，有时甚至是非法的。&lt;/p>; &lt;hr />; &lt;p>;约翰·梅纳德·凯恩斯曾经在拍卖会上购买了一批艾萨克·牛顿的原始论文。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;许多东西以前从未见过，已经在剑桥藏了几个世纪了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;牛顿可能是有史以来最聪明的人。但凯恩斯惊讶地发现，大部分作品都致力于炼金术、巫术，并试图寻找永生药剂。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;凯恩斯 &lt;a href=&quot;https://mathshistory.st-andrews .ac.uk/Extras/Keynes_Newton/&quot;>;写道&lt;/a>;：&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;我应该说，我已经浏览了至少 100,000 个单词的大量内容。完全不可能否认它完全是神奇的，完全没有科学价值。也不可能不承认牛顿为此付出了多年的努力。&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;我想知道：尽管牛顿沉迷于魔法，但他还是一个天才，或者对看似不可能的事情感到好奇是什么让他如此成功？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我认为这是不可能知道的。但疯狂的天才有时看起来很疯狂的想法几乎是不可避免的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;电影&lt;em>;巴顿&lt;/em>;中有一个场景，扮演二战传奇将军乔治巴顿的演员遇到了战后他的俄罗斯同行。俄罗斯将军通过翻译提议敬酒。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我向将军致意，”巴顿说，“但请告诉他，我不想和他或任何其他俄罗斯儿子一起喝酒。一个婊子。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;翻译员惊呆了，并说她无法转达该消息。巴顿坚持认为。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;俄罗斯将军通过翻译回应说，他认为巴顿也是个王八蛋。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;巴顿歇斯底里地大笑，举起酒杯，说道：我可以喝的东西。从一个王八蛋到另一个王八蛋！”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这可以完美地概括极其成功的人的运作方式。当然，他们也有不正常的特征。这就是他们成功的原因！我们不应该假设所有这些异常特征都是积极的、礼貌的、可爱的或有吸引力的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我长期以来一直认为这是真的，当你寻找它时，它会不断出现，就是在某件事上异常擅长的人往往在其他事情上异常糟糕。就好像大脑只能容纳这么多的知识和情感，而异常的技能会剥夺某人性格其他部分的带宽。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以埃隆·马斯克为例。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;什么样的 32岁认为他们可以同时对抗通用汽车、福特和 NASA？ &lt;em>;一个彻头彻尾的疯子&lt;/em>;。这种人认为正常的约束不适用于他们——不是以一种自私的方式，而是以一种真诚的、骨子里相信的方式。这也是那种不担心推特礼仪等问题的人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;能够将个人财富倾注到殖民火星上的心态，并不是那种担心夸张的负面影响的心态。 。那种提出通过不断在火星大气层中投放核弹来使火星变得适宜居住的人，并不是那种担心超越现实界限的人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那种说有 99.9999% 的可能性的人人性是计算机模拟，不是那种担心向股东做出站不住脚的承诺的人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那种承诺在试图拯救泰国儿童足球队的几天内解决密歇根州弗林特市水问题的人在帐篷里重建特斯拉 Model 3 装配线几天后，他被困在一个山洞里，他并不是那种认为律师签字是关键一步的人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人们喜欢这位有远见的天才马斯克的一面，但希望它没有在他扭曲的“我不在乎你的习俗”版本的现实中运作的一面。但我认为这两件事不能分开。它们是相同性格特征的风险回报权衡。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;约翰·博伊德也是如此。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;史蒂夫·乔布斯也是如此，他既是天才又是怪物。老板。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沃尔特·迪士尼也是如此，他的野心将他接触过的每一家公司推向破产的边缘。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美国前国家安全顾问麦克乔治·邦迪曾经告诉约翰·F·肯尼迪总统：试图登上月球是一个疯狂的目标。肯尼迪回应道：“除非你有一定的勇气，否则你不会在四十多岁的时候竞选总统。”&lt;/p>; &lt;hr />; &lt;p>;部分原因是意识到有能力实现令人难以置信的事情的人经常会冒险。这可能会适得其反。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;什么样的人能够登上一家成功公司或一个大国的高层？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;意志坚定、乐观的人不会”不要接受“不”的答案，并对自己的能力充满信心。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;什么样的人可能会做得太过分，贪得无厌，并且对显而易见的风险不予理会对其他人来说？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;意志坚定、乐观、不接受“不”的答案，并且对自己的能力充满信心的人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;均值回归是一种历史上最常见的故事。它是经济、市场、国家、公司、职业——一切的主角。发生这种情况的部分原因是，将人们推向顶峰的相同性格特征也增加了将他们推向悬崖边缘的可能性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于国家，尤其是帝国来说，情况确实如此。一个决心通过获取更多土地来扩张的国家不太可能由一个能够说“好吧，够了。让我们感谢我们所拥有的一切，并停止入侵其他国家。”他们将继续努力，直到遇到对手。小说家斯特凡·茨威格 (Stefan Zweig) 说：“历史上没有任何征服者因征服而被征服的例子”，这意味着没有征服者得到他们想要的东西然后退休。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;也许这个主题最重要的部分是更好地洞察我们应该尊敬谁，特别是我们想成为谁以及我们想效仿谁。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Naval 曾经写道：&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;我们羡慕的人的那一部分并不没有那个人的其他部分，我就不会存在……有一天，我意识到，对于所有这些我嫉妒的人，我不能只选择他们生活中的小方面。我不能说我想要他的身体，我想要她的钱，我想要他的个性。你必须是那个人。你想真正成为那个拥有所有反应、欲望、家庭、幸福水平、人生观、自我形象的人吗？如果你不愿意与那个人进行大规模、24/7、100％的交换，那么嫉妒就没有意义。&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;要么你想要别人的生活或者你不这样做。两者都同样强大。在寻找榜样时只需知道哪个是哪个。&lt;/p>; &lt;hr />; &lt;p>;“你必须挑战所有假设。如果你不这样做，那么第一天的教条就会永远成为教条，”约翰·博伊德曾经说过。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这就是你将永远被铭记的哲学 - 无论好坏。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 17:51:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/wild-minds/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/wild-minds/</guid></item><item><title>我最近读过的聪明的东西</title><description>&lt;p>;“在我们知道自己错了之前，错误的感觉就像是正确的一样。” – David McRaney&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我只是一组镜子，反映了其他人对我的期望。” – 罗洛·梅&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“基本上，当你到了我这个年纪，你会真正衡量你生活中是否成功的标准是，有多少你想要爱你的人实际上爱你。我认识一些很有钱的人，他们会得到见证晚宴，并会得到以他们的名字命名的医院翼楼。但事实是世界上没有人爱他们。如果你到了我这个年纪，却没人看好你，我不管你的银行存款有多大，你的生活就是一场灾难。” – 沃伦·巴菲特&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“如果你对一个主题的看法可以从你对另一个主题的看法中预测出来，那么你可能已经被一种意识形态所束缚。当你真正独立思考时，你的结论将是不可预测的。” – 凯文·凯利&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“当我写完书评时，我经常会对自己说，‘好了！现在没有人必须读这本书了。我已经为他们把它简化了。如果作者自己做这项工作，我们的情况会更好。” – 阿诺德·金&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“生活不是一个需要解决的问题。这是一个需要经历的悖论。你可以相信一件事，也可以相信它的反面。” – 德里克·西弗斯&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“道德是你在事后感觉良好，不道德是你在事后感觉糟糕。” – 欧内斯特·海明威（我认为他在理想上是错误的，但在现实上是正确的）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“获得世界上最差医疗保健的人是非常贫穷的人和非常富有的人。富人可以向医生提出任何疯狂的要求。” –（我忘了我在哪里听到的这句话。它指的是100年前的医疗保健。千真万确。）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“邪恶通常在打开门并让它进来的人没有意识到的情况下进入世界。大多数作恶的人并不认为自己所做的事是恶事。邪恶主要存在于旁观者的眼中，尤其是在受害者的眼中。” – Roy Baumeister&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“人们怀念的不是过去的样子，而是过去本来可以的样子。”斯维特兰娜·博伊姆&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“乍看之下，怀旧是对一个地方的向往，但实际上它是对另一个时间的向往——我们的童年时光，我们梦想的缓慢节奏。” – Svetlana Boym&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“怀旧是没有罪恶感的历史。” – Svetlana Boym&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;纳西姆·塔勒布 (Nassim Taleb) 曾经写道，出版商总是试图推动作者撰写针对最近新闻事件的特定主题。 “不，不;恰恰相反，”他写道。 “如果你想在未来被阅读，请确保你在过去也被阅读过。我们不知道未来会发生什么，但我们对过去有一些了解……我推测二十年前相关的书籍（当然前提是今天相关）二十年后会很有趣”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我努力不嘲笑人类的行为，不为它们哭泣，不恨它们，而是理解它们。” – 巴鲁克·斯宾诺莎&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们存在的一个奇怪特征是，我们来自一个非常擅长促进生命但更擅长消灭生命的星球。” – Bill Bryson 论进化&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“在生活中，只要有可能，就优化独立性而不是付费。如果你有独立性，并且你对你的输出负责，而不是你的输入——那就是梦想。” – Naval&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“被恶魔驱使的人会做事很糟糕。” – 沃尔特·艾萨克森 (Walter Isaacson) 描述埃隆·马斯克&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“创造力的最高形式是在一系列限制条件下即兴创作。” ——克里斯托弗·诺兰&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“一位父亲希望能像他的孩子们一样非凡，在他们的天真中想象他的样子，这样他们就永远不会对他失望。也许有些父亲做到了这一点。” – 大卫·冯·德雷勒&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;查理·芒格职业成功公式：&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>; &lt;p>;不要出售任何你自己不会买的东西。&lt;/p>; &lt;/ li>; &lt;li>; &lt;p>;不要为任何你不尊重和钦佩的人工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;/li>; &lt;li>; &lt;p>;只与你喜欢的人一起工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;/li >; &lt;/ul>; &lt;p>;关于怀旧的俄罗斯谚语：“过去比未来变得更加不可预测。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“能力是当你能有所收获时你有多优秀。品格就是当你一无所获时你有多优秀。人们会因为你的能力而奖励你。但人们只会因为你的性格而爱你。” – 马克·曼森&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我写下了太多的历史，以至于无法相信它。” – 亨利·亚当斯&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“花了很长时间才取得成功。我想说，回想起来，我很高兴花了这么长时间，因为这很有趣。” – 芒格&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;哈维·费尔斯通：&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;为什么一个人一拿到足够的钱，就建造一座比他需要的大得多的房子？&lt;/p>; >; &lt;p>;我在阿克伦有一所房子，比我最少用的房子大很多倍；我在迈阿密海滩还有另一所房子，它也比我需要的大得多。我想在我死之前我会购买或建造其他的房子，这些房子也会比我需要的大。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我不知道我为什么这样做——房子只是一种负担。但我做到了，有钱的朋友都有大房子。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;也许这是古代封建思想的一些愚蠢的残余，大房子意味着坚固的房子，可以在里面保留一支小军队。保护。在少数情况下，建造一栋大房子只是为了炫耀自己有钱；有时会建造一座大房子，以便进行精彩的娱乐活动。但在大多数情况下，尤其是对于那些自己挣钱的人来说，房子才刚刚建成，建成后，没有人完全知道为什么要开始建造它。无数人把他们的房子建得那么大，以至于他们还不如住在酒店里。&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;“本·格雷厄姆曾经谈论第一类和第二类真理。第一类真理是绝对的。第二类真理因信念而成为真理。如果有足够多的人认为一家公司的股票价值 X，那么它就会变得价值 X，直到有足够多的人不这么认为。” – 巴菲特&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“幸福不是你经历的，而是你经历的。”这是你记得的事情。” – 奥斯卡·黎凡特&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 17:20:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/smart-things-ive-read-lately/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/smart-things-ive-read-lately/</guid></item><item><title>人工智能让地球更凉爽：Phaidra 对抗数据中心排放的使命</title><description>&lt;p>;随着计算需求呈指数级增长，像 Phaidra 这样的人工智能对于遏制排放是必要的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;任何曾经遭受过这种情况的人&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/ pmc/articles/PMC4292129/&quot;>;笔记本电脑燃烧&lt;/a>;可以理解计算能力会产生热量。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;就像您的笔记本电脑一样，数据中心 - 其中包含为&lt;a href=&quot;https: //about.netflix.com/en/news/what-the-latest-research-on-streaming-emissions-tells-us&quot;>;Netflix&lt;/a>; 至 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nasa. gov/centers-and-facilities/nssc/nccips/&quot;>;NASA&lt;/a>; - 也会产生热量，必须缓解这些热量才能保持这些服务器的正常运行。因此，冷却是数据中心环境中最大的能源使用来源之一。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3 id=&quot;the-data-center-energy-crisis&quot;>;数据中心能源危机&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;事实上，到 2021 年，世界各地的数据中心消耗的能源&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.voyagervc.com/news-and-letters/decarbonizing-data&quot;>;与英国大致相同&lt;/ a>; – 大约相当于&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iea.org/energy-system/buildings/data-centres-and-data-transmission-networks&quot;>;全球用电量的1-2%&lt;/ a>;。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;考虑到即将到来的计算海啸：人工智能，能源消耗预计只会加速。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种繁荣将被设定为&lt;a href=&quot;https: //www.mckinsey.com/industries/technology-media-and-te communications/our-insights/investing-in-the-rising-data-center-economy&quot;>;两倍或三倍&lt;/a>;数据中心。就上下文而言，这&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_countries_by_electricity_conspiration&quot;>;意味着&lt;/a>;数据中心将比世界上除美国以外的任何国家承担更多的电力需求美国和中国。&lt;/p>; &lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/energyforecast.r1.png&quot; alt=&quot;数据中心能源使用趋势和效率图表策略”/>;来源：&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.akcp.com/blog/the-real-amount-of-energy-a-data-center-use/&quot;>;AKCP&lt;/a>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;数据中心和分布式计算系统已经消耗了世界总发电量的很大一部分。如果没有技术创新，这种能源需求和相关的温室气体排放可能会大幅增加。数据中通过提高数据中心的性能来抵消数据中心不断增长的能源需求。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这就是我们最近主导投资 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.phaidra.ai/&quot;>; 的原因Phaidra&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3 id=&quot;phaidras-ai-solution&quot;>;Phaidra 的人工智能解决方案&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Phaidra – 由 AlphaGo 的先驱之一、Katie 的 Veda Pannershevlvam（CTO）创立霍夫曼（总裁兼首席运营官）领导了特灵与 Deepmind 的合作，高吉姆（首席执行官）在 Deepmind 构建了框架，通过 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.deepmind 减少了谷歌数据中心的能源使用.com/blog/deepmind-ai-reduces-google-data-centre-cooling-bill-by-40&quot;>;近 40%&lt;/a>; – 正在利用人工智能来优化数据中心和其他关键任务设施的效率.&lt;/p>; &lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/deepmind.r1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Google PUE 逐年下降图表。&quot; />; 来源：&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.deepmind.com/blog/deepmind-ai-reduces-google-data-centre-cooling-bill-by-40&quot;>;Deepmind&lt;/a>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;Phaidra 不仅仅是为人类提供实施建议，他们还使用&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TmPfTpjtdgg&quot;>;强化学习&lt;/a>; - 唯一的机器学习的一个分支，它产生行动，而不仅仅是预测 - 直接控制数据中心冷却和其他功能，同时确保最严格的保障措施得到维护。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Phaidra 与首批财富 100 强试点客户的结果令人震惊。实施一年内，他们能够节省 10-15% 的能源。就背景而言，一家公司估计，能源减少 10% 相当于每个设施每年节省 2-300 万美元的能源。客户不需要任何可持续发展激励措施就能发现 Phaidra 的产品引人注目——经济效益已经足够了（Collab 的 &lt;a href=&quot;https://collabfund.com/blog/the-villain-test/&quot;>;Villain 的一个典型例子工作中进行测试&lt;/a>;）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是一项巨大的技术突破。世界上没有其他公司能够自主控制大型工业设施。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3 id=&quot;how-it-works&quot;>;工作原理&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Phaidra 通过插入设施的现有系统（无需新硬件），通常通过建筑管理系统 (BMS) 或监控和数据采集 (SCADA) 系统。这会将来自传感器的数千个数据点直接输入 Phaidra 的人工智能代理，使 Alfred（团队亲切地称呼它）能够识别并实施（实时）最大化设施性能的行动，包括能源消耗、二氧化碳排放、稳定性、机器性能等。运行时间和许多其他变量。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/Screenshot%202023-10-23%20at%204.59.31%E2%80%AFPM。 png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot 2023-10-23 at 4.59.31 PM.png&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这与当今工业自动化的工作方式截然不同。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;工业设施，例如数据中心依赖于不适应不断变化的条件的硬编码规则（由数千行 IF/THEN 语句组成）。这些明确编程的控制系统迫使物理工厂永久以相同的方式运行（或者直到有人硬编码新规则）——这是一个导致设施退化的次优过程。相比之下，Phaidra 的强化学习系统会随着时间的推移不断学习并变得更好，从而不断提高性能并加快 Phaidra 客户的投资回报率。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3 id=&quot;moving-beyond-data-centers&quot;>;超越数据中心&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;虽然优化数据中心的机会足够大（无论是在经济回报还是潜在的气候影响方面），但 Phaidra 有潜力超越数据中心环境。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;他们的算法是一个通用框架，可以应用于从提高发电厂转换效率到帮助制造设施提高吞吐量的任何事情。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大型工业系统可以实现更多的效率提升。随着计算需求呈指数级增长，像 Phaidra 这样的人工智能对于遏制排放是必要的。 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.phaidra.ai/&quot;>;Phaidra&lt;/a>; 优雅地部署人工智能来优化自身，说明了技术对气候的双重承诺和危险。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 07:55:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/ai-for-a-cooler-earth/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/ai-for-a-cooler-earth/</guid></item><item><title>团队建设</title><description>&lt;p>;胜利是由团队完成的，我现在对协作基金的团队感到非常兴奋。两周前我们在纽约聚会。这是一场混乱。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们迎来了几位跨核心职能部门的新员工，包括投资、运营和我们的平台团队。看到 Collaborative 中的人才团结在一起真是太酷了。这体现了我们所有人都应该兴奋的使命的共鸣，也体现了我为之自豪的支持后起之秀的记录。最重要的是，这些新团队成员带来的广泛经验和观点将使我们能够更好地为我们的创始人和投资者提供未来的服务。介绍完毕后，我们深入讨论了基金业绩、如何更好地支持我们不断增长的投资组合以及新兴的兴趣领域。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/a1. png&quot; alt=&quot;a1.png&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们会议的一些亮点包括：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;- 新兴的拉丁美洲创业生态系统&lt;/strong>; - 我们就我们如何最好地帮助这个快速增长地区的创始人进行了富有洞察力的讨论。我们很高兴能够继续发展与当地合作伙伴的关系，获得文化熟练程度，并为创始人提供长期支持。就背景而言，在过去 18 个月中，我们投资了该地区的许多初创公司，包括：&lt;strong>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mercadodiferente.com.br/&quot;>;Diferente&lt;/a >;&lt;/strong>;、&lt;strong>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://kanastra.com.br/en/&quot;>;喀纳斯特拉&lt;/a>;&lt;/strong>;、&lt;strong>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// ruuf.cl/&quot;>;Ruuf Solar&lt;/a>;&lt;/strong>;、&lt;strong>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.soyplenna.com/&quot;>;Plenna&lt;/a>;&lt;/strong>; 和 &lt;strong>; >;&lt;a href=&quot;https://fu.do/es/&quot;>;Fu.do&lt;/a>;&lt;/strong>;。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/ uploads/b1.png&quot; alt=&quot;b1.png&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;- 地热能令人兴奋的潜力&lt;/strong>; - 我们探索了地热技术如何能够实现永远在线、清洁的能源基荷发电。然而，我们也认识到，要实现地热的全部前景，需要有效的政策倡导和愿意支持长期投资的耐心资金。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;- GLP-1 药物如何改变行为&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;- GLP-1 药物如何改变行为&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;- GLP-1 药物如何改变行为我们对未来进行了一次发人深省的讨论，未来这些类型的药物不仅可以治疗糖尿病，还可能更广泛地影响饮食和生活方式的选择。精准医疗的未来能力看起来既极其复杂，又充满希望。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在我们的战略会议结束后，我们参观了&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.royalpalmsbrooklyn.com/&quot;>;皇家棕榈沙狐球俱乐部&lt; /a>; - 一个很棒的地方（带来&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/948151585/bring-shuffleboard-back-to-brooklyn-on-its-100th-a&quot;>;生活&lt; /a>; 部分由 Collab Fund 投资组合公司 Kickstarter 提供），并享受了一些不错的老游戏和美味的食物。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/c1.png&quot; alt=&quot;c1.png&quot; />;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;这次聚会使我们的目标更加明确，并对我们所有杰出的同事表示赞赏。在一个似乎每天都在加速变化的世界中，像这样定期聚集在一起制定战略并调整引人注目的机会对于我们继续推动风险投资走向未来绝对至关重要。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;前进！&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 08:59:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/teambuilding/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/teambuilding/</guid></item><item><title>致富的几条法则</title><description>&lt;p>;全球10位最富有的人中有13人离婚。前十名中的七人至少离婚过一次。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;相关性不是因果关系，而且样本量很小。但是，在一个生活被很多人羡慕的群体中，在一个对幸福如此重要的话题上，一个比全国平均水平差得多的统计数据很有趣，不是吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有一个致富的方式有数百万种，其中大多数都涉及利用特定的利基市场和一次性机会，更不用说运气了。关于如何致富的普遍规则很难找到。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是赔钱，或者在有钱的时候失去幸福，或者成为金钱的奴隶——这些故事往往有共同点。它们非常常见，您可以将其称为法律。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;衡量财富很容易。你只要数一下就可以了。衡量财富的一些负面影响要困难得多，也更加微妙。它们是如此微妙且难以衡量，以至于许多人甚至不相信它们的存在。财富的&lt;em>;缺点&lt;/em>;？这怎么可能？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;让我提出，谈论财富的负面影响是荒谬的，这也是为什么财富并不能让人们像他们想象的那样幸福的部分原因。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当金钱的好处如此明显，但缺点又如此微妙时，你没有预料到的缺点可能比你预期的好处更令人震惊。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，我想要更多的钱。几乎每个人都这样做，尽管出于不同的原因。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这不是一份反财富清单——只是一系列容易被忽视的微妙缺点，而且如此常见，你不妨称它们为唯一真正的法则致富。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;1.生活中大部分让你快乐的事情与金钱无关，意识到一旦你有钱可能是一个痛苦的承认。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;威尔·史密斯在他的传记中写道，当他很穷的时候&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一旦他变得富有，这种乐观情绪就消失了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他有”郁闷直到你的梦想成真。一旦你的梦想成真，你意识到你的感觉和以前一样，你就会感到绝望。&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;幸福很复杂，但如果你把它简化成一个充满爱的家庭这样的事情、健康、友谊、八小时睡眠、平衡的孩子，以及成为比你自己更大的事情的一部分，你就会意识到金钱的作用是多么有限。并不是说它没有作用；而是它没有作用。只是比你想象的要小。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这样想：你愿意每年赚 10 万美元，有一个爱你的配偶、钦佩你的孩子、好朋友、身体健康、问心无愧吗？ ，或者赚了 1,000,000 美元却什么都没有？这是很明显的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，你可以贫穷而痛苦，也可以富有而快乐。但只有富人知道这种关系有多么脆弱。赚钱可能并不能改善你的婚姻，它不能让你的朋友更喜欢你，也不能让你更满足。因此，曾经对金钱可以为你做的令人安慰的乐观情绪，现在被金钱不能为你做的严酷现实所取代。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有时，梦想是感觉良好的，一旦你实现了它，梦想消失了，你实际上变得沮丧。 Malcolm Forbes：当我们成功时，我们已经拥有了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;2.你所认为的对自己成功的钦佩实际上可能是嫉妒。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;说唱歌手德雷克曾经说过，“人们更喜欢你在为某件事而努力的时候，而不是当你拥有它的时候。”&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;很难判断这种转变何时发生，富人通常认为自己受到钦佩，但实际上却受到嫉妒。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作者罗伯特·格林 (Robert Greene) 曾经写道： &lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;永远不要愚蠢地相信你通过炫耀使你超越他人的品质来激起钦佩。通过让别人意识到自己的劣势，你只会激起不愉快的钦佩或嫉妒，这会侵蚀他们，直到他们以你无法预见的方式削弱你。&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;这尤其重要当你致富的原因是通过某种形式宣传你的成功，让其他人愿意帮助和支持你时，情况确实如此。当钦佩变成嫉妒时，支持就会减少，人们对你的错误的容忍度就会减少。如果一位无名记者写了一本书间接地为萨姆·班克曼-弗里德辩护，没有人会在意——他们实际上可能会祝贺作者。 But since Michael Lewis did, the pitchforks came out.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thoreau said, “Envy is the tax which all distinctions must pay.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;3. The richer you become, the less likely people around you are to tell you when you&#39;re wrong, crazy, mean, or oblivious.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Matt Damon says, “You retard socially and emotionally the moment you become famous. Your experience of the world is never the same.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The same may be true – and far more common – for those who become wealthy.没有人会以同样的方式对待你。 And the worst part is that you may not even know it.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Artist Damien Hirst &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.idler.co.uk/article/interview-damien-hirst/&quot;>;once said&lt;/a>;:&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;They all love you.银行爱你，会计师也爱你，因为他们拿走了你的钱。每年你都会有越来越多的人。一个人拿走 10%，然后另一个人拿走 10%，另一个人拿走 10%，这就是一场盛大的聚会。 The people who give you the overdraft are your best mates as well, smiling at you and telling you that you&#39;re amazing so you keep doing it.&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;Sometimes people take advantage of you intentionally, prying some benefit out of you.其他时候，他们不应该认真对待你。 A big problem with bubbles is the reflexive association between wealth and wisdom, so a bunch of crazy ideas are taken seriously because a temporarily rich person said it.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Buffett once explained:&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;I was at my best at giving financial advice when I was twenty-one years old and people weren&#39;t listening to me.我本可以站起来说出最精彩的话，但不会受到太多关注。 And now can say the dumbest things in the world and a fair number of people will think there&#39;s some great hidden meaning to it or something.&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;4. Sometimes what made you successful was worry and anxiety, and you can&#39;t let go of that when you&#39;re rich.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I think what many people really want from money is the ability to stop thinking about money.有了足够的钱，他们就可以不再思考这个问题，而专注于其他事情。 It&#39;s this weird relationship: They become obsessed with making money with the hope that someday they can ignore it altogether.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That obsession is fueled by stress and anxiety. It often shows up as career ambition, aggressive investing, and Type-A motivation.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Then, once they become rich, they realize they can&#39;t let go of that stress. It&#39;s become ingrained in their identity.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They work 80 hours a week because they want to eventually never have to work at all. But once they have enough money to retire, they can&#39;t cut back because they don&#39;t know how to do anything else in life but work.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A lot of financial planners I&#39;ve talked to say one of their biggest challenges is getting clients to spend money in retirement.即使是适当的、保守的金额。 Frugality and savings become such a big part of some people&#39;s identity that they can&#39;t ever switch gears.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I think for some people that&#39;s actually fine. Watching money compound gives them more pleasure than they would get spending it.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But those whose ultimate goal is to stop thinking about money are stuck. Refusing to recognize that you&#39;ve met your goal can be as bad as never meeting the goal to begin with.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;5. There is no easy way to manage wealth and kids.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Charlie Munger was once asked by one of his rich friends if leaving his kids a bunch of money would ruin their drive and ambition.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Of course it will,” Charlie said. “But you still have to do it.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Why?” the friend asked.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Because if you don&#39;t give them the money they&#39;ll hate you,” Charlie said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Like a lot of Munger advice, I think this interaction is designed to be memorable. It&#39;s probably 80% true.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But by and large, he&#39;s right. Those are the two options for the rich: Ruin their ambition with inheritance, or risk some form of strife by denying them an easy life.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Warren Buffett once said that he often hears rich people talk about how dangerous a welfare society is, creating a generation of moochers reliant on food stamps and unemployment benefits.但他说，“这些人给他们的孩子留下了终生可用的食品券等等”。 “他们没有福利官员，而是信托基金官员。 And instead of having food stamps, they have stocks and bonds that pay dividends.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course there are exceptions.但大多数例外——继承金钱的富家子弟并不会影响他们的野心——是因为孩子很特别，而不是因为父母一定做出了明智的决定。即使18岁的比尔盖茨继承了10亿美元，也不会阻止他的野心。史蒂夫·乔布斯和埃隆·马斯克也是如此。 Mark Zuckerberg was offered $1 billion cash for Facebook when he was 22 and he didn&#39;t blink, didn&#39;t even consider it.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But those are the rare birds. Most people need to be driven by fear of not making it.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My friend Chris Davis &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3GTpG8ePCaw&amp;amp;ab_channel=TheCompound&quot;>;grew up in a wealthy household&lt;/a>; – his grandfather is legendary investor Shelby Davis, who turned $50,000 into almost $1 billion – and was told when he was young that he wouldn&#39;t see a penny of it because his family didn&#39;t want to rob him of the opportunity of making it on his own.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chris joked: “They could have robbed me &lt;em>;just a little&lt;/em>;.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It&#39;s never easy.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;6. Quick wealth is fragile wealth.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I love the idea that the speed in which you made your wealth is the halflife for how fast you can lose it.一年内你的钱翻倍？当您以同样的速度失去一半时，请不要感到惊讶。闪电式扩张？ Blitz failing.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two things happen with quick, fragile wealth.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One is that money that comes easily tends to be spent easily.当钱来得快的时候，把钱花在无意义的事情上的情感成本就很低。只有当某件事对你来说很珍贵时，你才会小心翼翼。花掉你没有投入太多时间或精力来赚钱的快钱感觉就像是一夜情：冲动且容易后悔。 Old money wants a tax shelter, new money wants a Lambo.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The other is that the quicker the wealth was made, the higher the odds it came from luck that will revert just as fast.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Put those two together, and whenever you see a surge of quick wealth – crypto in 2021 was a good example – you know it&#39;s going to end poorly, as luck converts to risk and conspicuous consumption converts to inconspicuous lifestyle debt.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;7. Reputations have momentum in both directions because people want to associate with winners and avoid losers.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The more successful you are the more people want to be associated with you – which is great.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But that&#39;s equally powerful in reverse.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Someone early in their career can screw up and recover quickly, moving onto the next company. A successful person or company has each flaw blared across the news, saturating the gossip channels of their network.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lehman Brothers&#39; 2008 struggles made front-page national news; a small community bank could have been at its wits end with hardly a soul aware.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A company like Sears also fits this bucket: Everyone is aware how strained it is, so no one – customers, employees, investors, vendors – wants to be associated with it.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It&#39;s like the saying, “The higher the monkey climbs on the pole, the more you can see its ass.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;8. Expectations can rise faster than income, so a higher income sends expectations spiraling out of control.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wealth is relative.奢华是相对的。 Both are just a comparison between what you have and what other people have.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A quirk I have seen many times is that some of the wealthiest people are the most prone to expectations spinning out of control, because they become hyper aware of how other rich people live.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1907, author William Dawson wrote about how the feeling of wealth is relative to what you&#39;re accustomed to:&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;A man of education, accustomed to easy means, would suffer tortures unspeakable if he were made to live in a single room of a populous and squalid tenement, and had to subsist upon a wage at once niggardly and precarious. He would be tormented with that memory of happier things, which we are told is a &#39;sorrow&#39;s crown of sorrow.&#39;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the man who has known no other condition of life is unconscious of its misery.他没有比较的标准。一个会让一个有教养的人产生自杀念头的环境，不会让他产生太多的不满。 Hence there is far more happiness among the poor than we imagine.&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;To drive home his point: Dawson was himself fairly successful and accustomed to easy means by the standard of his day.但道森于 1928 年去世，他一生的大部分时间都没有电或空调。他从未服用过抗生素、Advil 或脊髓灰质炎疫苗。 He never experienced reasonably accurate weather forecasts, or an interstate highway.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An average American today sent back in time to experience Dawson&#39;s life would suffer the same “tortures unspeakable” he wrote about. But he didn&#39;t have modern times to compare his life to, so it felt luxurious to him.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Everything good in life is just &lt;a href=&quot;https://collabfund.com/blog/expectations-and-reality/&quot;>;the gap between expectations and reality&lt;/a>;, and when your main frame of reference are other rich people trying to impress each other, that gap can close quickly.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;9. No one is going to remember you in 100 years.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So you might as well focus on what&#39;s going to make you happy now, instead of what money might buy you in the future.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a Scottish proverb: Be happy while you are living, for you are a long time dead.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 11:38:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/a-few-laws-of-getting-rich/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/a-few-laws-of-getting-rich/</guid></item><item><title>大胆与鲁莽之间的一线之隔</title><description>&lt;p>;Cornelius Vanderbilt had just finished a series of business deals to expand his railroad empire.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One of his business advisors leaned in to tell Vanderbilt that every transaction he agreed to broke the law.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“My God, John,” &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2DymfK7&quot;>;said&lt;/a>; Vanderbilt, “You don&#39;t suppose you can run a railroad in accordance with the statutes of the State of New York, do you?”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My first thought when reading this was: “That attitude is why he was so successful.”在范德比尔特时代，法律并不支持铁路建设。所以他说“管它呢”，然后还是继续了。范德比尔特取得了巨大的成功，因此人们很容易把他的藐视法律的行为——这臭名昭著，但却对他的成功至关重要——视为圣人的智慧。 That scrappy visionary let nothing get in his way!&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But how dangerous is that analysis?没有一个理智的人会推荐公然犯罪作为一种创业特征。 You can easily imagine Vanderbilt&#39;s story turning out much different – an outlaw whose young company collapsed under court order.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So we have a problem here.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;People could praise Vanderbilt for flouting the law with as much passion as they criticize Enron for doing the same.约翰·D·洛克菲勒 (John D. Rockefeller) 也有类似之处：他经常规避法律——一位法官曾称他的公司“不比普通小偷好多少”——经常被历史学家描述为狡猾的商业智慧。也许是的。 But when does the narrative shift from, “You didn&#39;t let outdated laws get in the way of innovation,” to “You committed a crime?”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It&#39;s hard to know.我认为我们只能根据结果来判断过程。 Which is dangerous.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The hardest thing about studying businesses and investors is that many traits that fueled their success could have just as easily triggered failure. But we rarely think about it that way when learning from specific outcomes.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Those eager to learn from others tend to look at the tails.大赢家做对了什么？大输家做错了什么？通常很难从两者中找到可行的结论，因为赢家和输家经常采取类似的冒险策略，而结果却因偶然而略有倾斜。我的观点是，巨大的成功需要挑战传统智慧，但传统智慧通常是正确的并且值得遵循。 We&#39;re left with outcomes where winners are praised more than they should be, losers criticized more than they deserve.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There&#39;s more to this than breaking laws.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The majority of Benjamin Graham&#39;s investing success &lt;a href=&quot;http://jasonzweig.com/was-benjamin-graham-skillful-or-lucky/&quot;>;is due to&lt;/a>; owning shares of Geico.他最初的购买以及随后以高估值持有该股票，几乎打破了格雷厄姆本人在其著名著作中制定的所有规则。 What are we supposed to learn from that?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We think Mark Zuckerberg is a genius for turning down a big offer to sell his company.但人们批评 Groupon 和 Yahoo!也同样热衷于拒绝他们的大笔收购要约。 What is the lesson for entrepreneurs here?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Uber took no prisoners as it disrupted the entrenched taxi market.但事实证明，支持一家斗志旺盛的初创公司和“#DeleteUber”之间的界限微乎其微。 Which case study will be taught in business schools?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Countless fortunes (and failures) owe their outcome to leverage.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The best (and worst) managers drive their employees as hard as they can.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The customer is always right” and “customers don&#39;t know what they want” are both accepted business wisdom.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The line between “inspiringly bold” and “foolishly reckless” can be a millimeter thick and only visible with hindsight. But it&#39;s easy to view the process that led to successful outcomes as something to emulate, and the process that led to failures as something to avoid.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I don&#39;t think there&#39;s much we can do about this. It&#39;s one of those things that just &lt;em>;is&lt;/em>;. Risk is unfair and unforgiving.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But a few things are worth thinking about.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Focus less on case studies and more on broad patterns&lt;/strong>;.案例研究可能很危险，因为我们研究极端的例子，而考虑到极端的例子的复杂性，它们通常最不适用于其他情况。通过寻找广泛的事物模式，例如人们如何应对意外、竞争优势有多脆弱、人/企业/经济发展的速度以及什么让人们感到高兴，你将更接近于可采取行动的事情。 This is also why &lt;a href=&quot;https://microcapclub.com/2018/01/morgan-housel-industries-teach-us-investing/&quot;>;multidisciplinary learning is so important&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Accept that strategies expire&lt;/strong>;.历史的讽刺之处在于，它主要是对事物变化的研究，通常被用作下一步行动的指南。唯一比低估别人的策略的风险更危险的是没有意识到整个策略只在不同的时代有效。 When you accept that things change over time you become less interested in specific strategies used in the past and more interested in broad topics, like how people discovered the strategies to begin with.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;There&#39;s more to learn from people who endured risk than those who seemingly conquered it&lt;/strong>;.如果成功需要承担很容易变成失败的风险，而两者之间的界限几乎是实时看不见的，那么我想向那些不小心跨过界限并活下来讲述故事的人学习。从严重衰退中幸存下来的公司。从熊市中幸存下来的投资者。失败的产品经过重新设计，然后才发挥作用。在任何冒险的努力中，成功与失败之间的界限都很窄，几乎没有人能找到它，但永远不会跨过它。因此，学习如何忍受偶尔的失误并从中幸存下来，比试图完全避免它们会收获更多。 This is why &lt;a href=&quot;https://collabfund.com/blog/the-theory-of-maybes/&quot;>;room for error and humility&lt;/a>; are so important.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“What do I care about the law?”范德比尔特曾经说过。 “Ain&#39;t I got the power?”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He did, and it worked. But it&#39;s easy to imagine those being the last words of a story with a very different outcome.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 09:07:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/the-thin-line-between-bold-and-reckless/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/the-thin-line-between-bold-and-reckless/</guid></item><item><title>充电、回收、重复：电池世界的可持续发展秘密</title><description>&lt;p>;Something amazing has been happening in the battery world: battery recycling rates have been steadily rising thanks to smart industry initiatives and consumer awareness.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Take the lead-acid batteries that power our cars for starters.据行业报告，这些电池在美国的回收率为 99%，是铝罐回收率的 2 倍。 According to Recycling Today, that makes lead car batteries the single &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.recyclingtoday.com/news/bci-study-claims-lead-batteries-most-recycled-consumer-product-in-united-states/&quot;>;most recycled consumer product&lt;/a>;. That&#39;s right - about 160 million lead batteries are collected and recycled each year, keeping more than 2.5 million tons of lead and plastic from clogging up landfills.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/Fig1_RecycledProducts.r2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Chart of top recycled products in the United States, with lead-acid batteries at the top at 99%&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It wasn&#39;t always this way.就在几十年前，只有一半的铅电池被回收。但通过电池制造商、回收商和政府之间的协调努力，基础设施和激励措施的出现使铅电池回收不仅可行，而且成为常态。这需要耐心。这需要投资。 But the industry transformed battery recycling from an afterthought into a shining example of the circular economy.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As we look forward to a future with more and more lithium-ion batteries (LiB) powering everything from our phones to the latest electric vehicles, the lead battery&#39;s success story gives reason for optimism even while current LiB recycling rates languish around 5-15%.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As electric vehicle adoption grows in the coming decades, LiB waste is expected to exceed 20 million tons per year by 2040. This seems daunting, but it also represents a huge opportunity if we can ramp up recycling efforts.许多人看到废电池的浪潮，只看到一堵废物墙。 But the scrapheap of today is the goldmine of tomorrow if we have the patience and ingenuity to extract it.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/Fig2_BatteryRecycling.r2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Chart of the global supply of EV batteries for recycling in kilotons&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recycling any complex product is hard.弄清楚物流和经济需要时间。挑战比比皆是，尤其是在收集和运输废旧电池方面。但我们有一个模板，并且有动力投资解决问题。这些电池的回收价值是巨大的。但我们以前就这样做过，企业已经在努力扩大锂电池的回收规模。 This is one of the reasons we&#39;re excited about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.redwoodmaterials.com/news/redwood-series-d/&quot;>;our investment&lt;/a>; in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.redwoodmaterials.com/&quot;>;Redwood Materials&lt;/a>; and infrastructure they have today to recycle EV and other types of batteries, extracting and re-entering valuable materials back into the battery supply chain. This Series D raise of more than $1B was on the heels of Redwood Materials &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rgj.com/story/news/money/business/2023/02/09/redwood-materials-gets-2-billion-doe-loan-for-mega-battery-facility-near-reno/69886953007/&quot;>;$2B loan from the DOE&lt;/a>;, giving the company ample capital to continue investing in scaling up capacity.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/RedwoodMaterialsFacility.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Aerial view of a Redwood Materials recycling facility.&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This won&#39;t happen overnight.我们需要建设基础设施并扩大流程。汽车制造商、电池生产商和回收商需要在复杂的价值链上进行合作。 Persistence and problem-solving are required.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at the humble lead battery for inspiration may seem archaic.您可能不会从外表上猜到，但标志性的铅电池在设计上堪称可回收性的奇迹。 Its three main components - lead, plastic, acid - are engineered to be recycled over and over in closed-loop perfection.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is recycling not as an afterthought, but as the core principle.铅电池不会被丢弃，而是会重生。 &lt;strong>;The typical new lead battery is formed from 80% recycled material. No loss of performance, just the cycle continuing. Remarkably, 83% of the lead these batteries need is sourced right here in North America, not from distant mines.&lt;/strong>; The plastic casings also find new life. All of it circulating in near-perfect loops.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Over decades, lead batteries have woven a network of manufacturing, collection sites, and recyclers across the country, with &lt;strong>;over 300,000 locations&lt;/strong>; accepting used batteries.这是一个旨在保持铅流通的生态系统。这不是一夜之间发生的。行业团体将利益相关者聚集在一起，慢慢构建智能系统并灌输负责任的电池管理。 No hype, just persistence.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The benefits of recycling go beyond reducing waste. &lt;strong>;Recycled lead requires 70% less energy to produce than mining and smelting new lead ore. Less energy means less carbon emissions.&lt;/strong>; Recycling completes the loop. Lead batteries have shown a path forward and, according to research by McKinsey &amp;amp; Company, there&#39;s hope that LiB can follow a similar path.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Replicating the lead recycling pipeline for LIBs will not be straightforward.不幸的是，回收锂离子电池的过程本质上比回收铅电池更加棘手。铅是铅酸电池中唯一的金属，可以通过简单的工艺将其与其他电池材料分离，从而产生高纯度的铅锭。 Compare this to an LIB, where the valuable metals are numerous and varied and exist in chemical mixtures that generally require more sophisticated separation methods.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lead car batteries are a recycling success story, but the even more ubiquitous single-use alkaline batteries that power our flashlights and TV remotes have followed a less inspiring path. Recycling rates for these batteries remain quite low, buoyed only by regulations that incentivize otherwise-noneconomic practices (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1878535223006020&quot;>;source&lt;/a>;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/sustainable-business/2016/apr/14/drawer-full-of-them-battery-recycling-waste-eu&quot;>;source&lt;/a>;). A key problem lies in the fact that the metals that make up an alkaline battery – mainly iron, zinc, and manganese – are so darn cheap.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Luckily for LIBs, the lithium, nickel, and cobalt that make up the bulk of material costs are quite valuable. This, combined with the massive and growing LIB market, gives us hope that LIB recycling can become profitable at scale.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Driven by this prize and the goal of increasing EV sustainability, startups like Redwood Materials, are addressing the technological challenges of separation.像他们这样的工艺能够回收高达 95% 的电池材料，以降低成本进行再利用。 That&#39;s valuable metal pulled back from the brink to offset the need for costly new mining.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/Fig3_CarbonFootprint.r2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Chart showing recycled batteries using recycled materials released 28% less emissions&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It will take some time before recycled LIB materials will be able to steal significant market share from mined minerals. The problem is that EV adoption is simply growing too fast for new battery demand to be matched by a supply of old batteries – From 2021 to 2022, the share of new car purchases that were EVs increased from 8.7% to 14% globally and from 4.5% to 7.7% in the US (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iea.org/data-and-statistics/data-tools/global-ev-data-explorer&quot;>;source&lt;/a>;).就问题而言，这是一件好事，而且它当然不应该阻碍锂离子电池回收领域的活动。 Estimates are that recycling will be able to satisfy about 7% of lithium and 11% of cobalt and nickel demand in 2030 (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0921344922003317&quot;>;source&lt;/a>;), and about double that a decade later.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most exciting thing is that we are just now nearing a critical mass where the volume of LIBs ending their service life can justify investment in building recycling gigafactories. By 2025, we should have enough recyclable battery material to manufacture &amp;gt;100GWh of new LIBs (source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mckinsey.com/industries/automotive-and-assembly/our-insights/battery-recycling-takes-the-drivers-seat&quot;>;McKinsey&lt;/a>;).得益于 2022 年《通货膨胀减少法案》，电池回收利用立法中名为“先进制造生产信贷”的条款得到了大力推动，该条款为国内电池制造和电池制造提供了 10 年的税收抵免。模块。 Under the provision, batteries recycled in the US qualify for subsidies, regardless of their origin.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Importantly, the prospect of a dual-stream market for these battery materials may redound to the benefit of recyclers.如果回收商能够实现更低的成本（包括促进绿色实践的监管激励措施），但他们无法供应整个行业，那么他们可以要求的价格可能会反映开采材料的更高成本，从而带来更高的利润。 And increasing the value of an end-of-life LIB may reduce total cost of ownership for an EV, further growing the EV market.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Importantly, the monetary profit generated per ton of battery material could approach approximately $600 by as early as 2025 according to a recent McKinsey &amp;amp; Company study. Going forward, we expect the value creation potential to grow to similar levels to the primary metals industry, which is around 30 percent depending on price developments.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/Fig4_MonetaryValue.r1.png&quot; alt=&quot;The monetary value generated per ton of battery recycling material.&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to better recycling techniques and infrastructure, there&#39;s significant opportunities in creating new kinds of batteries that are not only optimized for particular use cases but are also longer lasting and safer. For example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.byterat.io/&quot;>;Byterat&lt;/a>; provides an end-to-end cloud platform for battery research and engineering.反过来，这有助于该行业制造更好、更耐用的电池。 Similarly, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zitara.com/&quot;>;Zitara&lt;/a>; offers powerful battery management software to help better understand, manage, and maximize batteries. By extending battery life, we can reduce the amount of batteries entering recycling in the first place.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recycling this coming wave of LiB is no small challenge.但我们以前也曾面临过这个十字路口，并通过耐心投入将问题转化为进步。 If we apply those lessons, battery recycling could quietly blossom into a pillar of the circular economy, just when we need it most.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The incentives align for recycling to become the norm, not the exception.但需要有远见才能看到废弃电池的价值，并需要坚持不懈地提取它。如果我们保持这种心态，锂电池回收就有可能悄然取得胜利，在最需要的时候支持可持续发展。 The opportunity is in our hands if we have the patience.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most things that matter take patience and persistence.电池回收也不例外。 But if we apply the mindset that transformed lead battery recycling, we can do it again for LiB and other technologies.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Often the most important progress goes unnoticed precisely because it becomes so widely adopted that we take it for granted. We forget how much effort went into making recycling not just viable but normal.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Battery recycling likely won&#39;t make headlines. But it&#39;s a quiet triumph, and an encouraging reminder of our ability to build smart circular systems if we put our minds to it.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/recharge-recycle-repeat-the-sustainable-secret-of-the-battery-world/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/recharge-recycle-repeat-the-sustainable-secret-of-the-battery-world/</guid></item><item><title>潮水即将退去</title><description>&lt;p>;Like many Americans, when I was a child, my family used to take a week-long vacation in July or August.与许多家庭不同，我们不是“海滩类型”。我们开玩笑说，这是因为我的弟弟讨厌脚上热沙的感觉，但这很大程度上是因为我的父母希望我们每个夏天都能体验不同的东西。这就是说，三十年后，讽刺的是，那次被人们记住和谈论最多的旅行却是“出错”最多的那次旅行。 It isn&#39;t even close.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1992, my family decided it would be fun to visit Nova Scotia.由于我和哥哥没有出过国，父母认为这是一个北上边境的好机会。结果，我们在八月初挤进车里，沿着 95 号州际公路向北行驶。接下来是一次充满创纪录高温的旅行，乔治华盛顿大桥上的大规模备份，几次错过出口，工作紧急情况迫使我父亲飞回东海岸的一半，以及一家没有空气的酒店由于加拿大这一地区的气温很少超过 80 度，仅举几个我们遇到的“问题”。 However, these all paled in comparison to us almost getting trapped on an island in the middle of the Bay of Fundy.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While you have likely never heard of it, the Bay of Fundy has the largest tidal range in the world with a range of 16 meters versus an average range worldwide of 3.3 meters. In a single 12-hour tidal cycle, about 100 billion tons of water flow in and out of the bay, which is &lt;em>;twice as much as the combined total flow of all the rivers of the world over the same period&lt;/em>;.因此，在退潮时，您甚至可以驾驶汽车穿过底部前往各个岛屿。 The key, however, is that you have to carefully watch the clock because if you don&#39;t get back in time, you will be stuck on the island for the night.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You can see where this is going.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After my father rejoined us in Nova Scotia, he was determined to drive across the Bay of Fundy, so we headed out to explore one of the islands the next day.尽管我最初对此表示怀疑，但这实际上是一次非常酷的体验。我们看到一些人走过，而另一些人只是在里面闲逛。令我们惊讶的是，我们是唯一过路的汽车，但是当我们到达岛上时，停车场里已经有很多汽车了。 I didn&#39;t think anything of it at the time, but this would make a lot more sense in a few short hours.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/Screenshot%202023-09-29%20at%2010.19.57%20AM.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot 2023-09-29 at 10.19.57 AM.png&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After parking, we started to explore.停车场附近没什么可看的，所以我们最终偏离了汽车，比我们计划的要远一些。最终，我父亲说是时候回去了，因为他知道潮水很快就会回来。问题是我们回来时停车场已经没有车了。他们都穿越回来了。他没有意识到你需要在潮水到来之前提前返回。你不能在水涨之前偷偷溜回去。 Thankfully though, we made it back to our car just in time and crossed back over the Bay of Fundy.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, why do I bring up the Bay of Fundy and our trip to Nova Scotia?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, I have always found it interesting that the family vacation which involved the most problems is the one that comes up most often to this day.最重要的是，我们不会从负面角度谈论它。事实上，当我们中的一个人提到它时，它很大程度上会引起笑声和积极的回忆——我们如何适应炎热，我们如何找到加拿大最好的培根芝士汉堡，我们如何在高尔夫球场上开球更长时间，因为它是如此坚硬因缺雨而疲惫不堪，我妈妈如何在夜间独自穿越缅因国家森林，当然，还有我们如何差点被困在芬迪湾中部的一座岛上。让你想知道，在人们不断“追求完美”的今天——完美的家庭度假、完美的运动体验、完美的房子、完美的生活，我们是否错过了重点？ Instead of “searching for perfect”, should we instead be searching for unique experiences and embracing whatever this pursuit brings?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, it feels like the economy might be experiencing the early stages of a “Bay of Fundy” moment. Much like the tidal cycle in Nova Scotia, which sees the tide go in and out every 12-hours, the economy has been in a very advantageous tidal period for more than 12-&lt;em>;years&lt;/em>; given how long interest rates hovered near historic lows.然而，随着美联储加息速度比 1980 年代初以来的任何时期都快，经济潮流正在明显发生变化。 So far, we have just seen the earliest signs.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most obvious?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The yield curve is the most inverted it&#39;s been in two decades, gasoline prices above $4 are squeezing consumers, leading economic indicators have been trending lower for 17 straight months, office occupancy is cratering as leases roll, instability in the banking sector is rising as balance sheets fall under water as a result of higher rates, credit is expensive at best and unavailable at worst, housing affordability is at an all-time low, and corporate bankruptcies are rising, just to name a few.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The less obvious?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the wake of the financial crisis fifteen years ago, congress enacted legislation to strengthen and safeguard the financial system.更具体地说，为了防止另一场危机，监管机构通过多德弗兰克法案限制了银行再次过度扩张的能力。毫不奇怪，这导致许多银行限制放贷，专注于更少的业务渠道，并更广泛地承担更少的风险。 As is typically the case, in trying to solve the past crisis, the government may have sown the seeds for the next one.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Regulation simply shifted the risks to a different part of the economy. In this case, when Dodd-Frank forced most banks to pull back on lending, &lt;em>;plenty&lt;/em>; of people and/or funds stood ready to fill the gap.毫不奇怪，这主要来自市场中监管较少的部分，即以私人市场的形式。 With rates at historic lows, these new lenders provided capital to nearly anyone who asked for it.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The good news?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It led to an increase in sources of capital and new business formation.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The bad news?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Capital inevitability funded many more businesses and opportunities than were needed, or warranted.它还导致了无数基金的创建，其中许多基金是由从未经历过危机投资的人领导的。 Looking ahead, this could be a problematic combination.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So where does this leave us?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If I had to guess, we are likely in a similar situation to the one my family found ourselves in when we started making our way back to our car in the middle of the Bay of Fundy. In this case though, while a few cars have already left the island (see any private equity firms that raised large funds, funds that made large asset sales in 2021-2022, or companies that obtained long-term cheap debt), many more haven&#39;t.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, what is in store for those “still on the island”?更具体地说，那些拥有伟大概念但根本上无利可图的企业、在高估值下部署过多资本的风险基金以及认为利率将永远保持在低位的贷款人？我怀疑许多人会发现自己陷入困境，无法获得资金和其他重要资源；只是不是一晚，而是可能好几年。 Some will survive long enough to eventually get off the island, but many more will not.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While this will likely still take time to unfold in the private markets, it appears to already be well underway in the public markets with the average small-cap stock in the Russell 2000 down more than 33% from its 52-week high.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the meantime, for those who managed to get off the island in time or passed on visiting the island altogether (ie, those who took less risk, did not get overextended, and/or have plenty of cash on hand), it might make sense to spend time trying to make a distinction between those that will eventually get off and those that will not, because when those that get off do, they will likely be available for &lt;em>;very&lt;/em>; attractive prices.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 13:14:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/the-tide-is-going-out/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/the-tide-is-going-out/</guid></item><item><title>书面文字</title><description>&lt;p>;A few thoughts I have about writing:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Writing is an art, and art is subjective&lt;/strong>;.小说家威廉·莫恩说过，优秀的写作需要遵循三个规则。 “不幸的是没有人知道它们是什么。”我实际上认为有一个：写你喜欢读的东西。为自己写作是很有趣的，这一点也表明了这一点。 Writing for others is work, and it shows.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Good writing is a performance&lt;/strong>;.马克吐温曾经大声朗读他的家人并观察他们的反应。如果他看到他们感到无聊，他就会把那部分剪掉。如果他看到他们变得兴奋，他就会在该部分加倍努力。 People don&#39;t remember what you wrote as much as they remember how they felt when they read it.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;A good story is like leverage for ideas&lt;/strong>;.故事利用思想，就像债务利用资产一样。 A idea on its own might be boring, but if you tell a good story about someone interacting with that idea, you can get people to nod their heads and pay attention.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;People don&#39;t remember books, blogs, or articles&lt;/strong>;.他们记住句子。这应该是你的目标：收集令人难忘的句子。 One good line is infinitely more powerful than a few clumsy paragraphs.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Most good writing is a byproduct of good reading&lt;/strong>;.你永远不会遇到一个不把大部分时间花在阅读上的好作家。不是一些。 &lt;em>;Most&lt;/em>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Writing is an efficiency game&lt;/strong>;. Whoever says the most stuff in the fewest words wins.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;But efficient doesn&#39;t necessarily mean brief&lt;/strong>;.有900页的书，每一个字都增值。 Efficient just means every line is a delight to read.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Don&#39;t try to build up to your point&lt;/strong>;.这是造成漫无目的的最大原因，也是你失去读者的地方。 The beginning of a story should be as pleasurable to read as the big idea that comes later.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;The best books I&#39;ve read have short chapters&lt;/strong>;.即使它们是很长的书，它们也会将内容分成快速的部分，让您不断前进。 It keeps the author succinct and makes the reader feel like they&#39;re progressing.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Big words mask little thoughts&lt;/strong>;. They&#39;re an attempt to fool the reader into thinking you&#39;re smart when you have nothing smart to say.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Don&#39;t overthink it. Just start writing&lt;/strong>;.伟大的音乐家在即兴演奏中找到他们的音乐——无组织、没有计划，只是看看会发生什么。我认为好的写作也是一样的。如果你想太多，你就会陷入困境。 Start with one brave sentence and see where it goes.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 26 Sep 2023 16:23:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/the-written-word/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/the-written-word/</guid></item></channel></rss>