<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>合作基金</title><description>Collab Fund 是推动世界前进的企业家的主要资金来源。</description><link/> https://collabfund.com<atom:link href="https://collabfund.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><pubDate> Wed, 31 May 2023 16:36:57 -0400</pubDate><lastbuilddate> 2023 年 5 月 31 日星期三 16:36:57 -0400</lastbuilddate><generator>网站叶</generator><item><title>注意</title><description>&lt;p>;夏洛克·福尔摩斯在&lt;em>;血字的研究&lt;/em>;一书中说：&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;我认为一个人的大脑本来就像一个空荡荡的小阁楼，你必须用你选择的家具储存它。一个傻瓜把他遇到的所有种类的东西都吸收了，这样可能对他有用的知识就被排挤了，或者充其量是与许多其他东西混在一起，以至于他很难整理自己的知识...关注是很难的、被忽视的，最重要的是，这是一种消极技能——它是关于你故意忽略的和你积极寻找的一样多。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Francis Crick，他发现了双螺旋结构DNA，曾被问及获得诺贝尔奖需要什么条件。他回答说：“哦，这很简单。我的秘诀是我知道该忽略什么。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作者约翰·巴里 (John Barry) 写道：&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;据报道，爱因斯坦曾经说过，他自己的主要科学才能是他能够观察一个物体大量的实验和期刊文章，选择极少数既正确又重要的，忽略其余部分，并在正确的基础上建立理论。&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;我最好的阅读策略遇到的是&lt;a href=&quot;https://collabfund.com/blog/how-to-read-lots-of-inputs-and-a-strong-filter/&quot;>;宽漏斗和严密过滤器&lt; /a>;。愿意阅读任何看起来有点有趣的东西，但如果它不适合你，请毫不留情地迅速放弃它。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;选择进入阁楼的内容。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我发现的其他一些事情有助于选择要关注的内容：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;在阅读文章、书籍或报告时，问：“一年后我还会关心这个吗？ ”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;五年？十岁？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大多数时候您会发现自己不会在意一周内阅读的内容。这是新闻——也许它很有趣，但它有一个有效期。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有两种类型的知识：过期的和永久的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;过期的知识是季度收入、选举民意调查、市场信息和政治。它引起了比应有的更多关注，原因有二。第一，有很多，渴望抓住我们短暂的注意力。第二，我们追逐它，急于在它失去相关性之前挤出洞察力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;永久性知识往往是帮助您理解过期信息的原则和框架。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我读过每天的报纸和书籍。我不记得我在报纸上读到的一件事，比如 2011 年。但我可以告诉你一些很棒的细节 &lt;a href=&quot;https://collabfund.com/blog/23-books-that-c​​hanged- my-life/&quot;>;我在 2011 年读过的书&lt;/a>;以及它们如何改变了我的思维方式。我会永远记住他们。我会继续看报纸。但是，如果我读更多的书，我可能会开发出更好的过滤器和框架，以帮助我更好地理解新闻。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;询问您将在多长时间内关心您阅读的信息会促使您专注于永恒的事物，很少关心暂时的事物——一种长期思考的好心态。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;记住故事，突出事实，跳过废话&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有一个我喜欢的台词：人们不记得书本；他们记得句子。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;更具体地说，他们记得故事。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;即使在您读过的最好的书中，您还记得什么？几句话，几个故事。这些句子和故事可能会改变您的生活，但它们是您从一本书中学到的全部内容。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我在阅读时努力记住这一点。对于几乎每一篇博文和大多数非小说类书籍：没有必要对每一个字都精打细算。如果我能记住一些伟大的故事和史诗般的台词，那就是一个胜利。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;太多的读者陷入了细节，他们无论如何都不会记住，而他们本可以写出一些令人难忘的台词离开一本书并转到下一本书。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;当您钦佩的人不同意您热衷的话题时，请密切注意。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;查尔斯·达尔文按照查理·芒格的说法，他并不是特别聪明，但却成为了一流的科学家，因为他一生都在努力证明自己是错误的。 “从达尔文那里学到的最重要的事情之一就是极端客观性的价值，”芒格曾经说过。 “他一得到想法就试图否定他的想法。他很快在笔记本上记下了任何与一个备受喜爱的想法不符的东西。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是一个了不起的技巧，对于大多数人来说，否定自己信仰的方法是关注那些不同意你的人.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但这很难，因为很容易假设那些不同意你的人不如你聪明或见多识广。很多好想法都被忽略了，或者被故意拒绝了，因为它们出自你不敬佩的人之手。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果你没有幸运地拥有完美的同理心，那么敞开心扉接受你的观点的诀窍就是不同意就是找到那些在你尊重的话题上有观点的人——勾选你脑海中的方框，上面写着“这个人并不疯狂”——然后听取他们关于你不同意的话题的看法。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当这两件事是一致的——你钦佩的人在一些基本问题上不同意你——密切注意。这很有可能是您希望存储在脑海中的信息。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 31 May 2023 16:28:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/paying-attention/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/paying-attention/</guid></item><item><title>期望债务</title><description>&lt;p>;我住在西雅图，亚马逊是我们的巨头。我三分之一的邻居都在公司工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当亚马逊在 2021 年登上世界之巅时——名声在外，股价在飙升——你能感受到自豪和繁荣。你几乎可以闻到它的味道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我曾经听说 90% 的文化只是“获胜”——当一家公司获胜时，每个人都会快乐、富有、得到晋升，他们认为他们的工作有助于&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那是 2021 年的亚马逊。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然后 Jeff Bezos 离开了，股价下跌了 50%，10,000 名员工被解雇，还有数十万人担心他们“ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;那&lt;/em>;现在是我家附近飘荡的气味。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;它是如此清晰，如此明显，情绪是如何转变的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; p>; &lt;p>;那么问题来了：您如何称呼亚马逊在 2021 年的世界顶级地位？是礼物吗？努力工作的奖励？资本主义的自然波动？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;是的，所有这些。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但还有另一种方式来看待它：预期债务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;预期如此之高在 2021 年，投资者和员工必须取得非凡的成就才能实现收支平衡。当结果仅仅是好的时候，他们会感觉很糟糕。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;期望就像一笔债务，必须先偿还，然后才能从所做的事情中获得任何快乐。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;困难的是每个公司和每个员工都希望拥有亚马逊在 2021 年拥有的东西——胜利、财富、声望和声誉。但是，在偿还了预期的债务之后，看看现在的结果。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这值得吗？很难说。&lt;/p>; &lt;hr />; &lt;p>;日经指数——相当于日本股市的道琼斯指数——最近收于 1990 年以来的最高水平。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有两种观察方式在那：作为胜利，或者作为现代表现最差的股票市场之一的例子。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但这是日本股票市场最有趣的地方。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;回报过去 33 年的表现非常糟糕。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但 1965 年至 1990 年的回报&lt;em>;非凡&lt;/em>;。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;日经指数和标准普尔 500 指数的表现非常相似过去 57 年的回报。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/Screenshot%202023-05-25%20at%208.02.46%20AM.png&quot; alt=&quot;屏幕截图 2023-05-25 at 8.02.46 AM.png&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但日经指数在 25 年的大幅飙升中获得了所有这些回报，而标准普尔 500 指数则相对更为平稳.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/Screenshot%202023-05-25%20at%2010.21.50%20AM.png&quot; alt=&quot;屏幕截图 2023-05-25 at 10.21.50 AM.png&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我认为说日本股市在过去 33 年里停滞不前是不公平的。真正发生的事情是，在 20 世纪后期，50 年的回报被塞进了 25 年的时期，而过去 30 年的苦难只是在偿还多余的部分。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;再次强调，高期望值1990 年就像一笔债务，在投资者受益之前必须先偿还。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;没有人得到这笔债务的声明；它没有出现在任何人的资产负债表上；没有人知道利率是多少。但正是真正的债务让投资者陷入困境，摧毁了财富，并花了三分之一个世纪的时间才还清。&lt;/p>; &lt;hr />; &lt;p>;你不配拥有的资产很快就会变成负债。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;也许你的投资组合在泡沫中飙升，你的公司估值过高，或者你协商的薪水超出了你的能力。当时感觉很棒。但现实最终会赶上来，要求偿还与你的错觉相同的比例——加上利息。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些债务很容易被忽视，因为它们通常以自我怀疑和士气低落的形式偿还。但它们是非常真实的，当你了解它们的力量时，你就会变得小心翼翼。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;公司应该想要他们应得的估值，而不是多一分钱。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;工人应该想要一份与他们的技能相匹配的薪水，仅此而已。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;家庭应该想要一种他们可以维持的生活方式，而不是更高的东西。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些都不是关于安定下来或放弃的。这是关于避免当现实赶上来时到期的某种心理债务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有一句坚忍的谚语：“不幸最沉重地压在那些只期待好运的人身上。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;只期待好的感觉就像是一种很好的心态——你很乐观，很快乐，而且很成功。但无论您是否知道，您很可能会积累一笔最终必须偿还的隐藏债务。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 25 May 2023 11:41:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/expectations-debt/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/expectations-debt/</guid></item><item><title> “火星适合戒烟者”——萨拉·莱特曼 (Sara Ledterman)</title><description> &lt;p>;与哈佛大学维斯研究所联手，为地球创造更好的材料。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该联盟的目标是发明并商业化下一个伟大的、改变世界的材料——一种同样便宜、用途广泛且高性能的材料-性能作为最后一个改变世界的发现，塑料，但没有负面影响。通过利用合成生物学，我们计划推动可持续发展的选择，其功效和商业成功甚至超过 Goretex。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;开发对我们的星球和消费者都更好的新材料提供了巨大的经济和生态机会.然而，尽管潜力巨大，但令人惊讶的是，材料在过去几十年里几乎没有变化。塑料、金属、木材、玻璃和合成纤维几乎构成了我们消费的所有东西。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;原因是什么？化石燃料。所有这些材料都依赖于碳氢化合物进行生产和加工，这使它们对环境造成危害，但也更容易获得、成本更低且难以替代。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;虽然该领域仍处于新兴阶段，但有一个几家著名的公司一直处于使用合成生物学将可持续材料商业化的最前沿：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ginkgo Bioworks&lt;/strong>;：Ginkgo Bioworks 设计和制造各种产品，包括香精、香料和&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Solugen&lt;/strong>;：Solugen 从植物来源生产可持续化学品，例如过氧化氢和溶剂。该公司的技术平台使用酶和可再生原料来创造比传统石油基产品更具可持续性和成本效益的产品。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zymergen&lt;/strong>;：Zymergen（被 Ginkgo 收购）设计和制造比传统材料更具可持续性和高性能的新型材料，例如粘合剂、涂料和薄膜。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些公司预示着我们预计会出现的机会类型下一个十年及以后。合成生物学是一个迅速兴起的领域，它结合生物学、工程学和计算机科学来设计和构建新的生物系统。通过利用生物体的力量，合成生物学有可能彻底改变我们生产材料、食物和能源的方式。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这就是我们与 &lt;a href=&quot;https:/ /wyss.harvard.edu/&quot;>;哈佛大学威斯生物启发工程研究所&lt;/a>;。 Wyss Institute 成立于 2009 年，是一家世界级的研发中心，专注于模拟自然的突破性技术。我们很高兴共同宣布启动&lt;strong>;可持续材料研究与创新实验室&lt;/strong>;，以创造新的知识产权 (IP) 并将新型可持续材料推向市场。我们将共同努力探索开发复制天然物质特性的仿生材料，以及从可再生资源中提取的生物基材料。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些材料有望减少我们对化石燃料的依赖，减少温室气体排放，并尽量减少生产过程中的浪费。此外，这些创新有可能创造全新的市场并颠覆现有市场，为投资者提供有吸引力的财务回报。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wyss.harvard.edu/&quot;>;Wyss Institute&lt;/a>; 是这样一个雄心勃勃的新实验室的完美家园。哈佛大学威斯研究所是仿生工程领域的世界领先者。通过模仿自然的设计原则，该研究所为各种行业开发创新解决方案，包括医疗保健、能源和制造业。凭借其多学科方法和最先进的设施，Wyss Institute 具有独特的优势，可以为合作伙伴关系贡献其合成生物学专业知识。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;消费品 (CPG) 和重工业部门都是全球温室气体排放和资源枯竭的主要贡献者。通过投资可持续材料并将其商业化，我们与 Wyss Institute 的合作旨在推动这些行业的范式转变。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们迫不及待地想向您介绍这一开创性技术将产生的所有令人兴奋的技术联盟。我们相信 Collab 和 Wyss Institute 将共同推动新的材料创新浪潮，同时建立一个令人兴奋的新模式，通过联合学术界和风险资本加速从科学发现到市场实现的旅程。该联盟旨在利用合成生物学投资和开发尖端的可持续材料，最终目标是在消费品和重工业中产生可观的财务回报并产生深远的积极环境影响。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果您是在生物材料领域追求创新理念的有远见的研究人员、科学家或企业家，请与我们联系。我们很乐意听取您的意见，并探索合作实现可持续未来的机会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;– Sophie 和 Craig&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（PS 我们对太空及其潜力感到兴奋，但正在致力于我们在解决地球问题上的时间和精力）&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 23 May 2023 08:19:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/mars-is-for-quitters/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/mars-is-for-quitters/</guid></item><item><title>财务依赖和独立的范围</title><description>&lt;p>;&lt;em>;“我不打算致富。我只是想独立。” – Munger&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;把你自己、你的企业和你认识的其他人列在这个清单上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第 0 级：在经济上完全依赖陌生人的好意谁对您的成功没有既得利益&lt;/strong>;。无法工作时乞讨，或者公司依赖于从不关心你是否失败的首次投资者那里筹集资金。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第 1 级：&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;在财务上完全依赖那些希望你成功的人，因为他们喜欢你，而且他们的声誉与你的成功息息相关。&lt;/strong>;15 岁以下的儿童——由父母抚养，通常太小不能工作——属于这一类。由不打算收回资金的朋友和家人支持的公司也是如此。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第 2 级：完全财务依赖对您的财务结果有既得利益的人&lt;/strong>;。没有盈利但前景广阔的企业，由投资者支持，他们可以从投资中获得有意义的回报，因此可能会继续支持您。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第 3 级：能够通过以下方式部分养活自己&lt;/strong >; &lt;strong>;在一定程度上依赖外部支持的同时为他人增加价值&lt;/strong>;。工作但依靠父母来支持他们认为基本的生活必需品的年轻人。或者，如果公司改变成本结构，实际上可以盈利，但继续从投资者那里筹集资金以支持增长。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第 4 级：能够通过为他人增加价值来完全支持自己，但边际价值和易于替代的价值&lt;/strong>;。这是个人和企业的共同类别。它磨碎而脆弱。这听起来像是独立，但老板或客户仍然掌控着你的一天，并可以主宰你的未来。您的未来取决于他们的决定。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第 5 级：&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;足够的储蓄来解决一般问题&lt;/strong>;。您可以忍受每个人或公司都应该定期经历的麻烦，而不会被淘汰。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第 6 级：足够的储蓄来解决无法预见的大问题&lt;/strong>;。你仍然依赖你的老板或你的客户逐月赚钱，但如果危机来袭，你可能会在一段合理的时间内没事。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第 7 级：退休储蓄，教育储蓄，避免消费和汽车债务&lt;/strong>;。你仍然依赖老板和客户，但你可以预见到有一天你当前的储蓄将为你和你的家人开启一个新的独立水平。对于大多数人来说，这是最现实的目标。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第 8 级：&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;选择工作或特定客户的能力，可以避免最恶劣的废话和生活中不必要的麻烦。&lt;/strong>;你仍然依赖老板和客户，但可以自由地说，“不，不是你。我会找到其他人，”当你太沮丧时。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第 9 级：&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;对你的社会地位变得足够自在，你觉得没有必要用昂贵的消费品炫耀你的孔雀羽毛，其唯一价值在于信号&lt;/strong>;。无法做到这一点是一种隐藏的债务和依赖形式，它会堆积在那些错误地认为自己足够富有，可以独立的人身上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第 10 级：能够对银行说不，因为您不需要银行的债务，包括抵押贷款。&lt;/strong>;债务可能是廉价资本，但它会让您对他人感激不尽，为您的未来决策和现金流需求做出贡献。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;11 级&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;很少有现实情况会导致您、您的公司或您的家人被降到 5 级以下。&lt;/strong>;您可以养活自己一年或更长时间关闭您的流动储蓄。这是独立的第一个真正阶段。现在，您几乎可以对任何人说“不”，而且很可能会从后果中恢复过来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第 12 级：利息和股息支付了您一半以上的生活费用&lt;/strong>;。这种独立性大部分归功于苗条的生活方式，而不是巨大的资产。您意识到对生活方式的渴望比几乎任何资产的复合速度都快。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第 13 级：您的资产及其合理的回报预期将覆盖基本生活费用，其寿命超过您的预期寿命&lt;/strong>;。恭喜。你不再依赖老板或客户。如果你愿意，你可以和他们打交道，你可能会的。但前提是你愿意，在你愿意的时候，和你想要的人在一起。感觉很好。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第 14 级：&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;您的资产足以支付基本生活费用以上的资产及其合理的回报预期&lt;/strong>;。您可以根据需要定义“above-basic”。因人而异。记住 Chris Rock 所说的话：“如果比尔盖茨醒来时拿着奥普拉的钱，他会跳出窗外。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第 15 级：&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;独立让你做和说随心所欲，不关心其他人是否反对你&lt;/strong>;，因为你不依赖他们可能提供的支持或机会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第 16 级：&lt;/strong>;有意义的慈善事业这是您的资产增长速度不会超过支出速度的唯一合理方式。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对我来说，这是金融领域最重要的主题之一。每个人都不一样。但是，虽然几乎每个人都能适应自己的东西，但通过独立来控制自己的时间在拥有时总是感觉很棒，而在没有时总是令人痛苦的负担。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 16 May 2023 03:49:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/the-spectrum-of-financial-dependence-and-independence/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/the-spectrum-of-financial-dependence-and-independence/</guid></item><item><title>恶性陷阱</title><description>&lt;p>;在自然界中，有时二加二等于十 - 当两个小东西组合成一个大东西时。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;来自北方的一点冷空气没什么大不了的。一阵暖暖的南风吹来，令人心情愉悦。但是，当它们在密苏里州上空混合在一起时，就会发生龙卷风。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;两个平静的水流不是问题。但如果逆流相遇，就会形成致命的漩涡。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;漂白剂和氨水是常见的家用产品。将它们混合在一起，就会得到致命的氯胺气体。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在每种情况下，都很容易低估风险——或者至少对发生的事情感到惊讶——因为最初的成分似乎是无害的。两个无辜的小东西可以结合形成一个大危险的东西的想法是不直观的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同样的事情也发生在人格特质上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;多年前有人告诉我泡沫会发生当信心（一个好的特质）、乐观（一个好的特质）、信任（通常是好的）混合形成贪婪和妄想时。泡沫之所以如此普遍，是因为输入大多是无辜的，即使输出是疯狂和破坏。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;很多事情都是这样的。当两个令人钦佩的特征以错误的方式混合并产生危险时，就会出现一些最恶毒的陷阱。它们是最难识别和修复的缺陷。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;要有耐心和信心。他们都听起来很棒。但它们混在一起往往会形成固执，这是一场灾难&lt;/strong>;。相信自己是对的可以让您忽略错误的迹象，而耐心可以让您无限期地延长这种否认。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;查理芒格曾经说过：&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p >;未能处理心理否认是人们破产的常见方式。你对某事做出了巨大的承诺。你已经投入了精力和金钱。你投入的越多，整个一致性原则就越让你认为，“现在它必须起作用了。如果我再投入一点，那么一切都会奏效。”人们就那样破产了，因为他们不能停下来，重新思考，然后说，“我有能力注销这个，然后活着再次战斗。我不必以一种会让我崩溃的方式来追求这件事。”&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;一般来说：恐慌的人知道他们在恐慌。不诚实的人知道他们不诚实。但那些陷入耐心-自信陷阱的人却一无所知，因为这两种特质本身看起来都很积极。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;或者好奇心和勇气。它们本身就很棒，但结合起来很容易产生冲动&lt;/strong>;。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果没有好奇心和大胆——新想法加上付诸行动的能力，几乎不可能在商业上取得成功。想想当你不好奇和大胆时会发生什么：要么迟钝和大胆——我什至不知道那是什么样子——要么好奇和胆小，这可能是……学术？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但没有某种刹车、好奇心和大胆很容易变成冲动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;部分原因是意识到 &lt;a href=&quot;https://collabfund.com/blog/natural-maniacs/&quot;>;非常成功人士的第一条规则&lt;/a>;：那些以您欣赏的独特方式思考的人可能也以您不欣赏的独特方式思考。很多因为思考“&lt;em>;我想知道如果我们尝试不同的东西会发生什么&lt;/em>;”而受到钦佩的人是同一个人因为做了不同的东西而被鄙视但行不通，或者赔钱， &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Elon Musk 的 Twitter 就是一个例子（到目前为止）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;扩展到他们没有经验的领域的巨大而成功的公司是另一个例子（AIG，通用电气... >; &lt;p>;如果不是因为他的兄弟罗伊能够将狂野的野心驯服为可行的商业冒险，您永远不会听说过沃尔特·迪斯尼这个名字。 Walt 非常专注于制作优秀的动画，如果让他自己动手，他会把每个项目都推到突破点。在 Roy 加入并踩刹车之前，他早期的企业已经破产。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;正如您可能想象的那样，Walt 经常将 Roy 的平衡视为他雄心壮志的锚定。这就是为什么好奇心和大胆如此危险 - 它们感觉像是正确的特质，即使它们是您成功的最大风险。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;谦逊和野心如何？优秀的特质，但它们一起可以成功地创造出伪装的傲慢。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当你谦虚（“我很幸运，没有其他人的帮助，我不可能做到这一点”）但雄心勃勃（ “我很有才华，而且可以取得比现在更多的成就”），这种心理冲突常常以隐藏的傲慢来解决（“我很特别，但我不能大声说出来”）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;虚伪的谦虚可能比外显的自我更危险，因为它隐藏了——甚至在你自己的头脑中——你的意图和动机。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;正确的平衡是知道你擅长什么，而不是害怕说出来，同时保持公正&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但这种情况很少见——尤其是在社交媒体时代——到处都是表现谦逊的人，通常是两种天真的特质结合在一起的结果，这使得它如此很难承认。这是一个恶性陷阱。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 04 May 2023 16:04:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/vicious-traps/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/vicious-traps/</guid></item><item><title>想赢就举手</title><description>&lt;p>;我们很高兴开始寻找两名新的团队成员加入我们，作为我们为期两年的 Associate 计划的一部分。在 Collab Fund，我们在评估新投资机会时问自己的第一个问题是：如果这家初创公司取得巨大成功，它会让世界变得更美好或更有趣吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot; https://collabfund.com/uploads/CFAssociateProgram2023-06e71b.png&quot; alt=&quot;CFAssociateProgram2023-06e71b.png&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们专注于投资那些推动世界前进的企业，同时也旨在在未来十年及以后超越市场并产生阿尔法回报。为此，我们问自己第二个但也是至关重要的问题：如果“恶棍”的动机是纯粹的自身利益，他们会投资这家公司吗？我们称之为&lt;a href=&quot;https://collabfund.com/blog/the-villain-test/&quot;>;反派测试&lt;/a>;。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们相信最大的回报（财务和社交）在风险投资中通常来自逆向思维，以不同的方式看待事物的最佳途径是让自己置身于不同和独特的视角。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们理想的职位候选人包括：&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>;有创业精神&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;吃苦耐劳&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;乐观&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;求知欲强&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;自创&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;乐于生活在纽约&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;p>;Associates 将与我们的合作伙伴和整个 Collab 团队密切合作，寻找和评估新投资，以及支持现有的投资组合公司。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在除了提供您期望的所有东西（全面且有竞争力的薪酬和福利待遇，包括奖金、带薪假期、病假、健康和牙科保险、团队异地和 401k），我们还提供在不断推动的公司工作的机会现状。我们创造了一种文化，在这种文化中，我们每天醒来都会感到受到鼓舞和激励，全心全意地做出贡献，这不是因为我们必须这样做，而是因为我们想要这样做。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这里有一些您可能（或可能不）关心的其他杂项关于：&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>;我们的风险基金成立于 2010 年，投资于早期（种子前）到早期成长阶段（B 和 C 系列）的公司&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;我们的主要重点是投资在早期阶段（种子+）&lt;/li>; &lt;li>;我们还筹集了各种主题基金，具体任务集中在以下领域：(i) &lt;a href=&quot;https://collabfund.com/blog/collaborative-fund -and-sesame-workshop-launch-collabsesame/&quot;>;kids&lt;/a>;, (ii) &lt;a href=&quot;https://collabfund.com/blog/consumer-startups-are-a-great-investment-heres -why/&quot;>;consumer&lt;/a>; 和 (iii) 最近，&lt;a href=&quot;https://collabfund.com/blog/collab-sos-a-new-fund-and-a-call-to- action/&quot;>;sustainability&lt;/a>;&lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;p>;如何申请？第一步是在 5 月 31 日之前填写&lt;a href=&quot;https://forms.gle/eaE8mjQ4cdYt6XZV9&quot;>;此表格&lt;/a>;，如果您被选中参加面试，我们将在 6 月 15 日之前通知您。我们预计该流程将在 8 月底完成，新员工可于 9 月在纽约开始工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果它不是您的最佳人选，但您知道理想的人选，请直接发送电子邮件至 andrew [at] collabfund.com。如果我们最终雇用了您推荐的人，我们将向您选择的慈善机构捐赠 1000 美元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果您觉得这很有趣，我们很乐意联系！&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;—Andrew蒙哥马利&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 01 May 2023 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/associate-program/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/associate-program/</guid></item><item><title>宣布我们对 pH7 技术的投资</title><description>&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;pH7 技术：开拓可持续金属提取&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如《巴黎协定》所述，为了到 2050 年实现净零排放目标，我们需要承担the Herculean task of decarbonizing entire economies. This challenge means reimagining virtually every industry on a global scale.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Critical to this transformation is electrification, which relies heavily on a steady supply of precious metals and industrial minerals. Unfortunately, mining has long been one of the least sustainable activities on Earth, often involving environmentally harmful processes such as acid leaching, excessive heat usage, the creation of hazardous working conditions, huge water waste and contamination and other notable &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.mit.edu/12.000/www/m2016/finalwebsite/problems/mining.html&quot;>;environmental risks&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While some of these processes might be inescapable, a new wave of innovative technologies aims to make mining more sustainable. Companies like KoBold Metals, which focuses on efficient prospecting of mining sites, and Redwood Materials, which specializes in battery recycling, exemplify the rise of “green metals” startups that are rising to meet the challenge head-on.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One pioneering company at the forefront of clean and sustainable critical metals extraction is pH7 Technologies. Their proprietary closed-loop process enables a minimal environmental impact in extracting key minerals essential for supporting the global electrification movement. We&#39;ve been inspired by their vision and progress, and were thrilled to recently participate in their Series A alongside lead investors TDK Ventures and Pangaea Ventures, as well as BASF, Rhapsody, and others.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While primary metals production often faces longer start-up times, we believe that innovative recycling methods can expedite market entry and boost supply by efficiently extracting metals already in circulation. The issue is both pressing and immediate. The supply and demand balance for many essential metals inputs is turning sharply negative, as showcased by the Heraeus chart below, which highlights the striking imbalance between the supply and demand for Palladium (bottom right cell) due to the gradual increase in supply while demand surges relentlessly.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/platinum-supply-demand-table_image_w1300.png&quot; alt=&quot;platinum-supply-demand-table_image_w1300.png&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;(Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.heraeus.com/en/hpm/market_reports/precious_metals_demand/pgm_demand_supply.html&quot;>;link&lt;/a>;)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;pH7 Technologies addresses challenges traditional smelters face by recycling metals from e-waste. CEO Mohommad Doost and team have spent years perfecting an alchemy-like approach to extracting metals at low temperatures using renewable solvents. Their scalable, commercially viable technology works with ores, concentrates, and other low-grade resources and substrates to quickly bridge our widening supply-demand imbalance. Throughout his career, Mohammad has worked tirelessly to develop environmentally sustainable approaches to metals extraction while minimizing carbon and ecological footprints.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Mohammad and the team he&#39;s assembled, we found a group of humble, driven entrepreneurs eager to rapidly scale sustainable solutions for the mining and metals industries. We were particularly impressed by his ability to efficiently scale-up with limited capital, and we&#39;re confident that pH7 will quickly meet the market demand for platinum group metals, e-waste and other critical minerals in the coming years.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As we continue to push for a more sustainable future, it is vital to support and celebrate cleantech companies like pH7 that are dedicated to making material improvements to overlooked areas. Their innovative solutions pave the way for a more sustainable and environmentally responsible approach to mining, fostering the growth of the cleantech movement and ultimately helping us inch closer to our net-zero emissions goal. We&#39;re excited to back entrepreneurs like Mohammad via our &lt;a href=&quot;sos.fund&quot;>;SOS Fund&lt;/a>;. If you&#39;re interested in learning more or discussing similar opportunities please feel free to reach out to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:mai@collabfund.com&quot;>;mai@collabfund.com&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 28 Apr 2023 10:05:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/announcing-our-investment-in-ph7-technologies/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/announcing-our-investment-in-ph7-technologies/</guid></item><item><title> Some Things I Think</title><description> &lt;p>;The fastest way to get rich is to go slow.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many beliefs are held because there is a social and tribal benefit to holding them, not necessarily because they&#39;re true.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nothing is more blinding than success caused by luck, because when you succeed without effort it&#39;s easy to think, “I must be naturally talented.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Social media makes more sense when you view it as a place people go to perform rather than a place to communicate.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Comedy is the best way to teach about human behavior. George Carlin, Chris Rock, and Jerry Seinfeld have done more to enlighten others than 99.9% of psychology PhDs.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The best measure of wealth is what you have minus what you want. (By this measure, some billionaires are broke.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most valuable personal finance asset is not needing to impress anyone.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most financial debates are people with different time horizons talking over each other.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From school, I remember: Every good story I was told, but none of the formulas I memorized before a test.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It&#39;s easiest to convince people that you&#39;re special if they don&#39;t know you well enough to see all the ways you&#39;re not.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“People like you more when you are working towards something, not when you have it.” - Drake&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A lot of people seem to have a necessary level of stress, and when their life is going well they make up imaginary problems to fill the void.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Few things are as persuasive as your own BS, while nothing is easier to identify than other people&#39;s BS.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Everything is sales.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every employee is replaceable.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Those we admire most in sports, business, politics, and entertainment tend to share one quality: They knew when it was time to quit, time to pass the baton, time to disappear, in a way that preserved, even enhanced, their reputation. Nothing diminishes past success like overstaying your welcome.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The hardest thing when studying history is that you know how the story ends, which makes it impossible to put yourself in people&#39;s shoes and imagine what they were thinking or feeling in the past.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You can only ignore the critics if you also discount the praise.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Related: Few traits are as destructive as an appetite for praise.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are two types of people: Those who want to know more and those who want to defend what they already know.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My jealousy of dogs: They can sit for hours doing absolutely nothing, appearing perfectly content.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A lot of people like making money more than they enjoy having money. The change, not the accumulated amount, is the thrill.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Matt Damon says, “You retard socially and emotionally the moment you become famous. Your experience of the world is never the same.” The same may be true – and far more common – for those who become wealthy.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most beliefs are self-validating. Angry people look for problems and find them everywhere, happy people seek out smiles and find them everywhere, pessimists look for trouble and find it everywhere. Brains are good at filtering inputs to focus on what you want to believe.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Few traits are as attractive as humility, but few are as common as vanity.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Everyone wants to be lucky and to be admired, but no one admires a person for their luck.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The market is rational but investors play different games and those games look irrational to people playing a different game.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A big problem with bubbles is the reflexive association between wealth and wisdom, so a bunch of crazy ideas are taken seriously because a temporarily rich person said it.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Logic doesn&#39;t persuade people. Clarity, storytelling, and appealing to self-interest do.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You only know someone well if you can correctly predict how they will react in stressful situations.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a big difference between an expert, whose talent should be celebrated, and a guru, whose bad ideas should never be questioned.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Past performance increases confidence more than ability.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Happiness is the gap between expectations and reality, so the irony is that nothing is more pessimistic than someone full of optimism. They are bound to be disappointed.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In social fields, very few things are true all the time. “Too many theories try too hard to be laws,” says Carl von Clausewitz.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most important decision most people will ever make is whether, when, and whom to marry. But that topic is never taught in school. It can&#39;t be – everyone&#39;s different, and you can&#39;t reduce it to a formula or a statistic.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I&#39;ve often wondered how many personal bankruptcies and financial troubles were caused by spending that brought no joy to begin with. It&#39;s a double loss: not only are you in trouble, but you didn&#39;t even have fun getting there.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nothing leads to success like unshakable faith in one big idea, and nothing sets the seeds of your downfall like an unshakable faith to one big idea.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are two types of successful people: those with imposter syndrome, and sociopaths.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The bust is only dangerous if you depend on the boom.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Reality will pay you back in equal proportion to your delusion.” - Will Smith&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every five to seven years people forget that recessions occur every five to seven years.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many people check their portfolios every day but their blood pressure every few years, if even that.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The pessimists can be wrong if just a few big things go right.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most important communication skill is knowing when to shut up.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It&#39;s good to have people in your life who you don&#39;t want to disappoint.” - Buffett&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not caring about temporary things, and obsessing over permanent things, is underrated.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lots of things are factually true but contextually nonsense.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Economies run in cycles but people forecast in straight lines.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You are twice as gullible as you think you are – four times if you disagree with that statement.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Price is what you pay, value is whatever you want Excel to say.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bad luck is easy to identify when you fail, but good luck is easy to ignore when you succeed&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Men resist randomness, markets resist prophecy.” - Maggie Mahar&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;People tend to be obsessed with harm posed by others (terrorism, crime) while oblivious to much greater self-inflicted harms (poor diet, no exercise).&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We underestimate the importance of control. Camping is fun, even when you&#39;re cold. Being homeless is miserable, even when you&#39;re warm.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So much of what people call “conviction” is actually a willful disregard for facts that might change their minds.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In school they tell you your paper must be a minimum of five pages long. In the real world you have five seconds to catch someone&#39;s attention before they&#39;re bored and move on.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Learn enough from history to respect one another&#39;s delusions.” - Will + Ariel Durant&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is an “ideal” net worth for everyone, when money not only stops bringing pleasure but becomes a social liability.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“If you only wished to be happy, this could be easily accomplished; but we wish to be happier than other people, and this is always difficult, for we believe others to be happier than they are.” - Montesquieu&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the right incentives, people can be led to believe and defend almost anything.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Good marketing wins in the short run and good products win in the long run.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Judge talent at its best and character at its worst.” - Lord Acton&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Net worth goes from $0 to $1 million: Ecstasy. Net worth goes from $10 million to $1 million: Despondency. Can we agree that all wealth is relative?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Three legal investment strategies: Be smarter than others, be luckier than others, be more patient than others. That&#39;s the whole list.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most productive hour of your day often looks the laziest. Good ideas rarely come during meetings – they come while going for a walk, or sitting on the couch, or taking a shower.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nothing destroys relationships – in love and careers – like being needy.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Schools are good at measuring intelligence but not great at measuring passion, endurance, and character, which tend to be more important than intelligence in the long run.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The majority of what you know comes from the experiences you&#39;ve had and the people you&#39;ve met, both of which are largely out of your control.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Average performance sustained for an above-average period of time leads to extraordinary performance. This is true not just in investing but careers, relationships, and parenting.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I recently came across something called the rule of thirds: One-third of days you should feel amazing. One-third of days should feel OK. One-third of days should be crappy. That&#39;s a good, balanced, realistic life.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The same traits needed for huge success are the same traits that increase the odds of failure. We should be careful praising winners or criticizing failures, because they often made similar decisions with different degrees of luck.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every generation is disappointed in their kids, partly because things typically get better over time, and you become resentful as you see younger generations bypassing problems you had to overcome.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Vaccines can be amazing at one point in time but lose effectiveness as the virus they were targeting adapts and evolves into something new. The same is true for business and investing strategies: What works wonders in one era might flop the next as the world evolves.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A good test when reading the news is to constantly ask, “Will I still care about this story in a year? Two years? Five years?”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A good bet in economics: the past wasn&#39;t as good as you remember, the present isn&#39;t as bad as you think, and the future will be better than you anticipate.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 26 Apr 2023 13:35:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/thoughts/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/thoughts/</guid></item><item><title> One Big Web: A Few Ways the World Works</title><description> &lt;p>;Joseph Tussman, a UC Berkeley philosophy professor, wrote in the 1960s that, “What the pupil must learn, if he learns anything, is that the world will do most of the work for you, provided you cooperate with it by identifying how it really works and aligning with those realities.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What could be more obvious than that? Figure out how the world works and align with those realities.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And here&#39;s an obvious trick: The best way to learn how the world works is to realize how connected everything is. The big lessons from one field can often teach you something critical about other fields.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We&#39;re usually taught as if math is math and chemistry is chemistry, with each field siloed off in its own department, focused on its own truths.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But learning of that sort is only useful in academia. The real world has no silos. The big learning comes when you connect the dots from one field to the next. And once you do so, you realize those connections are infinite. It&#39;s all just one big web. A big web of how the world works.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Let me give you one example. It&#39;s a story about kittens.&lt;/p>; &lt;hr />; &lt;p>;Two MIT cognitive scientists interested in how cats learn to walk once showed something I&#39;ve always found fascinating: The difference between firsthand experience and secondhand learning.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The scientists raised kittens in total darkness. Once the cats were old enough to walk, they were placed in a lighted box for three hours a day.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the box was a kind of carousel, with each kitten placed in a harness.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One of the cat&#39;s legs reached the floor, and its walking movements made the carousel move in a circle.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The other cat&#39;s legs were restrained by the harness. It could see everything going on – the movement, the other cat walking around in circles – but its legs never touched the floor. It had no active control over the carousel.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/Screenshot%202023-04-19%20at%201.03.37%20PM-d1455d.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot 2023-04-19 at 1.03.37 PM-d1455d.png&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After eight weeks of daily carousel walks the cats were brought into the real world to test what they had learned.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They were tested to see if they would automatically place their paws on a surface they were about to be set down on. And if they&#39;d avoid a steep ledge, walking around to a gradual ramp instead. And whether they&#39;d blink when an object was quickly brought close to their face.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The results were extraordinary.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;100% of the cats whose legs had control over the carousel&#39;s movements tested normal.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The cats who only watched, but never controlled, the carousel were functionally blind.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They fell off ledges. They didn&#39;t put their paws out to land on a surface. They didn&#39;t blink when an object accelerated toward their face.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It wasn&#39;t that they couldn&#39;t operate their bodies – they learned to do that in the dark room they were raised in.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But they couldn&#39;t associate visual objects with what their bodies were supposed to do.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The two cats grew up seeing the same thing. But one experienced the real world while the other merely saw it. The result was that one mastered a topic; the other was effectively blind.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And don&#39;t a lot of things work like that – with humans too, not just cats?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nothing is more persuasive than what you&#39;ve experienced firsthand. You can read about what it was like to have certain experiences – living through the Great Depression, fighting in World War II, or growing up in poverty. You can try to be open-minded and empathetic to those experiences.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But what about the people who actually &lt;em>;experienced&lt;/em>; those things firsthand? They understand details that those who merely read about their experiences don&#39;t, and never will. They will have opinions, skills, and emotions that outsiders can&#39;t comprehend.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It&#39;s just like the cats.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And it helps explain why people disagree about everything from politics to religion to investing to education.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The question, “Why don&#39;t you agree with me?” can have infinite answers.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But usually a better question is, “What have you experienced that I haven&#39;t that makes you believe what you do? And would I think about the world like you do if I experienced what you have?”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That is such a broader question than asking, “How do cats learn to walk?” But I&#39;ve never encountered a more potent example of the difference between experience and secondhand learning than the kitten study.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It might sound crazy, but once you understand the basic principles of your profession, you might gain more expertise by reading around your field than within your field. Connecting dots between fields helps you uncover the most powerful forces that guide how the world works, which can be so much more important than a little new detail that&#39;s specific to your profession.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And I&#39;m telling you: The more you look, the more you start to see these connections everywhere. They are endless. John Muir once said, “When we try to pick out anything by itself we find it hitched to everything else in the universe.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Here are a few more examples from one field that teach something much broader.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Founder Effect (&lt;a href=&quot;https://evolution.berkeley.edu/bottlenecks-and-founder-effects/&quot;>;genetics&lt;/a>;)&lt;/strong>;: Genetic variability collapses when a small group becomes separated from the larger population, often leading to a proliferation of harmful traits and the inability to adapt. Variance equals strength in evolution, because the more diverse a population is the more chances it has to come up with new traits that can be selected for. The same thing applies to countries, industries, and businesses: bad ideas tend to stick around in the absence of variety.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Allelopathy (ecology)&lt;/strong>;: Some plants produce chemicals that kill other plants around them, eliminating competition for resources. When trying to make sense of why humans can be ruthless and greedy, it helps to watch a brainless, thoughtless, emotionless plant ruthlessly destroy everything around it. &lt;em>;Nature&lt;/em>; is ruthless and greedy.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zipf&#39;s Law (linguistics)&lt;/strong>;: There is a heavy power law distribution in the words people use, with the most common word (“the”) being used twice as often as the second-most-common word (“of”), which is used twice as often as the third-most-common word, (“and”), etc. There are something like 180,000 English words, but fewer than 200 make up half of the words people speak and write. So even in a massively diversified set, a tiny handful of things make up the majority of occurrences. It&#39;s the same in business and investing – &lt;a href=&quot;https://collabfund.com/blog/tails-you-win/&quot;>;tails drive everything&lt;/a>;, and it&#39;s easy to underestimate how important just a few companies, a few investing periods, and a few products are to your long-term success.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Dollo&#39;s Law (evolution)&lt;/strong>;: An organism can never re-evolve to a former state because the path that led to its former state was wildly complicated and the odds of retracing that exact path round to zero. Say an animal has horns, and then it evolves to lose its horns. The odds that it will ever evolve to regain its horns are nil, because the path that originally gave it horns was so complex.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lots of things work like that. Take brands, relationships, and reputation. There are things that, once lost, will likely never be regained, because the chain of events that created them in the first place can&#39;t be replicated. If you realized how valuable those things are you&#39;d be more careful about risking their loss.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Immunity&lt;/strong>;: Derek Thompson of &lt;em>;The Atlantic&lt;/em>; once told me: Money is more like a vaccine than a performance-enhancing drug. It can prevent a lot of misery, but it won&#39;t necessarily make you happier.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Latent diseases (medicine)&lt;/strong>;: Some diseases and viral infections can remain hidden and dormant in your body for years or decades before causing problems. Tuberculosis can lurk inside of you for years before announcing its attack – same for heart disease and some cancers. It&#39;s the same in relationships, corporate performance, and social trends – it&#39;s hard to gauge how healthy something really is, because even critical problems can fester slowly and undetected over time before abruptly wreacking havoc.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Punctuated equilibrium (evolutionary biology)&lt;/strong>;: Many species go through long periods with little change, and brief periods of rapid change and adaptation. Punctuating events like climate change, natural disasters, and breaking off from a broader group can force more change than gradual evolution. It&#39;s the same for social trends: “History doesn&#39;t crawl; it leaps” says Nassim Taleb. Three events – 9/11, the financial crisis, and Covid – sparked more upheaval and economic change than most of what&#39;s happened in the last two decades combined.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Maximum scale (ecology, physics)&lt;/strong>;: Author Liz Marvin writes about giant sequoia trees:&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;This amazing tree can grow as tall as a skyscraper, but it still knows when to stop and take stock. Trees use a clever process of evaporation to pump water up to the canopies, where photosynthesis takes place. But the laws of physics dictate that this only works up to about 390 feet. The tallest tree on earth is a giant sequoia called Hyperion that stands at 379 feet. See?&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;This applies to businesses, products, marketing campaigns, and personal networks: There is a maximum scale – a natural ceiling – and if you try to push past it the system falls apart.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Arndt–Schulz rule (pharmacology)&lt;/strong>;: It states: “For every substance, small doses stimulate, moderate doses inhibit, large doses kill.” It&#39;s a loose rule, not a law, but it applies to so many things: Debt, ambition, networking, exercise, caution, and analysis. A lot of problems come from doing the right thing in the wrong dosage.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Autocatalysis (chemistry)&lt;/strong>;: A chemical reaction whose output produces the energy and material necessary to spark an identical reaction, so once a process gets started it tends to keep going for a while without any outside force. It&#39;s a pure example of compounding in nature, where growth produces the raw material needed for future growth. The same thing can happen in business and careers, where winners keep winning as success in one period produces the attention, capital, and confidence needed to keep succeeding.&lt;br />; &lt;br />; &lt;strong>;Critical period (linguistics)&lt;/strong>;: There is a period from early childhood into adolescence when people can master new languages without difficulty and without a foreign accent – after puberty, it becomes much more difficult. There is a window when the language-learning part of your brain is malleable and open to new information; afterwards, it tends to lock into place. I think it&#39;s similar for so many life experiences: Your views on politics, economics, religion, and relationships are heavily influenced by what you learned and experienced between childhood and your mid-20s. It&#39;s not impossible to re-learn in your later adult years; just much harder.&lt;br />; &lt;br />; &lt;strong>;Gause&#39;s principle (evolution)&lt;/strong>;: Two species that coexist and compete for limited resources cannot continue at constant populations – one will eventually push the other into extinction or weakness. It&#39;s the same in business: Without some sort of differentiating edge, companies that directly compete against one another often resemble a death match. I like Naval&#39;s point on this topic: “Escape competition through authenticity … Basically, when you&#39;re competing with people, it&#39;s because you&#39;re copying them. It&#39;s because you&#39;re trying to do the same thing. But every human is different. Don&#39;t copy.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Look around and you&#39;ll find hundreds of these ideas, linking one field to another. It&#39;s more fun than confining yourself to your own field, and it gets you closer to the truth.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When you align with them, it&#39;s just like Tussman said: the world will do most of the work for you.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 19 Apr 2023 16:03:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/one-big-web-a-few-ways-the-world-works/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/one-big-web-a-few-ways-the-world-works/</guid></item><item><title> What Makes You Happy</title><description> &lt;p>;Ernest Shackleton&#39;s ship, the &lt;em>;Endurance&lt;/em>;, became stuck in Antarctic ice. Before long it was crushed, ruined.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shackleton and his 27-man crew then spent 19 months – from January 1915 to August 1916 – rowing 800 miles to safety in tiny lifeboats, with nighttime temperatures hitting 10 degrees below zero.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They were constantly frozen, soaked, hungry, and sleep-deprived.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They survived – and all of them &lt;em>;did&lt;/em>; survive – on an occasionally captured seal and foraged seaweed.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It&#39;s one of the most astounding survival stories you&#39;ll ever hear.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But, for me, the most emotional part &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Endurance-Shackletons-Incredible-Alfred-Lansing/dp/0465062881&quot;>;of the book &lt;/a>;&lt;em>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Endurance-Shackletons-Incredible-Alfred-Lansing/dp/0465062881&quot;>;Endurance&lt;/a>;&lt;/em>; came at the end, when Shackleton&#39;s crew finally made it to a whaling station on South Georgia island, 1,600 miles east of Argentina.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Author Alfred Lansing writes:&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;Every comfort the whaling station could provide was placed at the disposal of Shackleton [and crew]. They first enjoyed the glorious luxury of a long bath, followed by a shave. Then new clothes were given to them from the station&#39;s storehouse.&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;They were then served a hot meal, and slept for 12 hours.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;Can you imagine?&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Can you imagine how good it must have felt to have a bath, a hot meal, and a warm bed after being constantly frozen and starving for 19 months?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even if the water was lukewarm and the food was half stale, that must have been one of the most pleasant and fulfilling evenings anyone has ever experienced.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A weird thing in life is that everyone strives for a good life because they think it will make them happy. But what actually brings happiness is the contrast between what you have now and whatever you were just doing.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The best drink you will ever taste is a glass of tap water when you&#39;re thirsty.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The best food you will ever eat is fast food when you&#39;re starving.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The best massage you will ever feel is sitting on a couch after a long run.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The best sleep you will ever experience is when your newborn finally sleeps through the night.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his book on the final days of World War II, Stephen Ambrose writes about a wounded American soldier who&#39;s carried back to the medic tent. He knows he&#39;s going home – his war is over. “Clean sheets boys!” he yells back to his fellow soldiers who are left behind. “Clean sheets, can you believe it! Clean sheets!” Living in foxholes made soldiers daydream about normal life, and few things chased their imaginations like the dignity of clean sheets. Not money or status or respect or glory. Just the absolute joy of clean sheets.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Money is a lot like this, too. The richest you&#39;ll probably ever feel is when you get your first paycheck, and your bank account goes from $5 to, perhaps, $500. The contrast that generates might be greater than going from $10 million to $20 million. Going from nothing to something is so much more powerful than going from a lot to super a lot.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The contrast, not the amount, is what makes you happy.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two things stick out here.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Happiness is a fleeting emotion&lt;/strong>;, because it&#39;s triggered by a contrast in circumstances, but you quickly adapt to whatever new circumstances you&#39;re in. Shackleton&#39;s second hot meal, second bath, and second night&#39;s sleep probably felt 1% as amazing.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But that shouldn&#39;t be depressing. Instead of chasing happiness, which is fleeting, people should be after contentment, which is similar but more enduring.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;When you realize how powerful expectations are&lt;/strong>;, you put as much effort into keeping them low as you do into improving your circumstances. Happiness, contentment, joy … all of those things come from experiencing a gap between expectations and reality.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shackleton&#39;s men learned this. After their ordeal, they found so much joy in little things they&#39;d never before considered. One sailor wrote in his diary: “One of the finest days we have ever had . . . a pleasure to be alive.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lansing wrote: “In this lonely world of ice and emptiness, they had achieved at least a limited kind of contentment. They had been tested and found not wanting.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That&#39;s about as good as it gets.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 11 Apr 2023 16:43:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/what-makes-you-happy/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/what-makes-you-happy/</guid></item></channel></rss>