<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>合作基金</title><description>Collab Fund 是企业家推动世界前进的主要资金来源。</description><link/> https://collabfund.com<atom:link href="https://collabfund.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><pubDate> Fri, 14 Jul 2023 22:01:25 -0400</pubDate><lastbuilddate> 2023 年 7 月 14 日星期五 22:01:25 -0400</lastbuilddate><generator>站点叶</generator><item><title>聪明人说的聪明事</title><description>&lt;p>;我最近看到的几句话我很喜欢：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“对掌声的渴望是人类最低等的性格特征之一。” – Jan-Willem van der Rijt&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“了解自己的一个好方法就是认真反思别人身上让你恼火的一切。” – 凯文·凯利&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“30 多岁的人知道世界将走向何方，因为他们会这么做。我已经80多岁了，所以我不知道。” – Daniel Kahneman&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我正处于人生阶段，不参与争论。即使你说1+1=5，你也是对的。玩得开心。” – 基努·里维斯&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“如果你在绝望和恐惧之间找到适当的平衡，你就可以让人们做任何事情。” – 特雷弗·诺亚&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“大多数人的幸福不是被巨大的灾难或致命的错误所毁掉的，而是被缓慢破坏性的小事情的重复所毁掉的。” – 欧内斯特·迪姆内特&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“幸福是在需要更多幸福之前获得的感觉” – 唐·德雷珀&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“适当的笑话，讲得恰当，可以更好地启发问题政治、哲学和文学的重要性胜过任何无聊的争论。” ——艾萨克·阿西莫夫&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“继承的财富必然会导致野心的死亡，就像可卡因会导致道德的死亡一样。” – William Vanderbilt&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“不需要太多就能让我们相信自己聪明又健康，但需要大量事实才能让我们相信事实恰恰相反。” – 丹·吉尔伯特&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“不安全感是贪婪之母。” ——威尔·杜兰特&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“无知越大，教条主义就越大。” – 威廉·奥斯勒&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“不要试图修复别人。只是设定界限。” – Shibetoshi Nakamoto（化名）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“通过改进你的想法来获得多巴胺比验证它们更好。 ” – 纳特·弗里德曼&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“生活中有一些你不想让他们失望的人，这很好。” – 沃伦·巴菲特&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“更多信息只是拖延的一种形式。” – Russ Roberts&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“他人对我们造成的伤害往往很严重；自残的后果往往是慢性的。” – 纳西姆·塔勒布&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“关于财富，人们最不了解的一点是，所有对金钱的快乐都会在经济变得不必要的时候结束。一个人可以在不咨询银行家的情况下购买任何他想要的东西，他不会珍惜他所购买的任何东西。” – William Dawson&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“衡量你对某人的爱的最准确的标准是你对他们的缺点的看法。” – 马克·曼森&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“假设你登上了顶峰，请记住：让你变得伟大的东西可能并不适合下一代。” – 理查德·汉明&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“除了自己的感受之外，没有人关心任何事情。” – 威尔·史密斯&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“在每一种满足的土壤中都会萌发不满的种子。” – Dee Hock&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“成千上万的人不喜欢我所做的事情。幸运的是，有数百万人这样做。” – 詹姆斯·帕特森&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“认识到你喜欢某人的什么。欣赏它作为与那个特定的人不同的品质，而不是与他或她混淆。你欣赏他们的品质是与他们所构成的特定（因此有缺陷）的例子分开存在的。” – 达伦·布朗&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“人们可能会拒绝相信某件事，即使它可以帮助他们活得更久一点，如果相信它会让他们生活得更悲伤的话。” – Cass Sunstein&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我坚信，你在生活和工作中的首要目标就是永远让自己变得过时。” – 蒂姆·汉森&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“你的感恩能力与你的权利感成反比。” – 马克·布鲁克斯&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“你的日历比你的银行账户更能衡量成功。” – James Clear&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“如果人们如此渴望幸福，为什么他们不尝试去理解自己的错误信念呢？首先，因为他们从来没有想到将它们视为错误，甚至视为信仰。他们将它们视为事实和现实，它们已经被深深地编程了。” – 安东尼·迪梅洛&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“生活的目的是体验那些你以后会怀念的东西。” – FedSpeak&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“生活中没有什么比你在思考时所认为的更重要。” – 卡尼曼&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“安全之道就是永远不安全。” – 本·富兰克林&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“如果我们不能嘲笑某件事，我们就无法理性地思考它。” – 克莱·约翰逊&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“稳定有两种类型：主动稳定和被动……当人们混淆这两种类型的稳定时，就会遇到麻烦。例如，人际关系需要关注和照顾。如果你认为你们的关系是被动稳定的，有一天你一觉醒来就会收到离婚协议书。” – 肖恩·帕里什&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“写下你的讣告，然后逆向生活。” ——巴菲特&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 05 Jul 2023 15:54:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/smart-things-smart-people-said/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/smart-things-smart-people-said/</guid></item><item><title>几个问题</title><description>&lt;p>;我钦佩谁的生活却暗自悲惨？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我相信什么是真实的，只是因为相信它使我在我的部落中享有良好的声誉？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我目前的哪一个如果我由不同的父母抚养长大，价值观会有所不同吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我最相信但证据最少的东西是什么？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;谁有正确的答案，但我因为他们沟通不好而被忽视？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;谁充满了野心，但我因为他们沟通良好而关注？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我认为什么是野心（一个好的沟通者）？特质），但实际上是嫉妒（可怕的嫉妒）？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我自己有时对别人做的事情让我恼火吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我的怀旧有多少是错误的或不完整的记忆过去？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在你的职业中，无论你变得多么聪明，有什么是不可能知道的？大卫·多伊奇说：“要注意预测和预言之间的区别。预言旨在了解无法得知的事情。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我担心的这件事实际上是一个问题，还是我在寻找需要担心的问题，因为它们让我感觉自己处于掌控之中？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; >; &lt;p>;在我的领域中，我认为什么是法则（始终有效），但实际上只是一条规则（有时有效）？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我认为什么是普遍真理，但实际上只是我自己文化所特有的规范？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;什么是上一代人的真实情况，但现在不再如此，谁还坚持这个古老的事实？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;什么是部分真实的，但是我如此绝对地相信它，并如此认真地对待它，以至于我把它变成了一种危险的信念？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;今天我的生活中是否有一些事情进展顺利，让我回顾起来并希望自己拥有在我领先时退出？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我的生活中是否有一些事情我认为我“充满热情”或“专注”，但实际上我只是沉迷于它？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我是否会花更多的时间来捍卫我已经知道的东西，而不是尝试学习新的东西？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我生活中是否有一些我认为善良且富有同情心的人，但他们实际上只是太害羞而不敢告诉我残酷的事实？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果 Instagram 是对人们生活的诚实反映，而不是精心策划的精彩片段，它会是什么样子？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我是否尽可能友善，而不仅仅是我需要有多好？&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 14:24:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/a-few-questions/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/a-few-questions/</guid></item><item><title>为什么你相信你所做的事情</title><description>&lt;p>;我记得几年前读过一篇文章，讲述也门的一位父亲因饥饿失去了一个儿子，结果又让另一个孩子患上了重病。绝望之下，他向部落长老求助，长老们推荐了一种民间疗法：将一根燃烧的棍子插入病童的胸口以排出疾病。父亲同意了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当被问及这个可怕的过程时，父亲&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2018/10/26/world/middleeast/saudi-arabia- war-yemen.html&quot;>;说：&lt;/a>;“人们说把他烧在体内就没事了。当你没有钱，你儿子病了，你就会相信任何事情。”&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&lt;em>;当你没有钱，而你的儿子病了，你就会相信任何事情。&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是一个非常有力的声明，它的某些版本适用于每个人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是一个普遍的现实：你相信什么是真实的，取决于你希望它是真实的程度。某件事越能帮助你应对不确定性，你相信它是真的的门槛就越低。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;永远都是这样。丹尼尔·笛福 (Daniel Defoe) 在 1722 年描述伦敦大瘟疫时写道：“人们比以往任何时候都更加沉迷于预言、占星术、梦境和老太太的故事。”当瘟疫杀死了四分之一的邻居时，你会相信任何能给你带来希望的东西。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Visa 创始人 Dee Hock 曾经说过：“我们生来就拥有几乎无限的相信事物的能力，因为这些信念对我们持有有利，而不是因为它们与事实有一点关系。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;想想投资者，他们的策略与他们的身份紧密相连，当它不再起作用时，他们就无法放手.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;或者是企业如此迫切地想要做好，却忽视了所有不好的方面。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;查理·芒格 &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamesclear.com/great-查理芒格的演讲/人类误判心理学&quot;>;曾经说过&lt;/a>;：&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;如果你打开电视，你会发现最明显的罪犯的母亲那个人能诊断出来，他们都认为他们的儿子是无辜的。现实太痛苦而难以忍受，所以你只能扭曲它，直到它可以忍受为止。&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;即使是看似硬科学的东西也属于这一类。法律界有一个叫做吉布森定律的东西，它规定：“对于每个博士学位，都有一个平等且相反的博士学位。”无论你想提出什么论点，你都可以找到一位合格的专家证人，他愿意在宣誓后以每小时 500 美元的价格出庭作证。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人们可以被引导去相信并捍卫几乎任何事情，因为信仰的目标往往不是发现真相，而是为了证明过去的行为是合理的，或者保护你的声誉，或者在缺乏希望时提供希望，或者最大化你的收入，或者向其他人表明你属于这个部落。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此，您相信自己所做的事情有一个原因：信念的吸引力可能会掩盖其真实性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;信念往往形成的其他几个原因：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;过去事件的记忆被过滤。你保留有意义的内容，扔掉令人困惑的细节。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;20 世纪 40 年代末，两位心理学家——戈登·奥尔波特 (Gordon Allport) 和利奥·波兹曼 (Leo Postman)——提出了他们所谓的“记忆中的平整和锐化效应”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事情是这样的：在任何重大事件中——车祸、恐怖袭击、经济衰退、流行病等——你经历和观察到的变量实际上可能有数百万个。你看到人们的情绪，听到不同的意见，读到不同的观点。你不可能记住所有的细节；实在是太多了。因此，在你的回忆中，你会强调一些记忆（锐化）并丢弃其他记忆（平整）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人们倾向于锐化那些构成一个好故事并符合他们现有观点的细节，并平整那些令人困惑、痛苦的细节。 ，或与预先存在的信念相矛盾。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此，我们有一个信念生成系统：你认为正确的东西在很大程度上基于你所经历的事情，并且你记得你的经历中的哪些部分使好故事，证实刻板印象，并将其他经历之间的点联系起来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;想想 2008 年金融危机有多么复杂。数十亿人同时做出复杂、情绪化的决定。没有人能够追踪一切。因此，事后看来，人们倾向于相信对他们来说有意义的简单叙述——美联储毁了经济，救助不公平，财富被摧毁。所有这些都可能是真实的并且被一个人相信，但被另一个经历过相同经济但记得不同细节的人反对。也许美联储拯救了经济，救助是最好的选择，也是千载难逢的买入机会。取决于你记得什么。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;危险的是，基于经验的信念似乎是基于证据的。但是，当我们对复杂世界的观察不知所措时，我们会挑选最有吸引力的证据来安抚我们简单、热爱故事的头脑。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;欺骗自己相信要容易得多说谎胜过承认错误。改变想法比应有的情况更罕见，这导致我们坚持错误的信念。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;物理学家 Max Tegmark 在《这会让你变得更聪明》一书中写道：&lt; /p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;科学生活方式的核心是在面对与自己观点不符的信息时改变想法，避免智力惯性，但我们很多人却称赞那些顽固坚持自己观点的领导者“坚强”。 ”伟大的物理学家理查德·费曼将“对专家的不信任”誉为科学的基石，但从众心理和对权威人物的迷信却普遍存在。逻辑构成了科学推理的基础，但一厢情愿的想法、非理性的恐惧和其他认知偏见常常主导决策。&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;你可以同意那里写的每一个字，但仍然很难改变你的想法 –或者认真对待那些这样做的人——原因有两个。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第一，当你改变主意时，你会觉得你为建立以前的信念而付出的所有艰苦努力都被浪费了。即使是现实带来的一点痛苦也足以说服你坚持原来的信念。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第二，当你改变主意，从一种信念转向另一种信念时，可能很难接受新的信念认真对待信仰——改变信仰证明新的信仰可能是短暂的，尤其是在其他人眼中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;两者都认识到一个重要的事实：信仰不仅与我们所知道的有关，而且与我们所知道的有关。它们是社会信号，提供有关我们如何建立信仰、对自己智力的信心以及向他人传递可靠事实的能力的线索。奇怪的是，这些信号可能是违反直觉的：我们应该想要一个愿意改变主意的专家，但我们真正想要的是一个足够自信、永远不必这样做的人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;很多时候，我们“对真相不感兴趣——我们感兴趣的是消除不确定性，而这一事实本身就让我们相信与现实无关的事情。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 21 Jun 2023 13:58:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/why-you- believe-the-things-you-do/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/why-you- believe-the-things-you-do/</guid></item><item><title>对橡子的恐惧</title><description>&lt;p>;我是寓言的忠实粉丝。无论是《蚂蚁和蚱蜢》、《狼来了》还是《龟兔赛跑》，每部作品都很棒，因为它们简洁、有趣，最重要的是，它们永远具有相关性。也就是说，最近几周我的办公桌上出现了一个寓言，我发现它与我们目前生活的世界和市场特别相关——“小鸡”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于那些不熟悉小鸡故事的人小鸡，事情是这样的。&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;小鸡正在树林里散步，突然被一颗从树上掉下来的橡子击中。小鸡确信这是天塌下来的征兆，从树林里冲出来警告国王。&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;在去见国王的路上，她遇到了几个朋友，它们也是鸟类，名字有 Henny Penny、Goosey Loosey、Ducky Lucky、Turkey Lurkey 等。当她沿途遇到每一个人时，小鸡警告他们天要塌下来了，而且她有第一手证据。&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;因此，这些鸟加入了小鸡的行列。当她走向国王时。很快，一大群人相信天要塌下来了。&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;在路上，他们遇到了 Foxy Loxy（当然是一只狐狸），谁问他们为什么这么着急。小鸡解释说天要塌下来了，他们正在去告诉国王的路上。狡猾的洛克西提出带他们去城堡，在那里他们会找到国王，鸟儿们同意陪伴他。然而，狡猾的狐狸没有把他们带到城堡，而是带到了他的巢穴，而这些鸟儿再也没有活着。&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;教训？&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;恐惧不是强加给我们的。相反，它是我们强加给自己的东西。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;怎么会这样？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因为恐惧是我们面对某些事物（通常是威胁）时的反应。&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;这提出了一个问题——恐惧是一个问题吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;简而言之，不是。恐惧本身并不一定是坏事。事实上，适度的恐惧实际上是一件&lt;em>;好事&lt;/em>;，因为它让我们更加了解周围的环境，并在必要时保持谨慎。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是，不合理的恐惧程度是一个问题，因为它使我们容易受到世界上“Foxy Loxy”的影响。那些旨在利用恐惧来谋取个人利益的人。那些出售会加剧恐惧的建议、产品和服务的人。那些想要它的人动不动就把它放大。媒体是明显的罪魁祸首，但还有无数其他罪魁祸首。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/Screenshot%202023-06-28%20at%2011.52.19%20AM .png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot 2023-06-28 at 11.52.19 AM.png&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是一个如此重要的问题，因为虽然 Chicken Little 将单个橡子视为一个标志，天塌下来了，今天的大多数人，尤其是投资者，似乎都将每一个“橡子”（即负面头条新闻）视为经济和/或市场必然崩溃的明确信号。&lt;/p>; &lt;想想过去十年吧。从 Covid-19 到虚假信息、加密货币和 FTX 欺诈、伊朗、中国、俄罗斯、气候变化、科技泡沫 2.0、供应链短缺、全球化、硅谷银行倒闭、办公室空缺和更高的利率（仅举几个例子）很少）都被视为对金融和/或地缘政治稳定的危险威胁。然而，失业率仍接近历史低点，股市也接近历史高点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此，这就引出了一个问题 - 如果我们今天仰望天空，下一个橡子是什么？落下？接下来要担心的事情是什么？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;很明显——人工智能（“AI”）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;仅上周末，我读到的各种论文中就有两打以上的文章强调人工智能的风险，它将如何瓦解美国劳动力，导致贫富差距进一步扩大，破坏经济稳定，甚至导致核浩劫。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;哇哦。谈论小鸡。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是我们应该害怕这个橡子吗？这最终可能是天塌下来的&lt;em>;真实&lt;/em>;迹象吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;历史告诉我们，答案显然是否定的。也就是说，人工智能可能会对经济部门和市场产生截然不同的影响。了解如何是不惧怕它到来的第一步。这里只是一些最重要的例子。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;教育&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;记住你在中学时必须写的关于罗马帝国的历史报告？或者高中经典作文？还是关于第二次世界大战的大学毕业论文？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;虽然这些是测试我们复述信息能力的好方法，但在测试我们对信息的理解程度方面却完全失败了。他们没有教我们如何在不同学科、不同时期或不同环境之间进行比较。换句话说，它们并没有让我们思考。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;好消息是，人工智能有潜力使未来的学生能够远远超越这些反胃练习。人工智能不仅可以简单地报道罗马帝国、苏格拉底和柏拉图，或者第二次世界大战，还可以为这些学生提供机会，将每个人的经验教训应用到他们自己的生活和周围的世界中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As对于更广泛的教育来说，这个消息可能更加光明，因为《经济学人》最近报道人工智能正在做“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/united-states/2023/06/15/how- chatgpt-could-help-teachers-and-lower-the-cost-of-college&quot;>;帮助教师编写不同阅读水平甚至不同语言的课程计划和工作表。&lt;/a>;”换句话说，它使用相同数量的“人力”实现更专业的教学。如果是这样，这难道不是提高生产力的定义吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;正如计算器取代了手动运行数学方程的需要一样，人工智能有潜力执行学生已经习惯做的大部分无意识的反省。 ，使他们能够自由地进行真正的思考和创造力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;医疗保健&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前，诊断和治疗身体疾病完全取决于概率和试验。错误方法。有胃痛吗？第一步通常是改变饮食。会不会有更严重的事情？当然可以，但医生总是先从最高概率开始，这是理所当然的。如果症状消退，则一切准备就绪。如果他们不这样做，你的医生可能会转向下一个最高的可能性。也许他们会开抗生素或其他处方药。还是没有好一点？接下来将是 CT 扫描或 MRI，但这可能需要几个月的时间。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那么人工智能会如何改变这种情况呢？展望未来，医生可以访问您的个人基因组成，将您的症状与家族史进行交叉对照，并与其他经历过类似症状和具有相似家族史/遗传学的患者进行检查。这会改变概率图吗？疗程怎么样？响应时间怎么样？我猜它会，而且很可能会在很大程度上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这只是冰山一角，因为人工智能也可能会彻底改变无数其他方面，例如治疗方法的研究方式，设计、创建和管理。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;工业&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;任何在工厂、工厂或装配线上生产产品的公司都应该从人工智能中受益匪浅鉴于它应该使他们能够简化运营、节省能源（从而节省成本）、增加吞吐量并提高整体效率。这是一个非常明显的最终结果。您越了解自己的运营，就越能更好地经营业务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;财务&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因为我无法说得比&lt;a href=&quot;更好https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2023-06-01/ai-bots-are-coming-to-finance&quot;>;彭博社的马特·莱文&lt;/a>;，我只是要向您展示他的内容上周写了一篇关于人工智能的文章。不用说，我无法想象一个行业会因为人工智能而经历比金融更多的繁荣和萧条。&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;“相对早期的广泛使用-阶段人工智能将为金融领域带来新的犯错方式。目前，在金融领域有一些经典的犯错方式，它们会定期导致各种后果，从滑稽的尴尬到数百万美元的交易损失，再到系统性金融危机。许多最经典的错误都具有“过于自信地根据有限的历史数据进行概括”的概括，尽管有些错误是按错了按钮。但出错的方法就这么多，而且都是凭直觉判断的。但现在有新方法了！奇怪的方式！哦，当然，人工智能可能会根据有限的历史数据做出过于自信的概括，但也许还有创新的空间。现在，一些银行家将在聊天机器人中输入“我们的客户想要对冲土耳其大选的风险”，聊天机器人会说“她应该出售一些狗狗币看涨期权，并用所得收益购买大量镍期货” ，”而银行家会说“很奇怪，好吧。”交易会以令人惊讶的方式出错，客户会起诉，客户、银行家和聊天机器人都会出庭，法官会问聊天机器人“为什么这个交易要对冲任何东西”，聊天机器人会耸耸肩，就像“兄弟，你为什么问我，我是一个聊天机器人。”或者它会说“实际上，狗狗币/镍价差是事前土耳其政治风险的绝佳代表，因为”，然后发出一系列你我和法官无法理解的“1”、“0”、“表情符号”和高亢噪音。但这对于聊天机器人来说非常有意义。犯错的新方法！在我们都被聊天机器人取代之前，这将使金融专栏作家的生活变得更加精彩。&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;消费者&lt;/strong >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《华尔街日报》本周专门用了一整个版块专门讨论这一主题，标题为“人工智能让麦迪逊大街既兴奋又担忧”，几乎完美地总结了这一领域。简而言之，会有很多优点和缺点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一方面，随着趋势的变化、偏好的调整和人口结构的变化，人工智能或聊天 GPT 应该如何弄清楚下一个时尚是什么，明年春天的服装阵容应该是什么样子，或者在消费者甚至不知道的情况下，哪些目的地会流行？有没有看过十年又十年的服装款式？祝试图解决这个问题的人工智能机器人好运。或者音乐呢？电影？汽车？室内设计？检查、检查、再检查。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;也就是说，消费领域的某些部分将从人工智能中受益匪浅，特别是那些专注于“此时此地”、客户服务和销售的领域，而不是预测未来。一家名为 &lt;a href=&quot;https://cresta.com/&quot;>;Cresta&lt;/a>; 的公司就是最好的选择，该公司利用生成式人工智能更好地为各种工作和行业的人们提供信息、教育和帮助，他们与潜在客户、现有客户和当前同事互动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本文中还有太多其他可能性要提及，就像大多数依赖于人类行为的事情一样，时间会告诉我们结果如何.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;体育&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;多年来，我们已经在体育界看到了 AI 的一个版本，即比利·比恩 (Billy Beane) 的“点球成金”(Moneyball) 的形式，休斯顿火箭队/金球奖州勇士队的“三球策略”，以及所有球队如何侦察球员、观看录像和研究对手。我想下一阶段将会加剧这种现象。但讽刺的是，我不认为人工智能的采用将决定未来的赢家。为什么？因为它不会新颖。每个人都会这样做。相反，它更有可能使整个生态系统更具竞争力，这将使赢得最高级别冠军变得更具挑战性，因为 &lt;a href=&quot;https://fs.blog/the-paradox-of -skill/&quot;>;技能悖论&lt;/a>;。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;地缘政治与战争&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这可能是最棘手、也是最重要的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;几年前，我写过一篇关于一个名叫斯坦尼斯洛夫·彼得罗夫 (Stanislov Petrov) 的文章，标题为“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/we-need- humans-ted-lamade/&quot;>;半人马的未来&lt;/a>;”。虽然你可能没有听说过他，但他可能是 20 世纪最重要的人物。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为什么？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因为他可能像我们一样单枪匹马地拯救了地球和文明。知道它。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;怎么知道的？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1983 年秋天，彼得罗夫负责俄罗斯的奥科核预警系统。 9月23日，系统报告称，美国向苏联发射了5枚核导弹。当时，苏联拥有世界上第二先进的导弹防御技术，因此彼得罗夫得出的威胁真实存在的结论是完全合乎逻辑的。然而，彼得罗夫对此表示怀疑。他的结论是，(a) 美国的打击更有可能是“全面”攻击，而不是仅仅发射五枚导弹，(b) 发射探测系统是新的，可能存在故障，(c)警报过快地通过了 30 层验证，并且 (d) 地面雷达未能获取确凿的证据。尽管存在潜在的个人后果（最好的是他职业生涯的结束，最坏的是他的生命），彼得罗夫还是选择违背他的命令。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;正如您可能已经猜到的，彼得罗夫的直觉被证明是正确的。通过依靠自己的直觉而不是盲目追随新技术，他很可能阻止了冷战的重大升级和无端的核事件。如果俄罗斯仅仅依靠“当今的人工智能”而不进行人类干预，事情的结果可能会非常非常不同。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;那么，这一切意味着什么？&lt;/strong>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;对于如此令人困惑和复杂的事情，答案可能相对简单。对于不太依赖人类行为的行业来说，人工智能可能是一项非常有益的发展。然而，对于那些更加依赖我们和我们的突发奇想的人来说，谨慎可能是有道理的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这就是说，大多数行业不出所料地会落在中间的某个位置，这意味着如果他们找到一种方法，他们的境况会更好充分利用这些新技术，但不要过分依赖这些新技术。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;问题是，这会是什么样子？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在他最畅销的书中，“&lt;a href=&quot;https: //www.amazon.com/Range-Generalists-Triumph-Specialized-World/dp/0735214506/ref=tmm_pap_swatch_0?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1685734534&amp;amp;sr=1-1&quot;>;Range&lt;/a>;”，作者 David爱泼斯坦描述了 1997 年国际象棋大师加里·卡斯帕罗夫 (Gary Casparov) 与 IBM 超级计算机深蓝 (Deep Blue) 之间的一场国际象棋比赛。输给深蓝后，卡斯帕罗夫沉默地回应道，&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“我们能做的任何事情，机器都会做”更好的。如果我们能够将其编码并传递给计算机，他们会做得更好。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，在更深入地研究了这场比赛之后，卡斯帕罗夫开始相信还有其他原因在起作用。简而言之，他转向“&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moravec%27s_paradox#:\~:text=Moravec&#39;s%20paradox%20is%20the%20observation,skills%20require%20enormous% 20computational%20resources.&quot;>;Moravec&#39;s Paradox&lt;/a>;”，它表明，&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“机器和人类具有相反的优点和缺点。因此，最佳场景可能是两者协同工作。”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在国际象棋中，这可以归结为战术与策略。战术是为了立即获得优势而采取的简短动作组合，而战略则指的是赢得比赛所需的全局规划。关键是，虽然机器在战术上完美无缺，但它们制定战略的能力却要差得多，因为战略涉及创造力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;卡斯帕罗夫通过一系列国际象棋场景确定，最佳棋手不是蓝色巨人，也不是更优秀的棋手。强大的机器。 Instead, it came in the form of a human “coaching” multiple computers. The coach would first instruct a computer on what to examine. Then, the coach would synthesize this information in order to form an overall strategy and execute on it. These combo human/computer teams proved to be far superior, earning the nickname “centaurs”.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By taking care of the tactics, computers enabled the humans to do what they do best — strategize.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sounds about right to me.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 21 Jun 2023 02:52:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/fear-of-acorns/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/fear-of-acorns/</guid></item><item><title> The Evolution of Sustainable Materials: Six Trends to Watch</title><description> &lt;p>;Sustainable materials — materials derived from renewable resources instead of fossil fuels — form the foundation of a brighter, healthier future for the planet and all who call it home. They&#39;re also the core focus of our climate fund, &lt;a href=&quot;https://collabfund.com/blog/collab-sos-a-new-fund-and-a-call-to-action/&quot;>;Collab SOS&lt;/a>;, encompassing everything from textiles and bioplastics to green chemicals and construction materials.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the year since we launched this fund, the sector has rapidly evolved to meet the demands of a swiftly changing world. Regulatory tailwinds and buy-in from large corporations have been balanced by higher costs of capital and trepidation among investors. Yet, scientific breakthroughs – including improvements in AI-based modeling and the falling costs of both renewable energy and gene editing – have accelerated progress and unlocked new pathways to scale-up.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Here are some of the top trends we&#39;ve noticed in recent months:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;1. Diversifying Feedstock&lt;/strong>; Companies are forgoing refined feedstocks, such as sugar, and are increasingly diversifying their feedstock choices when producing valuable materials. We are now seeing an uptick in companies using agricultural crop waste, food waste, fabric waste, municipal waste, and CO2 or CH4 gas waste (eg, flue gas from industry combustion or gas from wastewater treatment plants). Not only are these feedstocks often less costly, but these re-engineered workflows can often comparably reduce GHG emissions and land use.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;2. Uniting Biology and Green Chemistry&lt;/strong>; Companies are evolving beyond trying to produce products purely through fermentation. Instead, they harness the molecules that nature provides, optimize production of the best ones using a biological host, then employ chemistry to generate the final target. This approach often reduces the cost of fermentation and downstream processing and exponentially increases the number of possible chemical targets and applications.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;3. Optimizing Downstream Processing Costs&lt;/strong>; In the current environment of steep capital costs, companies are placing a heightened focus on cost optimization. This involves finding abundant and affordable feedstocks and streamlining downstream processes, which are often energy-intensive and yield-limited. By tackling these cost drivers head-on, sustainable material companies can enhance their competitiveness and pave the way for widespread adoption.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;4. Championing Ingredients Over Brands&lt;/strong>; Companies are much more focused on B2B go-to-market strategies, versus creating their own consumer brands. At Collab, we see a lot of value in capturing as much vertical value as possible by building end-to-end processes (or as close as possible). However team skills, especially at the early stage, often align better with creating ingredients versus vertical brands. And this strategy can allow for faster scale-up.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;5. Exploring Tunable Materials&lt;/strong>; Companies no longer offer just one material. Today, they have the ability to adapt materials for specific characteristics. This is often done through the exploration of potential enzyme activities and innovative green chemistry platforms. We have especially seen this in companies producing alternative leather and in those producing fabric treatments such as alternatives to PFAS for water resistance.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;6. Maturing Cell-Free Systems and Applications&lt;/strong>; Cell-free technologies, which allow for biological reactions to occur outside the confines of a living cell, are maturing rapidly. Re-invigorated by reasonably priced, novel and tunable resins that extend the lifetime and stability of enzymes, companies can now apply this technology to producing sustainable materials and chemicals. Once primarily used in pharmaceuticals, these systems now serve broader applications, including the creation of fibers from CO2, recycling hard-to-process plastics, and synthesizing complex chemicals. Cell-free systems permit precise regulation, optimization, and enhanced yields of biosynthetic pathways with the additional capability to create materials with unique, tailored properties.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This sector is undergoing a transformative period, marked by rapid advancements and evolving strategies. The first wave of biomaterials never quite lived up to the hype, but we&#39;re extremely optimistic about the future for this latest group of innovators. The trends outlined above highlight the sector&#39;s determination to innovate and address critical challenges. As investors and advocates for a more sustainable future, we must continue to monitor these trends and collaborate with companies leading the charge in innovation.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 08:23:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/sustainable-materials-six-trends/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/sustainable-materials-six-trends/</guid></item><item><title> Reask: Predicting Extreme Weather In Uncertain Times</title><description> &lt;p>;Extreme weather events are more frequent and severe than ever before.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Climate-driven weather events caused $115B in insured financial losses globally in 2022 — an astonishing 42% higher than the prior 10-year average.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The uncertainty caused by a surge of climate perils — hurricanes, cyclones, flooding, wildfire, and drought — presents a significant problem: if insurers, corporations, and governments can&#39;t forecast damaging climate-related threats, they can&#39;t make sound decisions to protect their assets.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a major problem – and opportunity – for the financial services industry and insurance markets, and the clients they serve.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/unnamed-011cd1.png&quot; alt=&quot;unnamed-011cd1.png&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Existing solutions for climate risk prediction exist, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rms.com/&quot;>;Moody&#39; RMS&lt;/a>;, but most are reliant on historical data. These models extrapolate from “historical loss rates” — the total value of losses over a given period divided by the total amount of exposure during the same period — to attempt to predict the future. But climate change is altering the frequency and intensity of weather events in ways that make historical extrapolation insufficient.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The models that predict future climate change are based on a range of assumptions and uncertainties, and it is difficult to accurately capture all of the complex interactions between the atmosphere, oceans, and land surface.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That&#39;s where &lt;a href=&quot;https://reask.earth/&quot;>;Reask&lt;/a>; comes in.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Led by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/thomasloridan/&quot;>;Thomas Loridan &lt;/a>;and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/jamie-rodney-2b4a2782/&quot;>;Jamie Rodney&lt;/a>;, along with a team of pioneering mathematicians, meteorologists and computer scientists, Reask steers clear of historical loss rate extrapolation in favor of bottoms-up physical weather modeling — the use of mathematical models to predict the weather based on current conditions and physical laws. These models take various atmospheric parameters such as temperature, humidity, wind speed and direction, atmospheric pressure, and others as inputs and apply the principles of physics to simulate the evolution of the weather over time.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reask&#39;s secret sauce is a set of proprietary weather models leveraging AI simulations that assigns risk factors down to the square kilometer.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This approach has several benefits:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Precision&lt;/strong>;: Reask directly calculates highly accurate variables such as wind speed, and captures the full distribution of risk, moving beyond simplistic risk scores and instead allows clients to arrive at a price.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Clarity&lt;/strong>;: Reask always uses physical variables to assess risk. Any output created can be directly related back to known physics of atmospheric systems rather than pure statistics.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Global&lt;/strong>;: The Reask model is inherently global, capturing the physics of the climate, and allows clients a means to assess how climate risk can be diversified and managed within a portfolio of financial assets for the first time ever.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reask&#39;s APIs can be leveraged to empower traditional insurance and re-insurance companies such as Swiss Re, as well as a new era of climate-focused insurers such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://ourkettle.com/&quot;>;Kettle&lt;/a>;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.arbol.io/&quot;>;Arbol&lt;/a>; to underwrite risk more effectively. The data can also be used by firms like &lt;a href=&quot;https://descartesunderwriting.com/&quot;>;Descartes &lt;/a>;to develop parametric insurance products that allow speedy relief to those impacted by damaging weather events.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moreover, the specificity of the models and the global nature of Reask&#39;s predictive capabilities enable a broader set of financial institutions and large asset holders to understand the risk their entire portfolio faces so that they can protect themselves, their employees, and the broader economy against impending catastrophes.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As we approach hurricane season in the United States, we&#39;re excited to see Reask&#39;s solution made available, and we&#39;re thrilled to support Reask, as we co-lead their Seed round with our friends at Mastry Ventures.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You can follow the company&#39;s progress &lt;a href=&quot;https://reask.earth/news/&quot;>;here&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And, if you&#39;re working on ways to combat climate change, we&#39;d like to hear from you!&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 15 Jun 2023 09:15:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/reask-predicting-extreme-weather-in-uncertain-times/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/reask-predicting-extreme-weather-in-uncertain-times/</guid></item><item><title> Compounding Optimism</title><description> &lt;p>;Let me share a little theory I have about optimism, and why progress is so easy to underestimate.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I&#39;ll explain it in four parts.&lt;/p>; &lt;hr />; &lt;p>;A crocodile in Costa Rica &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbsnews.com/news/crocodile-virgin-birth-costa-rica/&quot;>;was found pregnan&lt;/a>;t recently – and she did it all herself, with no help from a male. Her fetus is 99.99% genetically identical to her.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It&#39;s the first documented case of a crocodile reproducing asexually. A few other animals – some birds and snakes – can do it as well, but it&#39;s extremely rare.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There&#39;s a good reason why.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Almost 100 years ago, an evolutionary biologist named Herman Muller came up with a theory that eventually became known as Muller&#39;s Ratchet. It says dangerous mutations tend to pile up when there&#39;s no genetic recombination, which can ultimately lead a species to extinction. In the absence of variety – a male and female mixing genes – dangerous mutations tend to stick around, because there are no new, better, variations to compete the bad stuff out of the gene pool.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It&#39;s why so few species reproduce asexually.&lt;/p>; &lt;hr />; &lt;p>;David Senra of the wonderful &lt;em>;Founders&lt;/em>; podcast &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PI6QcwnfNe8&amp;amp;ab_channel=Acquired&quot;>;recently&lt;/a>; told a story about Steve Jobs:&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;Steve was in his 20s and he goes and meets [Polaroid founder] Edwin Land. And Steve says, “Visiting Edwin Land was like visiting a shrine … he is my hero.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And Jeff Bezos took a lot of ideas from Sam Walton. Both Steve and Jeff took a lot of ideas from Sony.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You always find these people where you&#39;re like, “Oh, I thought this was a Steve Jobs idea.” No, no. It&#39;s an [Sony founder] Akio Morita idea, or an Edwin Land idea.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Watch the presentations that Steve Jobs gives where he says, “We&#39;re building at the intersection of technology and liberal arts.” Edwin Land said those exact words!&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You&#39;re never going to find anybody who gets to the top of the profession without studying the people that came before them and learning from them and admiring them.&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;This is so true.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thomas Edison took a lot of ideas from Michael Faraday.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bill Gates took ideas from a computer inventor named Henry Edwards Roberts.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Warren Buffett learned from Ben Graham and Phil Fisher.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Edwin Land himself was massively influenced by a Harvard physics professor named George Wheelwright, who &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2001/03/03/business/gw-wheelwright-iii-97-dies-co-founder-of-polaroid.html&quot;>;became a Polaroid co-founder&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The question is: Did George Wheelwright know that he would influence Edwin Land, who would then influence Steve Jobs, who would then design a phone that 2.5 billion people would use?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Did Michael Faraday, who died in 1867, know that his ideas would directly influence the light bulb, which effectively led to the creation of everything from the modern power grid to nightlife?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Did Ben Graham know that his 1950s finance class would lead to 45,000 trekking to Omaha every year to hear his student speak?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course not. It&#39;s so hard to know what an idea, or an invention, or a philosophy, will influence, and what a person who&#39;s influenced by it will go on to create.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Visa Founder Dee Hock says, “A book is far more than what the author wrote; it is everything you can imagine and read into it as well.” An author might write something that&#39;s dull or obvious, but it could inspire a reader to go do something incredible.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ideas compound.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Inventions compound.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Education compounds.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A trivial thing can grow into a massive thing, and faster than most people realize.&lt;/p>; &lt;hr />; &lt;p>;Science writer Matt Ridley says most innovation happens when several different ideas “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ted.com/talks/matt_ridley_when_ideas_have_sex&quot;>;have sex&lt;/a>;.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most new ideas and inventions are pretty bland on their own. But when you mix several of them together, you can get magic. Plastic is great. Electronics are neat. Metal is special. But mix them together in the right way and you get an iPhone, which is pure magic.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It&#39;s ideas combining, joining, and merging, that create the modern world.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And it&#39;s the opposite process of what our crocodile friend recently pulled off.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ridley explains in his book &lt;em>;The Rational Optimist&lt;/em>; about the benefits of recombination:&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;A mutation that occurs in one creature can join forces with a mutation that occurs in another. If microbes had not begun swapping genes a few billion years ago, and animals had not continued doing so through sex, all the genes that make eyes could never have got together in one animal; nor the genes to make legs or nerves or brains. Each mutation would have remained isolated in its own lineage, unable to discover the joys of synergy.&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;Ridley once explained this further:&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;I&#39;m not interested in the debate about whether some groups have higher IQs than other groups. It&#39;s completely irrelevant. What&#39;s relevant to a society is how well people are communicating their ideas, and how well they&#39;re cooperating, not how clever the individuals are.&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;Small ideas mixing and compounding into big ones – that&#39;s what really drives the world.&lt;/p>; &lt;hr />; &lt;p>;I think part of the reason pessimism is so much easier and more common than optimism is that compound growth is not intuitive.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It&#39;s hard to imagine, say, our incomes doubling over the next few generations. That seems like such a massive leap, like we&#39;d have to boil the ocean to get it done. But doubling the average income over 30 years works out to about 2.3% growth per year. It&#39;s not crazy at all. It&#39;s actually quite achievable. What made it seem so ambitious to begin with is that compound growth is easy to underestimate.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you look at the end result of a long period of compounding, it&#39;s astounding. But all it took to get it done was little bits of incremental growth strung together for a long time.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;All progress is like that.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Technological progress is easy to underestimate because it&#39;s so counterintuitive to see how, for example, the philosophies of a guy who invented Polaroid film would go on to inspire the iPhone. Or how an 18th-century physicist would write a notebook that would set the foundations for a modern electrical system.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you view progress as being driven by the genius of individuals, of course it&#39;s hard to imagine a future where things are dramatically better, because no individual is orders of magnitudes smarter than average.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But when you view it as one person coming up with a small idea, another person copying that idea and tweaking it a little, another taking that insight and manipulating it a bit, another yet taking that product and combining it with something else – incremental, tiny bits, little ideas mixing, joining, blending, mutating, and compounding together – it&#39;s suddenly much more conceivable.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 13 Jun 2023 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/compounding-optimism/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/compounding-optimism/</guid></item><item><title> Brazil at Silicon Valley</title><description> &lt;p>;This has been a very difficult year for global tech companies and entrepreneurial ecosystems. However, Brazil at Silicon Valley managed to shed light on the opportunity for innovation in Brazil and the commitment of those building and investing in the country. Latin America continues to emerge as a vibrant landscape of innovation, and Brazil is quickly establishing itself as the epicenter.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Simon Rodriguez &lt;a href=&quot;https://technopoly.substack.com/p/is-brazil-losing-its-lead&quot;>;outlined this sentiment&lt;/a>; as “Ask anyone and Brazil is X years ahead of Spanish-speaking LatAm, where X depends on the nationality of the responder”.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbvaspark.com/contenido/en/news/land-of-unicorns-and-fintech-empire-this-is-sao-paulo-the-largest-innovation-ecosystem-in-latin-america/&quot;>;BBVA reports&lt;/a>;, “São Paulo&#39;s entrepreneurial ecosystem is valued at $108 billion. In comparison, &lt;a href=&quot;https://openinnovation.bbva.com/es/noticias/en-el-zocalo-del-emprendimiento-el-bum-emprendedor-y-fintech-de-ciudad-de-mexico/&quot;>;Mexico&lt;/a>; City&#39;s (the second-largest in Latin America) is valued at $22 billion.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moreover, São Paulo holds the 4th place in the Global Fintech ranking. In a region where “cash is king,” Brazil is leading the charge towards digital payments. Brazil&#39;s Central Bank launched the country&#39;s instant payment system PIX in 2020, which already boasts more than 130m registered users (60% of Brazil&#39;s population).&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To explore Brazil&#39;s technological progress, students from Stanford and Berkeley hold an incredible annual event called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brazilatsiliconvalley.com/&quot;>;Brazil at Silicon Valley&lt;/a>; (BSV).&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the name suggests, the aim is to bridge the gap between Brazil and Silicon Valley. This year, BSV was attended by a diverse crowd of over 600 founders, investors, technologists, and policymakers. My unofficial estimate is that at least 550 attendees undertook the long journey from Brazil — a minimum of two flights spanning at least 15 hours.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Let&#39;s just say that my portuñol came in handy.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the Agtech session: &lt;em>;How innovations in food systems can help solve the climate crisis&lt;/em>;, a BSV staff member used a voice-to-text function to generate the Chat-GPT summary minutes after the session was over. &lt;em>;Naturally&lt;/em>;, the summary was sent around via Whatsapp.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This year&#39;s BSV illuminated several key investment themes:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;● &lt;strong>;Verticalized Software&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;+ Fintech&lt;/strong>;: There are endless opportunities to create and scale local software solutions. Brazil has benefitted from supportive policies and the role of its Central Bank in implementing the digital payment system PIX. Angela Strange, a Partner at a16z, emphasized her view that every company will be a fintech company, as financial services will be a horizontal platform. She cited &lt;a href=&quot;https://fu.do/es/&quot;>;Fudo&lt;/a>;*, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uber.com/&quot;>;Uber&lt;/a>;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lyft.com/&quot;>;Lyft&lt;/a>;*, among others as noteworthy examples. We also think &lt;a href=&quot;https://kanastra.com.br/&quot;>;Kanastra&lt;/a>;* is a great example of an exciting fintech infrastructure play.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;● &lt;strong>;Agtech + Climate:&lt;/strong>; Agribusiness represents almost 30% of Brazil&#39;s GDP, 40% of the country&#39;s exports, and 20% of the labor force. Brazil is well-positioned to lead climate change initiatives, both in terms of technological innovation and adapting existing agricultural practices. Investors are looking for nature-based solutions, hardware and software plays, and sound business models that are not overly reliant on government subsidies (eg pass the &lt;a href=&quot;https://collabfund.com/blog/the-villain-test/&quot;>;Villain Test&lt;/a>;). Companies highlighted included &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.plenty.ag/&quot;>;Plenty&lt;/a>;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bcdbio.com/&quot;>;BCD Bioscience&lt;/a>;*, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.strellabiotech.com/&quot;>;Strella Biotech&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;● &lt;strong>;AI:&lt;/strong>; Two key messages resonated throughout the event: 1) we don&#39;t know what we don&#39;t know, and 2) the transformative potential of AI, which will affect almost every aspect of our lives. Alexandr Wang and Peter Norvig called for a careful rollout of AI technology and thoughtful consideration of its global impact. Optimism and enthusiasm for technology were spread by Vinod Khosla of Khosla Ventures and Julio Vasconcellos of Atlantico. They referenced &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@vkhosla/reinventing-societal-infrastructure-with-technology-f71e0d4f2355&quot;>;Reinventing Societal Infrastructure with Technology&lt;/a>;). Check out how &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mercadodiferente.com.br/&quot;>;Diferente&lt;/a>;* is &lt;a href=&quot;https://exame.com/bussola/diferente-lanca-ia-que-cria-receitas-com-itens-da-cesta-de-organicos/&quot;>;using AI &lt;/a>;for inventory management and recipe recommendations.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;● &lt;strong>;The Fundraising Market&lt;/strong>;: A clear slowdown in the market is being felt across the board, with rounds taking longer to close, valuations compressing, and regional exit liquidity shortages. However, these conditions also make it a great time to build as we&#39;ve seen teams be laser-focused on unit economics, capital efficiency, and nailing down PMF. McKinsey launched the &lt;a href=&quot;https://latamdigitalreport.mckinsey.com/&quot;>;2023 Latin American Digital Report&lt;/a>; during the event.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One thing that was not mentioned during the conference – politics.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a Venezuelan, I found it refreshing to see Brazilians come together and discuss secular trends, opportunities to innovate, and what is going right with the country&#39;s policies. After all, technological development is a rising tide that lifts all boats.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the week following BSV, Rio hosted &lt;a href=&quot;https://rio.websummit.com/&quot;>;Web Summit&lt;/a>; – a tech event that drew more than 20,000 attendees. Numerous key stakeholders have since gathered in NYC for events hosted by Itau, BTG, and Bank of America. I was lucky to attend Itau&#39;s Women Leaders in NY honoring &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ingridsilvaballet.com/&quot;>;Ingrid Silva&lt;/a>;. While an uptick in events doesn&#39;t necessarily equal a surge in innovation, it undeniably illustrates the escalating interest in Brazil as a premier global hub for tech development.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For great content about local and international tech events related to the Brazil entrepreneurial ecosystem, check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://substack.com/profile/38241540-julia-de-luca&quot;>;Julia de Luca&lt;/a>; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://abreu.substack.com/&quot;>;Lucas Abreu&lt;/a>;&#39;s newsletters.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And make plans now to join us at BSV next year, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.latitud.com/en/vamoslatamsummit&quot;>;Vamos Latam Summit&lt;/a>; in São Paulo, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brazilclimatesummit.com/&quot;>;Brazil Climate Summit&lt;/a>; in NYC.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With tons of admiration from a very Venezuelan VC.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Luisa&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;*Denotes Collab Portfolio Company&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 05 Jun 2023 16:46:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/brazil-at-silicon-valley/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/brazil-at-silicon-valley/</guid></item><item><title> Paying Attention</title><description> &lt;p>;Sherlock Holmes says in the book, &lt;em>;The Study of Scarlet&lt;/em>;:&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;I consider that a man&#39;s brain originally is like a little empty attic, and you have to stock it with such furniture as you choose. A fool takes in all the lumber of every sort that he comes across, so that the knowledge which might be useful to him gets crowded out, or at best is jumbled up with a lot of other things so that he has a difficulty in laying his hands.&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;This was written in 1887. Imagine how he&#39;d feel today – phone buzzing in his pocket, social media feeds gushing out useless information.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Deciding what to pay attention to is hard, overlooked, and most important, it&#39;s a negative skill – it&#39;s about what you willfully ignore as much as what you actively seek out.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Francis Crick, who discovered the double helix structure of DNA, was once asked what it takes to win the Nobel Prize. He responded: “Oh it&#39;s very simple. My secret had been I know what to ignore.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Author John Barry writes:&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;Einstein reportedly once said that his own major scientific talent was his ability to look at an enormous number of experiments and journal articles, select the very few that were both correct and important, ignore the rest, and build a theory on the right ones.&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;The best reading strategy I&#39;ve come across is the idea of &lt;a href=&quot;https://collabfund.com/blog/how-to-read-lots-of-inputs-and-a-strong-filter/&quot;>;a wide funnel and tight filter&lt;/a>;. Be willing to read anything that looks even a little interesting, but abandon it quickly and without mercy if it&#39;s not working for you.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Be choosy about what you let into your attic.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A few other things I&#39;ve found helpful in choosing what to pay attention to:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;When reading an article, book, or report, ask, “Will I still care about this in a year?”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Five years? Ten?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most of the time you&#39;ll realize you won&#39;t care about whatever you&#39;re reading in a week. It&#39;s newsy – maybe it&#39;s interesting, but it has an expiration date.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are two types of knowledge: Expiring and permanent.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Expiring knowledge is things like quarterly earnings, election polls, market information, and politics. It catches more attention than it should, for two reasons. One, there&#39;s a lot of it, eager to capture our short attention spans. Two, we chase it down, anxious to squeeze out insight before it loses relevance.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Permanent knowledge tends to be principles and frameworks that help you make sense of expiring information.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I read newspapers and books every day. I can not recall one thing I read in a newspaper from, say, 2011. But I can tell you details about a few great &lt;a href=&quot;https://collabfund.com/blog/23-books-that-changed-my-life/&quot;>;books I read in 2011 &lt;/a>;and how they changed how I think. I&#39;ll remember them forever. I&#39;ll keep reading newspapers. But if I read more books I&#39;d probably develop better filters and frameworks that would help me make better sense of the news.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Asking how long you&#39;ll care about the information you read pushes you to focus on permanent things and care little about temporary things – a great mindset for long-term thinking.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Memorize stories, highlight facts, skip the fluff&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There&#39;s a line I love: People don&#39;t remember books; they remember sentences.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More specifically, they remember stories.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even in the best book you&#39;ve ever read, what do you remember? A couple sentences, a few stories. Those sentences and stories might change your life, but they&#39;re all you&#39;ll take away from a book.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I try to remember that when reading. For nearly every blog post and most non-fiction books: there is no need to devour and focus on every word. If I can remember a few great stories and epic lines, it&#39;s a win.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Too many readers get too bogged down in details they&#39;re never going to remember anyways, when they could have pulled a few memorable lines out of a book and moved onto the next.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Pay close attention when someone you admire disagrees on a topic you&#39;re passionate about.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Charles Darwin, according to Charlie Munger, wasn&#39;t exceptionally bright, but became a first-class scientist because he spent his life trying to prove himself wrong. “One of the great things to learn from Darwin is the value of extreme objectivity,” Munger once said. “He tried to disconfirm his ideas as soon as he got &#39;em. He quickly wrote down in his notebook anything that disconfirmed a much-loved idea.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That is an amazing trick, and for most people the way to disconfirm your own beliefs is paying attention to people who disagree with you.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But that&#39;s hard, because it&#39;s so easy to assume those who disagree with you aren&#39;t as smart or informed as you are. A lot of good ideas are ignored, or intentionally rejected, because they are said by people you don&#39;t admire.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you&#39;re not blessed with perfect empathy, the trick to opening your mind to viewpoints you disagree with is to find people whose views on one topic you respect – that checks the box in your head that says “this person isn&#39;t crazy” – and listen to them about topics you disagree on.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When those two things align – a person you admire disagrees with you about something fundamental – pay close attention. There&#39;s a good chance this is information you&#39;ll want stored in your head.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 31 May 2023 16:28:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/paying-attention/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/paying-attention/</guid></item><item><title> Expectations Debt</title><description> &lt;p>;I live in Seattle, and Amazon is our giant. A third of my neighbors work for the company.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Amazon was on top of the world in 2021 – reputation gleaming, stock price booming – you could feel the pride and prosperity. You could practically smell it.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I once heard that 90% of culture is just “winning,” – when a company is winning, everyone&#39;s happy, rich, being promoted, and they see their work as contributing to something bigger than themselves.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That was Amazon in 2021.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Then Jeff Bezos left, the stock fell 50%, 10,000 employees were laid off, and hundreds of thousands more fear they&#39;re next.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;That&lt;/em>; is now the scent wafting around my neighborhood.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is so clear, so obvious, how the mood has shifted.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So here&#39;s the question: What do you call the top-of-the-world status Amazon had in 2021? Was it a gift? A reward for hard work? The natural swings of capitalism?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yes, all of those.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But there&#39;s another way to look at it: An expectations debt.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Expectations were so high in 2021 that investors and employees had to achieve extraordinary things just to break even. When results were merely good, they felt terrible.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Expectations are like a debt that must be repaid before you get any joy out of what you&#39;re doing.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The hard thing is that every company and every employee wants to have what Amazon had in 2021 – winning, wealth, prestige, reputation. But look at what it led to now, after the expectations debt was repaid.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Was it worth it? Hard to say.&lt;/p>; &lt;hr />; &lt;p>;The Nikkei – the Japanese stock market equivalent of the Dow Jones – recently closed at its highest level since 1990.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are two ways to look at that: As a win, or as an example of one of the worst-performing stock markets of modern times.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But here&#39;s what&#39;s most interesting about the Japanese stock market.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Returns over the last 33 years were terrible.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But returns from 1965 to 1990 were &lt;em>;extraordinary&lt;/em>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Nikkei and the S&amp;amp;P 500 have had very similar returns over the last 57 years.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/Screenshot%202023-05-25%20at%208.02.46%20AM.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot 2023-05-25 at 8.02.46 AM.png&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the Nikkei earned all of those returns during one massive 25-year surge, while the S&amp;amp;P 500 has been comparatively more even.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/Screenshot%202023-05-25%20at%2010.21.50%20AM.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot 2023-05-25 at 10.21.50 AM.png&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I don&#39;t think it&#39;s fair to say the Japanese stock market stagnated over the last 33 years. What really happened is that 50 years of returns were stuffed into a 25-year period in the late 20th century, and the past three decades of misery has just been repaying that excess.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Here again, high expectations in 1990 were like a debt that had to be repaid before investors could benefit.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No one got a statement for that debt; it didn&#39;t show up on anyone&#39;s balance sheet; no one knew what the interest rate would be. But it was very real debt that anchored investors down, destroyed wealth, and took a third of a century to pay down.&lt;/p>; &lt;hr />; &lt;p>;An asset you don&#39;t deserve can quickly become a liability.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Maybe your portfolio surged during a bubble, your company hit a monster valuation, or you negotiated a salary that exceeds your ability. It feels great at the time. But reality eventually catches up, and demands repayment in equal proportion to your delusions – plus interest.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These debts are easy to ignore because they are often repaid in the form of self-doubt and crushed morale. But they are very real, and when you understand their power you become careful what you wish for.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Companies should want the valuation they deserve, and not a penny more.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Workers should want a salary that matches their skill, and nothing more.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Families should want a lifestyle they can sustain, and nothing higher.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;None of those are about settling or giving up. It&#39;s about avoiding a certain kind of psychological debt that comes due when reality catches up.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There&#39;s a stoic saying: “Misfortune weighs most heavily on those who expect nothing but good fortune.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Expecting nothing but good feels like such a good mindset – you&#39;re optimistic, happy, and winning. But whether you know it or not you&#39;re very likely piling up a hidden debt that must eventually be repaid.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 25 May 2023 11:41:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/expectations-debt/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/expectations-debt/</guid></item></channel></rss>