<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>合作基金</title><description>Collab Fund 是企业家推动世界前进的主要资金来源。</description><link/> https://collabfund.com<atom:link href="https://collabfund.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><pubDate> Thu, 03 Aug 2023 15:23:40 -0400</pubDate><lastbuilddate> 2023 年 8 月 3 日，星期四 15:23:40 -0400</lastbuilddate><generator>站点叶</generator><item><title>如何阅读：大量输入和强大的过滤器</title><description>&lt;p>;我的阅读策略是开始阅读尽可能多的书，但读完其中的几本书。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;几年前，我听查理·芒格说过“大多数书我读完第一章就不会读完。我不会被坏书所困扰，”这句话一直困扰着我。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果你坚持读完你开始读的每一本书，那么阅读就是一件苦差事，因为大多数书要么 a) 在简介，b) 不适合你，或 c) 不适合任何人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;费力地读完这些书的最后一页（这可能是在学校早期养成的习惯）可以将阅读变成相当于 10-一个小时的工作会议什么也没做，每个人都很无聊。一旦你从这个角度看待阅读，你拿起另一本书的意愿就会减弱。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这当然是悲剧性的。马克·吐温说：“不读好书的人比不会读好书的人没有优势。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我认识的每个聪明人都是贪婪的读者，他们也说“每个聪明人都喜欢阅读”。我认识的一个人是一位贪婪的读者。”这条规则几乎没有例外，这令人震惊。大学学费为每年 25,000 美元，每堂课大约为 100 美元。好书——有时是同一位教授写的——可以花十五美元购买，并且可以提供数倍的改变生活的见解。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这两者之间的冲突——大多数书不需要阅读直到最后，但有些书可以改变你的生活 - 意味着你需要两件事才能从阅读中获得很多收获：&lt;strong>;大量输入和强大的过滤器&lt;/strong>;。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果你只挑选你确信你会喜欢的书，你会限制自己阅读相同主题的相同作者的书。它为确认偏见提供了新鲜的氧气，并限制了你将不同领域和不同文化之间的点联系起来的能力。最好对你愿意尝试的书设定一个较低的标准，即使是最微弱的兴趣也足以让你成功。 Kindle 样品是免费的，所以借口很少。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一旦你的办公桌上充满了输入，你就必须拿出过滤器。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;它应该是无情的，不留任何俘虏并且毫不留情。与约会类似，一本你在关注了 10 分钟后就不喜欢的书几乎不可能有幸福的结局。猛地关上它并继续前进。如果你读了三页书就退出了，就像你拒绝与刚认识的令你烦恼的人进行 10 小时的约会一样，你也不算失败。海里有很多鱼。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这不仅仅适用于读书。对于所有类型的数据、研究、对话和学习都是如此。如果你的大脑不被大量的输入淹没，你就会陷入你个人经历过的狭小世界中。但是，如果没有强大的过滤器，您会因选择而不知所措，并因无所作为而陷入瘫痪。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;良好的阅读过滤器更多的是艺术而不是科学。您必须找到一个适合您的。更重要的一点是，找到正确信息的最高几率来自于让自己被信息淹没，但很快就能说，“不是这样的。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 03 Aug 2023 07:57:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/how-to-read-lots-of-inputs-and-a-strong-filter/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/how-to-read-lots-of-inputs-and-a-strong-filter/</guid></item><item><title>一切都是周期性的</title><description>&lt;p>;法国地质学家最近发现喜马拉雅山脉在800年前曾遭受过大规模山体滑坡。规模可能是轻描淡写的：滑坡移动的泥土足以掩埋曼哈顿，高度与帝国大厦一样高。安纳普尔纳四号峰曾经是世界五座最高的山峰之一。今天，在滑坡从顶部削去三分之一英里后，它只是很大。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;令人惊奇的是，滑坡并不是由冰川侵蚀山体造成的，而冰川通常是侵蚀山体的原因。山的高度受到检查。安纳普尔纳四号峰太大了。正如任何建造过沙堡的人都知道的那样，总有一天，整个沙堡会自行崩溃，被自身垂直贪婪的重量压垮。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一切都是周期性的，而且是容易的事情忽略周期性的是，它不需要任何外力将其推向另一个方向。变大的行为足以让你变得更小，而无需受到任何人或任何事的推动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当你认为风险是由外力引起的，而实际上风险是由外力造成的时，生活中就会犯很多错误。在没有任何外部帮助的情况下，你自己的成功就足以让你失望。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这适用于很多事情。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在他 1944 年出版的书中&lt;em>;我们为什么不从历史中学习？&lt;/em>;，BH Liddell Hart 写道，为什么每次战争结束后，人们都会说：“那太可怕了，我们再也不会这样做了”，但几年后却发现自己又上了战场：&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;我们从历史中得知，完全的胜利从来不是通过胜利者一直期待的结果——良好而持久的和平来完成的。因为胜利总是播下新战争的种子，因为胜利在战败者中滋生了平反和复仇的渴望，因为胜利催生了新的对手。&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;胜利总是播下新的种子。新战争的种子&lt;/em>;。这是一个很奇怪的概念，但它显然是正确的。罗伊·鲍迈斯特在他的《邪恶》一书中写道：&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;第一次世界大战比欧洲人记忆中甚至想象中的任何事情都要可怕得多，它产生了持久而持久的影响。深刻的心理影响。胜利者得出的结论是，不能再有战争了。失败者得出的结论是，必须有另一场战争来扭转局面：不能让如此多的牺牲白费。&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;这几乎就像胜利越大，胜算就越高。未来的战争。第一次世界大战导致了第二次世界大战，导致了冷战，导致了俄罗斯入侵乌克兰，等等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;风险较低，但我认为类似的事情也会发生在公司身上。你变得越大、越成功，就越难保持成功。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上个世纪的大赢家是什么？通用汽车、通用电气、IBM、诺基亚、花旗集团、柯达、美国钢铁公司……不难列出一系列在自身压力下崩溃的先前巨头。公平地说，对于每个人来说，过去的成功通过权利、竞争对手之间的嫉妒和官僚主义膨胀直接导致了未来的失败。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现在阅读这篇关于当今不可触及的巨人的最新文章，&lt;a href=&quot;https: //www.businessinsider.com/amazon-leaders-aws-day-two-mindset-2023-7&quot;>;亚马逊&lt;/a>;：&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;在亚马逊，它总是应该是“第一天，“新时代的黎明，客户至上，大胆的赌注得到支持。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;毫不奇怪，现在它是一个科技和零售巨头，维持这一点变得更加困难。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; >;员工抱怨繁文缛节、臃肿和官僚主义。面对新的财务现实，首席执行官安迪·贾西 (Andy Jassy) 在对待亚马逊的赌注时表现得非常严格。该公司面临着巨大的外部压力，包括最近联邦贸易委员会的诉讼……成为价值 1 万亿美元的革命者很难。&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;Slack 前首席执行官 &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter .com/volodarik/status/1665854827224498177?s=20&quot;>;最近解释了&lt;/a>;成功公司膨胀的一个令人着迷的原因。争夺注意力的管理者经常根据一个简单的指标对自己进行排名：有多少员工向他们报告。那么，激励就是雇佣大量的人——即使他们几乎没有什么工作要做——这样经理就可以说，“400 个人向我汇报”，这表明了他们所谓的价值和重要性。你只能在一家拥有如此多的资金和如此成功的公司来实现这一目标，以至于令人讨厌的预算都得到批准。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这有什么教训？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;小心你的愿望吗？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;保持警惕？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在背后监视？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;是的，但最重要的是一切都是周期性的。平静孕育着疯狂的种子，成长孕育着衰败的种子，成功孕育着失落的种子。一切都是周期性的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在个人层面上也是如此。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作者罗伯特·格林写道：&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;永远不要愚蠢到相信你通过炫耀使您超越他人的品质来激起钦佩。让别人意识到自己的劣势，只会激起不愉快的钦佩或嫉妒……&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;没有什么比胜利更令人陶醉的了，也没有什么比胜利更危险的了。&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p >;确实如此——你认为自己在强调自己的成就，但你所做的往往是在强调别人相对缺乏的成就，这会滋生嫉妒而不是钦佩。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是一件棘手的事情。你越成功，人们就越容易怨恨你的成功。即使有人说：“我为你感到高兴！”，而且他们是真心实意的，你的成功——也许是升职或加薪——也会让他们自己的职业生涯变得更加清晰，从而提高他们的期望，并有可能离开他们对自己的感觉更糟。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当那些曾经渴望帮助你的人将来不再热情时，支持的减少可能会反过来产生影响。说唱歌手德雷克说：“当你为某件事而努力时，人们更喜欢你，而不是当你拥有它时。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然后是金钱和野心之间的联系。威廉·范德比尔特（William Vanderbilt）曾经说过，拥有很多钱“就像可卡因对道德的毁灭一样，对野心的毁灭。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;幸福可能是另一个周期性的东西。我喜欢轮胎大王哈维·费尔斯通的这个细节，想知道他在变得富有和成名之前过着简单的生活：&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;有时似乎回到那些简单的日子可能会更好，人们可能会从不太复杂的生活中获得更多。但这是不可能的。人随着繁荣而改变。我们都认为我们应该过简单的生活，然后我们发现我们已经养成了一千个我们完全没有意识到的小习惯，因为它们是我们存在的一部分——而这些习惯并不存在于简单的生活中。 。没有回头路——除非成为一个破碎的人。&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;也许这就是循环：从梦想开始，实现那个梦想，然后以前被认为是梦想的东西变成了新的基线，然后你的野心的目光转向下一个梦想。不足、努力、兴高采烈。不足、努力、兴高采烈。一切都是周期性的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;—&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在某种程度上，这些循环是不可避免的。对于经济、股市和其他社会趋势来说尤其如此。长期的成功在很大程度上依赖于接受周期性并为其做好准备，而不是假设它可以被预防。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在个人层面，我认为周期性可以在边缘进行管理。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Shane Parrish&lt;a href=&quot;https://fs.blog/entropy/&quot;>;曾经描述&lt;/a>;被动稳定性和主动稳定性之间的区别。岩石是被动稳定的——它会在没有任何干预的情况下保持其形状。婚姻则不然。随着时间的推移，它可以保持稳定，但需要不断的工作、妥协和维护才能保持其完好无损。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;你生活中的大多数事情充其量都是积极稳定的。如果放任不管，它们将遵循周期性的自然路径。但如果有持续的干预和管理——管理你的期望、管理你的声誉、管理你如何宣传自己以及你周围的人——你至少有机会在最长的时间内保持良好的发展。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 27 Jul 2023 11:19:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/everything-is-circular/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/everything-is-circular/</guid></item><item><title>富有且匿名</title><description>&lt;p>;我认为，当金钱不仅不再带来快乐，而是成为一种社会责任时，每个人都有一个“理想”的净资产。这个数字可能比大多数人想象的要低。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;商业内幕最近 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/lottery-winners-lost-everything-2017-8#gerald- muswagon-end-up-feeling-sorry-for-partying-8&quot;>;做了一个关于彩票中奖者失去一切的故事（人们喜欢这些故事中的幸灾乐祸）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一个常见的这些故事的分母是，彩票奖金有很高的社会债务——我们可以称之为社会债务——朋友、家人和陌生人，他们觉得自己有权索要、乞讨和偷窃，这让中奖者不仅身无分文，而且在社会上也受到影响。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其中一位获奖者解释道：&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;在 1985 年 10 月赢得 390 万美元和四个月后赢得 140 万美元之后，亚当斯女士发现她不再拥有这种特权的隐私。 “我是众所周知的，”她说，“我去任何地方都不被认出来。”&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;金钱的一个微妙问题是资产很容易衡量，但负债可以隐藏。衡量彩票奖金很简单：390 万美元，精确到一分钱。但如何衡量隐私的丧失呢？或者一直怀疑有些朋友只是因为你的钱而喜欢你？这要困难得多。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我曾经和一群 NBA 新秀交谈过。话题是如何避免运动员20多岁发财，30岁破产的悲剧。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有位选手提到了我认为非常重要的一句话。他说，大多数局外人认为运动员破产是因为他们把钱花在了珠宝和汽车上。有时确实如此，但最常见的原因是社会债务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“当你在贫困中长大，然后在 22 岁时赚到 1000 万美元时，那不是你的钱，”他说。 “那是妈妈的钱，爸爸的钱，奶奶的钱，表弟的钱，朋友的钱。你不能只是告诉他们‘我得到了我的，祝你们好运。’”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;给自己买一栋豪宅不是问题；问题在于解决问题。正是为他们的第五个堂兄弟买了一栋简陋的房子，他们从未谋面，但觉得有义务帮助他们，这导致运动员破产。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些看起来像是富人的问题。但对于普通人来说，社会债务无处不在。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我曾经乘坐美铁列车从华盛顿到纽约。火车有一个“安静车厢”——每个人都应该保持安静的区域，这样你就可以睡觉或完成一些工作。人们使用安静的汽车是因为他们想要宁静，但令人惊讶的是，这种做法常常适得其反。当你期待安静时，你就会对最轻微的噪音变得异常敏感。如果安静的车内有人说话超过耳语，整个车就会陷入极度恼怒的状态。我敢打赌，坐在“安静”的汽车里实际上会让人们患上高血压。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当人们购买好东西时，类似的事情也经常发生。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;你没有当你的旧车脏了或有凹痕时，你会介意 - 但现在你买了一辆更好的车，当它变得泥泞时，你无法忍受，当有人在停车场刮擦它时，你会失去理智。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当你买了一栋更大的新房子时，你以为你会更快乐。但后来你意识到，你想要一套更好的房子的原因是为了与其他拥有更好房子的人进行社会竞争。因此，一旦您拥有一栋漂亮的房子，您就会开始梦想拥有更好的房子。一旦你承认在你的社交群体中拥有最好的家是你的目标，它不仅会成为一种痴迷，而且会成为一场无法获胜的游戏，因为你将自己与自己进行比较的群体会随着你每次加薪而变化。&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;我的理论是，人们拥有的钱越多，他们承担的社会债务就越多。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;重点并不是说你应该避免漂亮的汽车和漂亮的房子——我喜欢两者。人们意识到，一旦金钱从一种让你自己快乐的工具变成了别人衡量你的象征，你就会陷入一种难以衡量但对你的幸福感有真正影响的社会债务之中。 .&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;梭罗曾经解释过：“一件东西的成本就是我所说的生命的数量，需要立即或从长远来看来交换它。”&lt;/p>; &lt;hr />; &lt;p>;我曾经为一个价值 80 亿美元的家庭做过一些咨询。如果你用谷歌搜索他们的名字，什么也没有出现。没有福布斯排行榜，没有盛大照片，没有个人资料，没有维基百科页面……什么都没有。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是故意的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他们发现了许多其他人无法认识到的东西：你的方式最大限度地享受你的金钱是通过消除社会债务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他们拥有完全的自由、隐私和独立。他们精心挑选朋友，并匿名捐出金钱。这可能是他们最宝贵的资产。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这让我想起了 Naval 曾经说过的话：最好的位置是富有而匿名。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 19 Jul 2023 15:01:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/rich-and-anonymous/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/rich-and-anonymous/</guid></item><item><title>我们对诗歌的投资</title><description>&lt;p>;电力让世界运转。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;产生所有电力也造成了世界 25% 的排放，这主要是因为我们燃烧化石燃料来获取电力。因此，为了避免灾难性的气候变化，组织必须尽快过渡到清洁能源。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;公司意识到能源市场波动和日益明显的气候变化使他们的运营面临高度风险，因此已经做好了转型的准备。一些公司通过签订购电协议 (PPA) 帮助促进了清洁能源市场的发展，但当今大多数公司很难获得清洁能源。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果清洁能源的采购和管理仍然高度复杂，由于这种转变既耗时又昂贵，大多数组织都将难以实现这一转变。即使那些如今有能力采购清洁能源的企业仍然依赖手动流程和过时的电子表格，这些流程不适合提供强大的数据驱动分析。无碳能源采购无法在 Excel 上进行扩展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是，如果可以在直观的软件平台上购买数百兆瓦的电力并帮助您管理一切，结果会怎样呢？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;输入&lt;a href=&quot;https://verse.inc/&quot;>;Verse&lt;/a>;。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Verse 正在构建一个名为 Aria 的 SaaS 平台，该平台利用生成式 AI 为以下领域提供端到端解决方案：组织以当今所需时间和成本的一小部分购买、管理和报告清洁能源。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;公司第一次可以定义其清洁能源目标、设计和采购清洁能源组合资产、管理和优化这些资产以及报告投资组合绩效——所有这些都在一个平台上完成。总体而言，我们预计这可以将购买清洁电力的成本降低高达 70%，从而使所有公司实现无碳能源的民主化。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在 Aria 平台上，组织可以设置针对特定目标的参数（例如，成本、排放量或每小时匹配），对冲化石燃料价格波动的风险，优化清洁电力资产管理，并提供可验证的投资组合绩效报告。该平台可以帮助处于减排历程各个阶段的公司，从交易购电协议 (PPA) 到优化 100% 可再生能源、排放量或 24/7 CFE（无碳能源）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;在&lt;a href=&quot;https://collabfund.com/&quot;>;Collab Fund&lt;/a>;，我们很荣幸能够与&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/seyed-h -madaeni-ph-d-5697a749/&quot;>;赛义德·马达埃尼&lt;/a>;、&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/matt-penfold/&quot;>;马特·彭福尔德&lt;/a>;和整个 Verse 团队。我们非常高兴能与 Coatue、Twine Ventures、My Climate Journey、First Minute Capital、Future Positive 和 Incite 一起在这轮种子轮中为他们提供支持。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;通过使组织能够利用清洁电力降低能源成本Verse 的 Aria 平台大幅简化了清洁能源采购流程，将有助于扩大各行业的脱碳规模。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 19 Jul 2023 08:58:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/our-investment-in-verse/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/our-investment-in-verse/</guid></item><item><title>聪明人说的聪明事</title><description>&lt;p>;我最近看到的几句话我很喜欢：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“对掌声的渴望是人类最低等的性格特征之一。” – Jan-Willem van der Rijt&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“了解自己的一个好方法就是认真反思别人身上让你恼火的一切。” – 凯文·凯利&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“30 多岁的人知道世界将走向何方，因为他们会这么做。我已经80多岁了，所以我不知道。” – Daniel Kahneman&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我正处于人生阶段，不参与争论。即使你说1+1=5，你也是对的。玩得开心。” – 基努·里维斯&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“如果你在绝望和恐惧之间找到适当的平衡，你就可以让人们做任何事情。” – 特雷弗·诺亚&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“大多数人的幸福不是被巨大的灾难或致命的错误所毁掉的，而是被缓慢破坏性的小事情的重复所毁掉的。” – 欧内斯特·迪姆内特&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“幸福是在需要更多幸福之前获得的感觉” – 唐·德雷珀&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“适当的笑话，讲得恰当，可以更好地启发问题政治、哲学和文学的重要性胜过任何无聊的争论。” ——艾萨克·阿西莫夫&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“继承的财富必然会导致野心的死亡，就像可卡因会导致道德的死亡一样。” – William Vanderbilt&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“不需要太多就能让我们相信自己聪明又健康，但需要大量事实才能让我们相信事实恰恰相反。” – 丹·吉尔伯特&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“不安全感是贪婪之母。” ——威尔·杜兰特&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“无知越大，教条主义就越大。” – 威廉·奥斯勒&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“不要试图修复别人。只是设定界限。” – Shibetoshi Nakamoto（化名）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“通过改进你的想法来获得多巴胺比验证它们更好。 ” – 纳特·弗里德曼&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“生活中有一些你不想让他们失望的人，这很好。” – 沃伦·巴菲特&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“更多信息只是拖延的一种形式。” – Russ Roberts&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“他人对我们造成的伤害往往很严重；自残的后果往往是慢性的。” – 纳西姆·塔勒布&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“关于财富，人们最不了解的一点是，所有对金钱的快乐都会在经济变得不必要的时候结束。一个人可以在不咨询银行家的情况下购买任何他想要的东西，他不会珍惜他所购买的任何东西。” – William Dawson&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“衡量你对某人的爱的最准确的标准是你对他们的缺点的看法。” – 马克·曼森&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“假设你登上了顶峰，请记住：让你变得伟大的东西可能并不适合下一代。” – 理查德·汉明&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“除了自己的感受之外，没有人关心任何事情。” – 威尔·史密斯&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“在每一种满足的土壤中都会萌发不满的种子。” – Dee Hock&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“成千上万的人不喜欢我所做的事情。幸运的是，有数百万人这样做。” – 詹姆斯·帕特森&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“认识到你喜欢某人的什么。欣赏它作为与那个特定的人不同的品质，而不是与他或她混淆。你欣赏他们的品质是与他们所构成的特定（因此有缺陷）的例子分开存在的。” – 达伦·布朗&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“人们可能会拒绝相信某件事，即使它可以帮助他们活得更久一点，如果相信它会让他们生活得更悲伤的话。” – Cass Sunstein&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我坚信，你在生活和工作中的首要目标就是永远让自己变得过时。” – 蒂姆·汉森&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“你的感恩能力与你的权利感成反比。” – 马克·布鲁克斯&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“你的日历比你的银行账户更能衡量成功。” – James Clear&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“如果人们如此渴望幸福，为什么他们不尝试去理解自己的错误信念呢？首先，因为他们从来没有想到将它们视为错误，甚至视为信仰。他们将它们视为事实和现实，它们已经被深深地编程了。” – 安东尼·迪梅洛&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“生活的目的是体验那些你以后会怀念的东西。” – FedSpeak&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“生活中没有什么比你在思考时所认为的更重要。” – 卡尼曼&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“安全之道就是永远不安全。” – 本·富兰克林&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“如果我们不能嘲笑某件事，我们就无法理性地思考它。” – 克莱·约翰逊&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“稳定有两种类型：主动稳定和被动……当人们混淆这两种类型的稳定时，就会遇到麻烦。例如，人际关系需要关注和照顾。如果你认为你们的关系是被动稳定的，有一天你一觉醒来就会收到离婚协议书。” – 肖恩·帕里什&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“写下你的讣告，然后逆向生活。” ——巴菲特&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 05 Jul 2023 15:54:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/smart-things-smart-people-said/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/smart-things-smart-people-said/</guid></item><item><title>几个问题</title><description>&lt;p>;我钦佩谁的生活却暗自悲惨？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我相信什么是真实的，只是因为相信它使我在我的部落中享有良好的声誉？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我目前的哪一个如果我由不同的父母抚养长大，价值观会有所不同吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我最相信但证据最少的东西是什么？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;谁有正确的答案，但我因为他们沟通不好而被忽视？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;谁充满了野心，但我因为他们沟通良好而关注？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我认为什么是野心（一个好的沟通者）？特质），但实际上是嫉妒（可怕的嫉妒）？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我自己有时对别人做的事情让我恼火吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我的怀旧有多少是错误的或不完整的记忆过去？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在你的职业中，无论你变得多么聪明，有什么是不可能知道的？大卫·多伊奇说：“要注意预测和预言之间的区别。预言旨在了解无法得知的事情。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我担心的这件事实际上是一个问题，还是我在寻找需要担心的问题，因为它们让我感觉自己处于掌控之中？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; >; &lt;p>;在我的领域中，我认为什么是法则（始终有效），但实际上只是一条规则（有时有效）？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我认为什么是普遍真理，但实际上只是我自己文化所特有的规范？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;什么是上一代人的真实情况，但现在不再如此，谁还坚持这个古老的事实？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;什么是部分真实的，但是我如此绝对地相信它，并如此认真地对待它，以至于我把它变成了一种危险的信念？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;今天我的生活中是否有一些事情进展顺利，让我回顾起来并希望自己拥有在我领先时退出？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我的生活中是否有一些事情我认为我“充满热情”或“专注”，但实际上我只是沉迷于它？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我是否会花更多的时间来捍卫我已经知道的东西，而不是尝试学习新的东西？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我生活中是否有一些我认为善良且富有同情心的人，但他们实际上只是太害羞而不敢告诉我残酷的事实？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果 Instagram 是对人们生活的诚实反映，而不是精心策划的精彩片段，它会是什么样子？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我是否尽可能友善，而不仅仅是我需要有多好？&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 14:24:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/a-few-questions/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/a-few-questions/</guid></item><item><title>为什么你相信你所做的事情</title><description>&lt;p>;我记得几年前读过一篇文章，讲述也门的一位父亲因饥饿失去了一个儿子，结果又让另一个孩子患上了重病。绝望之下，他向部落长老求助，长老们推荐了一种民间疗法：将一根燃烧的棍子插入病童的胸口以排出疾病。父亲同意了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当被问及这个可怕的过程时，父亲&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2018/10/26/world/middleeast/saudi-arabia- war-yemen.html&quot;>;说：&lt;/a>;“人们说把他烧在体内就没事了。当你没有钱，你儿子病了，你就会相信任何事情。”&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&lt;em>;当你没有钱，而你的儿子病了，你就会相信任何事情。&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是一个非常有力的声明，它的某些版本适用于每个人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是一个普遍的现实：你相信什么是真实的，取决于你希望它是真实的程度。某件事越能帮助你应对不确定性，你相信它是真的的门槛就越低。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;永远都是这样。丹尼尔·笛福 (Daniel Defoe) 在 1722 年描述伦敦大瘟疫时写道：“人们比以往任何时候都更加沉迷于预言、占星术、梦境和老太太的故事。”当瘟疫杀死了四分之一的邻居时，你会相信任何能给你带来希望的东西。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Visa 创始人 Dee Hock 曾经说过：“我们生来就拥有几乎无限的相信事物的能力，因为这些信念对我们持有有利，而不是因为它们与事实有一点关系。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;想想投资者，他们的策略与他们的身份紧密相连，当它不再起作用时，他们就无法放手.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;或者是企业如此迫切地想要做好，却忽视了所有不好的方面。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;查理·芒格 &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamesclear.com/great-查理芒格的演讲/人类误判心理学&quot;>;曾经说过&lt;/a>;：&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;如果你打开电视，你会发现最明显的罪犯的母亲那个人能诊断出来，他们都认为他们的儿子是无辜的。现实太痛苦而难以忍受，所以你只能扭曲它，直到它可以忍受为止。&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;即使是看似硬科学的东西也属于这一类。法律界有一个叫做吉布森定律的东西，它规定：“对于每个博士学位，都有一个平等且相反的博士学位。”无论你想提出什么论点，你都可以找到一位合格的专家证人，他愿意在宣誓后以每小时 500 美元的价格出庭作证。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人们可以被引导去相信并捍卫几乎任何事情，因为信仰的目标往往不是发现真相，而是为了证明过去的行为是合理的，或者保护你的声誉，或者在缺乏希望时提供希望，或者最大化你的收入，或者向其他人表明你属于这个部落。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此，您相信自己所做的事情有一个原因：信念的吸引力可能会掩盖其真实性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;信念往往形成的其他几个原因：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;过去事件的记忆被过滤。你保留有意义的内容，扔掉令人困惑的细节。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;20 世纪 40 年代末，两位心理学家——戈登·奥尔波特 (Gordon Allport) 和利奥·波兹曼 (Leo Postman)——提出了他们所谓的“记忆中的平整和锐化效应”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事情是这样的：在任何重大事件中——车祸、恐怖袭击、经济衰退、流行病等——你经历和观察到的变量实际上可能有数百万个。你看到人们的情绪，听到不同的意见，读到不同的观点。你不可能记住所有的细节；实在是太多了。因此，在你的回忆中，你会强调一些记忆（锐化）并丢弃其他记忆（平整）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人们倾向于锐化那些构成一个好故事并符合他们现有观点的细节，并平整那些令人困惑、痛苦的细节。 ，或与预先存在的信念相矛盾。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此，我们有一个信念生成系统：你认为正确的东西在很大程度上基于你所经历的事情，并且你记得你的经历中的哪些部分使好故事，证实刻板印象，并将其他经历之间的点联系起来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;想想 2008 年金融危机有多么复杂。数十亿人同时做出复杂、情绪化的决定。没有人能够追踪一切。 So in hindsight people tend to believe what makes sense to them, in simple narratives – the Fed ruined the economy, bailouts were unfair, wealth was destroyed. All of those could be true and believed by one person, but argued against by another person who experienced the same economy but remembers different details. Maybe the Fed saved the economy, bailouts were the best option, and it was the buying opportunity of a lifetime. Depends what you remember.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The dangerous thing is that beliefs based on experience seem evidence-based. But when we&#39;re overwhelmed with observations in a complex world, we cherry-pick the most attractive evidence to appease our simple, story-loving minds.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;It is far easier to fool yourself into believing a falsehood than admit a mistake. Changing your mind is rarer than it should be, leading us to cling to false beliefs.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Physicist Max Tegmark writes in the book &lt;em>;This Will Make You Smarter&lt;/em>;:&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;The core of a scientific lifestyle is to change your mind when faced with information that disagrees with your views, avoiding intellectual inertia, yet many of us praise leaders who stubbornly stick to their views as “strong.” The great physicist Richard Feynman hailed “distrust of experts” as a cornerstone of science, yet herd mentality and blind faith in authority figures is widespread. Logic forms the basis of scientific reasoning, yet wishful thinking, irrational fears, and other cognitive biases often dominate decisions.&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;You can agree with every word written there and still struggle to change your mind – or take seriously those who do – for two reasons.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One, when you change your mind you can feel like all the hard-fought effort you put into establishing your previous beliefs was wasted. Even a little pain from that reality can be enough to persuade you to stick to the original belief.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two, when you change your mind, moving from one belief to another, it can be hard to take the new belief seriously – changing beliefs offers proof that the new belief may be short-lived, especially in the eyes of others.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Both recognize an important truth: Beliefs are not just about what we know; They are social signals that offer clues about how we established our beliefs, our confidence in our intelligence, and our ability to pass reliable truth to other people. The quirk is that those signals can be counterintuitive: We should want an expert who is willing to change their mind, but what we actually want is someone who&#39;s confident enough to never have to.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A lot of times we&#39;re not interested in truth – we&#39;re interested in the elimination of uncertainty, and that fact alone causes us to believe things that have little relation to reality.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 21 Jun 2023 13:58:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/why-you-believe-the-things-you-do/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/why-you-believe-the-things-you-do/</guid></item><item><title> Fear of Acorns</title><description> &lt;p>;I am a big fan of fables. Be it the Ant and the Grasshopper, the Boy Who Cried Wolf, or the Tortoise and the Hare, each are great because they are concise, entertaining, and most importantly, forever relevant. That said, a fable crossed my desk in recent weeks that I found especially relevant to the world and markets we are currently living in — “Chicken Little”.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For those of you not familiar with the story of Chicken Little, it goes something like this.&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;Chicken Little is walking in the woods when she is struck by an acorn falling from one of the trees. Convinced this is a sign the sky is falling, Chicken Little rushes from the woods to go and warn the king.&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;On her way to see the king, she runs into several friends, who are also birds and go by names like Henny Penny, Goosey Loosey, Ducky Lucky, Turkey Lurkey, and so on. As she meets each along her way, Chicken Little warns them that sky is falling and that she has first-hand evidence of this.&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;As a result, these birds join Chicken Little as she makes her way to the king. Soon enough, there is a large group of them convinced that the sky is falling on them.&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;On their way, they come across Foxy Loxy (a fox, of course), who asks them why they are in such a hurry. Chicken Little explains that the sky is falling and that they are on their way to tell the king. Foxy Loxy offers to take them to the castle where they will find the king, and the birds agree to accompany him. However, the cunning fox leads them not to the castle, but to his den, and the birds are never seen alive again.&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;The lesson?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fear is not something that is forced upon us. Rather, it is something we force upon ourselves.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How so?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because fear is a reaction we have when we are confronted by something, typically a threat.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This raises a question — is fearing something a problem?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, no. Fear itself is not necessarily a bad thing. In fact, a reasonable amount of fear is actually a &lt;em>;good&lt;/em>; thing because it is what makes us more aware of our surroundings and cautious when warranted.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, an irrational amount of fear is a problem because it makes us susceptible to the “Foxy Loxy&#39;s” of the world. Those who aim to leverage fear for personal gain. Those who sell advice, products, and services that feed into the fear. Those who want it to magnify it at every turn. The media is the obvious culprit, but there are countless others.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/Screenshot%202023-06-28%20at%2011.52.19%20AM.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot 2023-06-28 at 11.52.19 AM.png&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason this is such an important issue is because while Chicken Little treated a single acorn as a sign that the sky was falling, most people today, investors in particular, seem to be treating each and every “acorn” (ie negative headlines) as a sure fire indication that the economy and/or markets are bound to crash.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just think about the last decade alone. From Covid-19 to disinformation, crypto and the FTX fraud, Iran, China, Russia, climate change, a tech bubble 2.0, supply chain shortages, globalization, Silicon Valley Bank&#39;s collapse, office vacancies, and higher interest rates (just to name a few) have all been deemed perilous threats to financial and/or geopolitical stability. Yet we are still here with unemployment close to all-time lows and the stock market near record highs.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, this begs the question — if we look up in the sky today, what is the next acorn to fall? The next thing to fear?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is pretty obvious – Artificial Intelligence (“AI”).&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This past weekend alone there were more than two dozen articles in the various papers I read highlighting the risks surrounding AI, how it is going to dismantle the American workforce, cause the wealth gap to widen even further, destabilize the economy, and even lead to nuclear holocaust.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whoa. Talk about Chicken Little.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But should we fear this acorn? Could this finally be the &lt;em>;true&lt;/em>; sign the sky is falling?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;History tells us the answer is clearly no. That said, AI is likely going to impact sectors of the economy and markets very differently. Understanding how is the first step towards not fearing its arrival. Here are just a few examples that have been top of mind.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Education&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Remember those history reports you had to write in middle school about the Roman Empire? Or essays on the Classics in high school? Or a senior thesis in college on World War II?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While these were great ways to test how well we could regurgitate information, they were utter failures at testing how well we understood it. They taught us nothing about drawing parallels across disciplines, time periods, or circumstances. Said another way, they did not make us think.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The good news is that AI has the potential to enable future students to go well beyond these exercises in regurgitation. Instead of simply reporting on the Roman Empire, Socrates and Plato, or World War II, AI could provide the opportunity for these students to apply the lessons from each to their own lives and the world around them.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for education more broadly, the news may be even brighter as the Economist recently reported that AI is doing things like “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/united-states/2023/06/15/how-chatgpt-could-help-teachers-and-lower-the-cost-of-college&quot;>;helping teachers write lesson plans and worksheets that are at different reading levels and even in different languages.&lt;/a>;” Said another way, it is enabling more specialized teaching using the same amount of “manpower”. If so, isn&#39;t this the definition of increased productivity?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just as calculators replaced the need to manually run math equations, AI has the potential to perform much of the mindless regurgitation that students have grown accustomed to doing, enabling them to be freed up for real thought and creativity.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Healthcare&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Diagnosing and treating physical ailments is currently all about probabilities and a trial &amp;amp; error approach. Have stomach pain? The first step is typically to change your diet. Could it be something more serious? Sure, but doctors always start with the highest probability first, rightfully so. If symptoms subside, you are all set. If they don&#39;t, your doctor will probably move to the next highest probability. Maybe they will prescribe antibiotics or another prescription drug. Still not better? Next up will be a CT Scan or an MRI, but this will likely be months down the road.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So how could this change with AI? Going forward, doctors could be able to access your personal genetic makeup, cross reference your symptoms with your family history, and check it all against other patients who have experienced similar symptoms and have similar family histories/genetics. Could this change the probability picture? How about the course of treatment? What about the response time? I am guessing it would, and quite possibly in a very big way.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is just the tip of the iceberg as AI will likely also revolutionize countless other aspects, such as the way therapeutics and treatments are researched, devised, created, and administered.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Industrial&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Any company that produces something in a factory, plant, or on an assembly line should benefit tremendously from AI given that it should enable them to streamline operations, save energy (and therefore costs), increase throughput, and raise overall efficiency. This is a pretty visible end result. The better you understand your operations, the better you can run your business.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Finance&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since I cannot say it any better than &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2023-06-01/ai-bots-are-coming-to-finance&quot;>;Bloomberg&#39;s Matt Levine&lt;/a>;, I am just going to show you what he wrote last week about AI. Needless to say, I can&#39;t imagine a sector that will experience more booms and busts than finance as a result of AI.&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;“The widespread use of relatively early-stage AI will introduce new ways of making mistakes into finance. Right now there are some classic ways of making mistakes in finance, and they periodically lead to consequences ranging from funny embarrassment through multimillion-dollar trading loss up to systemic financial crises. Many of the most classic mistakes have the broad shape of “overly confident generalizing from limited historical data,” though some are, like, hitting the wrong button. But there are only so many ways to go wrong, and they are all sort of intuitive. But now there are new ways! Weird ways! Oh sure an AI can probably make overly confident generalizations from limited historical data, but perhaps there is room for novelty. Now some banker is going to type into a chat bot “our client wants to hedge the risk of the Turkish election,” and the chatbot will be like “she should sell some Dogecoin call options and use the proceeds to buy a lot of nickel futures,” and the banker will be like “weird okay whatever.” And that trade will go wrong in surprising ways, the client will sue, the client and the banker and the chatbot will all come to court, the judge will ask the chat bot “well why would this trade hedge anything,” and the chatbot will shrug its little imaginary shoulders and be like “bro why are you asking me I&#39;m a chat bot.” Or it will say “actually the Dogecoin/nickel spread was ex ante an excellent proxy for Turkish political risk because” and then emit a series of ones and zeros and emojis and high-pitched noises that you and I and the judge can&#39;t understand but that make perfect sense to the chat bot. New ways to be wrong! It will make life more exciting for financial columnists, for a bit, before we are all replaced by the chat bots.&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Consumer&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Wall Street Journal had an entire section this week dedicated to this topic titled “AI has Madison Avenue Excited — and Worried” that nearly perfectly sums up this sector. In short, there will be plenty of pros and cons.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On one hand, as trends change, preferences adjust, and demographics shift, how is AI or Chat GPT supposed to figure out what the next fad will be, what the next spring&#39;s clothing lineup should look like, or what destinations will be popular when consumers don&#39;t even know until they know? Ever look at clothing styles decade by decade? Good luck to AI bot that attempts to figure that one out. Or what about music? Movies? Cars? Home Design? Check, check, and check.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This said, there will be parts of the consumer sector that will benefit tremendously from AI, specifically those that are focused on the “here and now”, client service, and sales, as opposed to predicting the future. Look no further than a company called &lt;a href=&quot;https://cresta.com/&quot;>;Cresta&lt;/a>;, which uses generative AI to better inform, educate, and assist people in a wide variety of jobs and industries as they engage with potential customers, existing clients, and current colleagues.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are too many other possibilities to mention in this article and, as with most things that depend on human behavior, time will tell how they turn out.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sports&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We&#39;ve seen a version of AI in sports for years in the form of Billy Beane&#39;s “Moneyball”, the Houston Rockets/Golden State Warriors “Three Ball Strategy”, and in how all teams scout players, watch film, and study their opponents. I would imagine this next phase will just hypercharge this phenomenon. Ironically though, I don&#39;t think AI adoption will determine future winners.为什么？ Because it won&#39;t be novel. Everyone will be doing it. Instead, it will more likely just make the entire ecosystem more competitive, which should make it even more challenging to win a title at the highest levels due to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://fs.blog/the-paradox-of-skill/&quot;>;Paradox of Skill&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Geopolitics and Warfare&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This might be the trickiest, and most important, of all.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I wrote a few years ago about a guy named Stanislov Petrov titled “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/we-need-humans-ted-lamade/&quot;>;A Centaur Future&lt;/a>;”. While you may not have heard of him, he might be the most important person of the 20th century.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because he single handedly may have saved the planet and civilization as we know it.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the fall of 1983 Petrov was in charge of Russia&#39;s Oko nuclear early warning system. On September 23rd, the system reported that the United States had launched five nuclear missiles at the Soviet Union. At the time, the Soviets had the second most advanced missile defense technology in the world, so it would have been perfectly logical for Petrov to conclude that the threat was real. Yet, Petrov was skeptical. He concluded that it was much more likely that (a) a US strike would more likely be an “all-out” attack as opposed to just five missiles, (b) the launch detection system was new and potentially faulty, (c) the alert had passed through 30 layers of verification too quickly, and (d) the ground radar failed to pick up corroborating evidence. Despite the potential personal consequences (the end of his career at best or his life at worst), Petrov chose to disobey his orders.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As you may have guessed, Petrov&#39;s intuition proved to be correct. By relying on his instincts and not blindly following the new technology, he likely prevented a major escalation in the Cold War and an unwarranted nuclear event. Had Russia relied solely on the “AI of the day” without a human override, things might have turned out very, very differently.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;So, what does it all mean?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For something that is so confusing and complicated, the answer is likely relatively simple. For industries less dependent on human behavior, AI will likely be a highly beneficial development. However, for those more dependent us and our whims, caution is likely warranted.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This said, the majority of industries will unsurprisingly fall somewhere in the middle, which means they will be better off if they find a way to leverage, but not rely too heavily on these new technologies.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The question is, how might this look?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his best selling book, “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Range-Generalists-Triumph-Specialized-World/dp/0735214506/ref=tmm_pap_swatch_0?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1685734534&amp;amp;sr=1-1&quot;>;Range&lt;/a>;”, author David Epstein profiled a chess match between chess-master Gary Casparov and IBM&#39;s Supercomputer Deep Blue in 1997. After losing to Deep Blue, Casparov responded reticently that,&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“Anything we can do, machines will do it better. If we can codify it and pass it to computers, they will do it better”.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, after studying the match more deeply, Casparov became convinced that something else was at play. In short, he turned to “&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moravec%27s_paradox#:\~:text=Moravec&#39;s%20paradox%20is%20the%20observation,skills%20require%20enormous%20computational%20resources.&quot;>;Moravec&#39;s Paradox&lt;/a>;”, which makes the case that,&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“Machines and humans have opposite strengths and weaknesses. Therefore, the optimal scenario might be one in which the two work in tandem.”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In chess, it boils down to tactics vs. strategy. While tactics are short combinations of moves used to get an immediate advantage, strategy refers to the bigger picture planning needed to win the game. The key is that while machines are tactically flawless, they are much less capable of strategizing because strategy involves creativity.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Casparov determined through a series of chess scenarios that the optimal chess player was not Big Blue or an even more powerful machine. Instead, it came in the form of a human “coaching” multiple computers. The coach would first instruct a computer on what to examine. Then, the coach would synthesize this information in order to form an overall strategy and execute on it. These combo human/computer teams proved to be far superior, earning the nickname “centaurs”.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By taking care of the tactics, computers enabled the humans to do what they do best — strategize.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sounds about right to me.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 21 Jun 2023 02:52:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/fear-of-acorns/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/fear-of-acorns/</guid></item><item><title> The Evolution of Sustainable Materials: Six Trends to Watch</title><description> &lt;p>;Sustainable materials — materials derived from renewable resources instead of fossil fuels — form the foundation of a brighter, healthier future for the planet and all who call it home. They&#39;re also the core focus of our climate fund, &lt;a href=&quot;https://collabfund.com/blog/collab-sos-a-new-fund-and-a-call-to-action/&quot;>;Collab SOS&lt;/a>;, encompassing everything from textiles and bioplastics to green chemicals and construction materials.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the year since we launched this fund, the sector has rapidly evolved to meet the demands of a swiftly changing world. Regulatory tailwinds and buy-in from large corporations have been balanced by higher costs of capital and trepidation among investors. Yet, scientific breakthroughs – including improvements in AI-based modeling and the falling costs of both renewable energy and gene editing – have accelerated progress and unlocked new pathways to scale-up.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Here are some of the top trends we&#39;ve noticed in recent months:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;1. Diversifying Feedstock&lt;/strong>; Companies are forgoing refined feedstocks, such as sugar, and are increasingly diversifying their feedstock choices when producing valuable materials. We are now seeing an uptick in companies using agricultural crop waste, food waste, fabric waste, municipal waste, and CO2 or CH4 gas waste (eg, flue gas from industry combustion or gas from wastewater treatment plants). Not only are these feedstocks often less costly, but these re-engineered workflows can often comparably reduce GHG emissions and land use.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;2. Uniting Biology and Green Chemistry&lt;/strong>; Companies are evolving beyond trying to produce products purely through fermentation. Instead, they harness the molecules that nature provides, optimize production of the best ones using a biological host, then employ chemistry to generate the final target. This approach often reduces the cost of fermentation and downstream processing and exponentially increases the number of possible chemical targets and applications.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;3. Optimizing Downstream Processing Costs&lt;/strong>; In the current environment of steep capital costs, companies are placing a heightened focus on cost optimization. This involves finding abundant and affordable feedstocks and streamlining downstream processes, which are often energy-intensive and yield-limited. By tackling these cost drivers head-on, sustainable material companies can enhance their competitiveness and pave the way for widespread adoption.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;4. Championing Ingredients Over Brands&lt;/strong>; Companies are much more focused on B2B go-to-market strategies, versus creating their own consumer brands. At Collab, we see a lot of value in capturing as much vertical value as possible by building end-to-end processes (or as close as possible). However team skills, especially at the early stage, often align better with creating ingredients versus vertical brands. And this strategy can allow for faster scale-up.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;5. Exploring Tunable Materials&lt;/strong>; Companies no longer offer just one material. Today, they have the ability to adapt materials for specific characteristics. This is often done through the exploration of potential enzyme activities and innovative green chemistry platforms. We have especially seen this in companies producing alternative leather and in those producing fabric treatments such as alternatives to PFAS for water resistance.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;6. Maturing Cell-Free Systems and Applications&lt;/strong>; Cell-free technologies, which allow for biological reactions to occur outside the confines of a living cell, are maturing rapidly. Re-invigorated by reasonably priced, novel and tunable resins that extend the lifetime and stability of enzymes, companies can now apply this technology to producing sustainable materials and chemicals. Once primarily used in pharmaceuticals, these systems now serve broader applications, including the creation of fibers from CO2, recycling hard-to-process plastics, and synthesizing complex chemicals. Cell-free systems permit precise regulation, optimization, and enhanced yields of biosynthetic pathways with the additional capability to create materials with unique, tailored properties.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This sector is undergoing a transformative period, marked by rapid advancements and evolving strategies. The first wave of biomaterials never quite lived up to the hype, but we&#39;re extremely optimistic about the future for this latest group of innovators. The trends outlined above highlight the sector&#39;s determination to innovate and address critical challenges. As investors and advocates for a more sustainable future, we must continue to monitor these trends and collaborate with companies leading the charge in innovation.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 08:23:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/sustainable-materials-six-trends/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/sustainable-materials-six-trends/</guid></item><item><title> Reask: Predicting Extreme Weather In Uncertain Times</title><description> &lt;p>;Extreme weather events are more frequent and severe than ever before.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Climate-driven weather events caused $115B in insured financial losses globally in 2022 — an astonishing 42% higher than the prior 10-year average.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The uncertainty caused by a surge of climate perils — hurricanes, cyclones, flooding, wildfire, and drought — presents a significant problem: if insurers, corporations, and governments can&#39;t forecast damaging climate-related threats, they can&#39;t make sound decisions to protect their assets.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a major problem – and opportunity – for the financial services industry and insurance markets, and the clients they serve.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/unnamed-011cd1.png&quot; alt=&quot;unnamed-011cd1.png&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Existing solutions for climate risk prediction exist, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rms.com/&quot;>;Moody&#39; RMS&lt;/a>;, but most are reliant on historical data. These models extrapolate from “historical loss rates” — the total value of losses over a given period divided by the total amount of exposure during the same period — to attempt to predict the future. But climate change is altering the frequency and intensity of weather events in ways that make historical extrapolation insufficient.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The models that predict future climate change are based on a range of assumptions and uncertainties, and it is difficult to accurately capture all of the complex interactions between the atmosphere, oceans, and land surface.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That&#39;s where &lt;a href=&quot;https://reask.earth/&quot;>;Reask&lt;/a>; comes in.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Led by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/thomasloridan/&quot;>;Thomas Loridan &lt;/a>;and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/jamie-rodney-2b4a2782/&quot;>;Jamie Rodney&lt;/a>;, along with a team of pioneering mathematicians, meteorologists and computer scientists, Reask steers clear of historical loss rate extrapolation in favor of bottoms-up physical weather modeling — the use of mathematical models to predict the weather based on current conditions and physical laws. These models take various atmospheric parameters such as temperature, humidity, wind speed and direction, atmospheric pressure, and others as inputs and apply the principles of physics to simulate the evolution of the weather over time.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reask&#39;s secret sauce is a set of proprietary weather models leveraging AI simulations that assigns risk factors down to the square kilometer.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This approach has several benefits:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Precision&lt;/strong>;: Reask directly calculates highly accurate variables such as wind speed, and captures the full distribution of risk, moving beyond simplistic risk scores and instead allows clients to arrive at a price.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Clarity&lt;/strong>;: Reask always uses physical variables to assess risk. Any output created can be directly related back to known physics of atmospheric systems rather than pure statistics.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Global&lt;/strong>;: The Reask model is inherently global, capturing the physics of the climate, and allows clients a means to assess how climate risk can be diversified and managed within a portfolio of financial assets for the first time ever.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reask&#39;s APIs can be leveraged to empower traditional insurance and re-insurance companies such as Swiss Re, as well as a new era of climate-focused insurers such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://ourkettle.com/&quot;>;Kettle&lt;/a>;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.arbol.io/&quot;>;Arbol&lt;/a>; to underwrite risk more effectively. The data can also be used by firms like &lt;a href=&quot;https://descartesunderwriting.com/&quot;>;Descartes &lt;/a>;to develop parametric insurance products that allow speedy relief to those impacted by damaging weather events.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moreover, the specificity of the models and the global nature of Reask&#39;s predictive capabilities enable a broader set of financial institutions and large asset holders to understand the risk their entire portfolio faces so that they can protect themselves, their employees, and the broader economy against impending catastrophes.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As we approach hurricane season in the United States, we&#39;re excited to see Reask&#39;s solution made available, and we&#39;re thrilled to support Reask, as we co-lead their Seed round with our friends at Mastry Ventures.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You can follow the company&#39;s progress &lt;a href=&quot;https://reask.earth/news/&quot;>;here&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And, if you&#39;re working on ways to combat climate change, we&#39;d like to hear from you!&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 15 Jun 2023 09:15:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/reask-predicting-extreme-weather-in-uncertain-times/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/reask-predicting-extreme-weather-in-uncertain-times/</guid></item></channel></rss>