<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>合作基金</title><description>Collab Fund 是企业家推动世界前进的主要资金来源。</description><link/> https://collabfund.com<atom:link href="https://collabfund.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><pubDate> Tue, 25 Jul 2023 10:03:22 -0400</pubDate><lastbuilddate> 2023 年 7 月 25 日，星期二 10:03:22 -0400</lastbuilddate><generator>站点叶</generator><item><title>富有且匿名</title><description>&lt;p>;我认为，当金钱不仅不再带来快乐，而是成为一种社会责任时，每个人都有一个“理想”的净资产。这个数字可能比大多数人想象的要低。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《商业内幕》最近&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/lottery-winners-lost-everything-2017-8#gerald-muswagon-end-up-feeling-sorry-for-partying-8&quot;>;报道了一个关于彩票中奖者失去一切的故事&lt;/a>;（人们喜欢这些幸灾乐祸的故事）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;这些故事的一个共同点是，彩票奖金有很高的社会债务，我们可以称之为社会债务——朋友、家人和陌生人，他们觉得自己有权索要、乞讨和偷窃，这使得中奖者不仅身无分文，而且受到社会剥削。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其中一位获奖者解释道：&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;在 1985 年 10 月赢得 390 万美元和四个月后赢得 140 万美元之后，亚当斯女士发现她没有不再享有隐私权。 “我是众所周知的，”她说，“我去任何地方都不会被认出来。”&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;金钱的一个微妙问题是资产很容易衡量，但负债可能会被隐藏。衡量彩票奖金很简单：390 万美元，精确到一分钱。但如何衡量隐私的丧失呢？或者一直怀疑有些朋友只是因为你的钱而喜欢你？这要困难得多。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我曾经和一群 NBA 新秀交谈过。话题是如何避免运动员20多岁发财，30岁破产的悲剧。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有位选手提到了我认为非常重要的一句话。他说，大多数局外人认为运动员破产是因为他们把钱花在了珠宝和汽车上。有时确实如此，但最常见的原因是社会债务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“当你在贫困中长大，然后在 22 岁时赚到 1000 万美元时，那不是你的钱，”他说。 “那是妈妈的钱，爸爸的钱，奶奶的钱，表弟的钱，朋友的钱。你不能只是告诉他们‘我得到了我的，祝你们好运。’”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;给自己买一栋豪宅不是问题；问题在于解决问题。正是为他们的第五个堂兄弟买了一栋简陋的房子，他们从未谋面，但觉得有义务帮助他们，这导致运动员破产。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些看起来像是富人的问题。但对于普通人来说，社会债务无处不在。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我曾经乘坐美铁列车从华盛顿到纽约。火车有一个“安静车厢”——每个人都应该保持安静的区域，这样你就可以睡觉或完成一些工作。人们使用安静的汽车是因为他们想要宁静，但令人惊讶的是，这种做法常常适得其反。当你期待安静时，你就会对最轻微的噪音变得异常敏感。如果安静的车内有人说话超过耳语，整个车就会陷入极度恼怒的状态。我敢打赌，坐在“平静”安静的汽车里实际上会让人们血压升高。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当人们买好东西时，类似的事情也经常发生。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当你的旧车脏了或有凹痕时，你并不介意 - 但现在你买了一辆更好的车，当它变得泥泞时，你无法忍受它，当有人在停车场刮擦它时，你会失去理智。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当你买了一栋更大的新房子时，你认为你会更快乐。但后来你意识到，你想要一套更好的房子的原因是为了与其他拥有更好房子的人进行社会竞争。因此，一旦您拥有一栋漂亮的房子，您就会开始梦想拥有更好的房子。一旦你接受了在你的社会群体中拥有最好的家是你的目标，它不仅成为一种痴迷，而且成为一场无法获胜的游戏，因为你将自己与自己进行比较的群体会随着你每次加薪而变化。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我的理论是，人们拥有的钱越多，他们往往会背负更多的社会债务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;重点并不是说你应该避免漂亮的汽车和漂亮的房子 - 我喜欢两者。人们意识到，一旦金钱从你用来让自己快乐的工具变成了别人衡量你的象征，你就陷入了一种难以衡量但对你的幸福有真正影响的社会债务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;梭罗曾经解释过：“一件东西的成本就是我所说的生命的数量，需要立即或长期来交换它。”&lt;/p>; &lt;hr />; &lt;p>;我曾经为一个有价值的家庭做过一些咨询。 80 亿美元。如果你用谷歌搜索他们的名字，什么也没有出现。没有福布斯排行榜，没有盛大照片，没有个人资料，没有维基百科页面……什么都没有。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是故意的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他们发现了许多其他人未能认识到的事情：最大限度地享受金钱的方式是消除社会债务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他们拥有完全的自由、隐私和独立。他们精心挑选朋友，并匿名捐出金钱。这可能是他们最宝贵的资产。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这让我想起了 Naval 曾经说过的话：最好的位置是富有而匿名。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 19 Jul 2023 15:01:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/rich-and-anonymous/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/rich-and-anonymous/</guid></item><item><title>我们对诗歌的投资</title><description>&lt;p>;电力让世界运转。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;产生所有电力也造成了世界 25% 的排放，这主要是因为我们燃烧化石燃料来获取电力。因此，为了避免灾难性的气候变化，组织必须尽快过渡到清洁能源。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;公司意识到能源市场波动和日益明显的气候变化使他们的运营面临高度风险，因此已经做好了转型的准备。一些公司通过签订购电协议 (PPA) 帮助促进了清洁能源市场的发展，但如今大多数公司都很难获得清洁能源。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果清洁能源的采购和管理仍然高度复杂、耗时且昂贵，那么大多数组织将难以实现转型。即使那些如今有能力采购清洁能源的企业仍然依赖手动流程和过时的电子表格，这些流程不适合提供强大的数据驱动分析。无碳能源采购无法在 Excel 上进行扩展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是，如果可以在一个直观的软件平台上购买数百兆瓦的电力，帮助您管理一切，结果会怎样？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;输入 &lt;a href=&quot;https://verse.inc/&quot;>;Verse&lt;/a>;。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Verse 正在构建一个名为 Aria 的 SaaS 平台，该平台利用生成式 AI 为组织提供端到端解决方案，让他们能够以目前所需时间和成本的一小部分购买、管理和报告清洁电力。 .&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;公司第一次可以定义其清洁能源目标、设计和采购清洁能源资产组合、管理和优化这些资产以及报告投资组合绩效——所有这些都可以在一个平台上完成。总体而言，我们预计这可以将购买清洁电力的成本降低高达 70%，从而使所有公司的无碳能源民主化。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在 Aria 平台上，组织可以设置针对特定目标（例如成本、排放或每小时匹配）的参数，对冲化石燃料价格波动的风险，优化清洁电力资产管理，并提供可验证的投资组合绩效报告。该平台可以帮助处于减排历程各个阶段的公司，从签订购电协议 (PPA) 到优化 100% 可再生能源、排放量或 24/7 CFE（无碳能源）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在&lt;a href=&quot;https://collabfund.com/&quot;>;合作基金&lt;/a>;，我们很荣幸能够与 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/seyed-h-madaeni-ph-d-5697a7 合作49/&quot;>;Seyed Madaeni&lt;/a>;、&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/matt-penfold/&quot;>;Matt Penfold&lt;/a>; 以及整个 Verse 团队。我们非常高兴能与 Coatue、Twine Ventures、My Climate Journey、First Minute Capital、Future Positive 和 Incite 一起在这轮种子轮中为他们提供支持。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;通过使组织能够利用清洁电力降低能源成本并大幅简化清洁电力采购流程，Verse 的 Aria 平台将帮助扩大各行业的脱碳规模。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 19 Jul 2023 08:58:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/our-investment-in-verse/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/our-investment-in-verse/</guid></item><item><title>聪明人说的聪明事</title><description>&lt;p>;我最近看到的几句话我很喜欢：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“对掌声的渴望是人类最低等的性格特征之一。” – Jan-Willem van der Rijt&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“了解自己的一个好方法就是认真反思别人身上让你恼火的一切。” – 凯文·凯利&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“30 多岁的人知道世界将走向何方，因为他们会这么做。我已经80多岁了，所以我不知道。” – Daniel Kahneman&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我正处于人生阶段，不参与争论。即使你说1+1=5，你也是对的。玩得开心。” – 基努·里维斯&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“如果你在绝望和恐惧之间找到适当的平衡，你就可以让人们做任何事情。” – 特雷弗·诺亚&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“大多数人的幸福不是被巨大的灾难或致命的错误所毁掉的，而是被缓慢破坏性的小事情的重复所毁掉的。” - 欧内斯特·迪姆内特&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“幸福是在你需要更多幸福之前获得的感觉” - 唐·德雷珀&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“适当的笑话，正确的讲法，比任何数量的无聊争论更能启发政治、哲学和文学问题。” ——艾萨克·阿西莫夫&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“继承的财富必然会导致野心的死亡，就像可卡因会导致道德的死亡一样。” – William Vanderbilt&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“不需要太多就能让我们相信自己聪明又健康，但需要大量事实才能让我们相信事实恰恰相反。” – 丹·吉尔伯特&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“不安全感是贪婪之母。” ——威尔·杜兰特&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“无知越大，教条主义就越大。” – 威廉·奥斯勒&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“不要试图修复别人。只是设定界限。” – Shibetoshi Nakamoto（化名）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“通过改进你的想法来获得多巴胺比验证它们更好。 ” – 纳特·弗里德曼&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“生活中有一些你不想让他们失望的人，这很好。” – 沃伦·巴菲特&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“更多信息只是拖延的一种形式。” – Russ Roberts&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“他人对我们造成的伤害往往很严重；自残的后果往往是慢性的。” – 纳西姆·塔勒布&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“关于财富，人们最不了解的一点是，所有对金钱的快乐都会在经济变得不必要的时候结束。一个人可以在不咨询银行家的情况下购买任何他想要的东西，他不会珍惜他所购买的任何东西。” – William Dawson&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“衡量你对某人的爱的最准确的标准是你对他们的缺点的看法。” – 马克·曼森&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“假设你登上了顶峰，请记住：让你变得伟大的东西可能并不适合下一代。” – 理查德·汉明&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“除了自己的感受之外，没有人关心任何事情。” – 威尔·史密斯&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“在每一种满足的土壤中都会萌发不满的种子。” – Dee Hock&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“成千上万的人不喜欢我所做的事情。幸运的是，有数百万人这样做。” – 詹姆斯·帕特森&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“认识到你喜欢某人的什么。欣赏它作为与那个特定的人不同的品质，而不是与他或她混淆。你欣赏他们的品质是与他们所构成的特定（因此有缺陷）的例子分开存在的。” – 达伦·布朗&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“人们可能会拒绝相信某件事，即使它可以帮助他们活得更久一点，如果相信它会让他们生活得更悲伤的话。” – Cass Sunstein&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我坚信，你在生活和工作中的首要目标就是永远让自己变得过时。” – 蒂姆·汉森&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“你的感恩能力与你的权利感成反比。” – 马克·布鲁克斯&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“你的日历比你的银行账户更能衡量成功。” – James Clear&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“如果人们如此渴望幸福，为什么他们不尝试去理解自己的错误信念呢？首先，因为他们从来没有想到将它们视为错误，甚至视为信仰。他们将它们视为事实和现实，它们已经被深深地编程了。” – 安东尼·迪梅洛&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“生活的目的是体验那些你以后会怀念的东西。” – FedSpeak&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“生活中没有什么比你在思考时所认为的更重要。” – 卡尼曼&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“安全之道就是永远不安全。” – 本·富兰克林&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“如果我们不能嘲笑某件事，我们就无法理性地思考它。” – 克莱·约翰逊&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“稳定有两种类型：主动稳定和被动……当人们混淆这两种类型的稳定时，就会遇到麻烦。例如，人际关系需要关注和照顾。如果你认为你们的关系是被动稳定的，有一天你一觉醒来就会收到离婚协议书。” – 肖恩·帕里什&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“写下你的讣告，然后逆向生活。” ——巴菲特&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 05 Jul 2023 15:54:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/smart-things-smart-people-said/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/smart-things-smart-people-said/</guid></item><item><title>几个问题</title><description>&lt;p>;我钦佩谁的生活却暗自悲惨？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我相信什么是真实的，只是因为相信它能让我在我的部落中拥有良好的信誉？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果我由不同的父母抚养长大，我目前的哪些价值观会有所不同？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我最相信什么，但证据最少？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;谁有正确的答案，但我忽略了，因为他们是一个糟糕的沟通者？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;谁充满了&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;什么是我认为是野心（一个好的特质）但实际上是嫉妒（一个可怕的特质）？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我自己有时对别人所做的事情让我恼火？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我的怀旧有多少是对过去的错误或不完整的记忆？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在你的职业中，无论你变得多么聪明，什么是不可能知道的？大卫·多伊奇说：“要注意预测和预言之间的区别。预言声称可以知道未知的事情。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我担心的这件事实际上是一个问题吗，还是我在寻找需要担心的问题，因为它们让我感觉自己处于掌控之中？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在我的领域，什么是我认为是法律（始终有效）但实际上只是规则（有时有效）？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我认为什么是普遍真理，但实际上只是我自己文化特有的规范？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;什么上一代人曾经是正确的，现在已经不再是了，谁还坚持这个古老的真理？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;什么是部分正确的，但我如此绝对地相信它，并且如此认真地对待它，以至于我把它变成了一种危险的信念？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;今天我的生活中是否有一些事情进展顺利，我会回顾起来并希望我在前进时放弃？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我的生活中是否有一些事情我认为我“充满热情”或“专注”，但实际上我只是沉迷于它吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我是否会花更多的时间捍卫我已经知道的东西，而不是尝试学习新的东西？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我的生活中是否有一些我认为善良和富有同情心的人，但他们实际上只是太害羞而不敢告诉我残酷的事实？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果 Instagram 是人们生活的诚实反映，而不是精心策划的精彩片段，那么它会是什么样子？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我是否已尽我所能，而不是我需要的那样友善？ ？&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 14:24:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/a-few-questions/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/a-few-questions/</guid></item><item><title>为什么你相信你所做的事情</title><description>&lt;p>;我记得几年前读过一篇文章，讲述也门的一位父亲因饥饿失去了一个儿子，结果又让另一个孩子患上了重病。绝望之下，他向部落长老求助，长老们推荐了一种民间疗法：将一根燃烧的棍子插入病童的胸口以排出疾病。父亲同意了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当被问及这个可怕的过程时，父亲&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2018/10/26/world/middleeast/saudi-arabia-war-yemen.html&quot;>;说：&lt;/a>;“人们说把他烧死在身体里就没事了。当你没有钱的时候，你儿子生病了，你就会相信任何事情。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;当你没有钱的时候，如果你的儿子病了，你就会相信任何事情。&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是一个非常有力的声明，它的某些版本适用于每个人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是一个普遍的现实：你相信什么是真实的，取决于你希望它是真实的程度。某件事越能帮助你应对不确定性，你相信它是真的的门槛就越低。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;永远都是这样。丹尼尔·笛福 (Daniel Defoe) 在 1722 年描述伦敦大瘟疫时写道：“人们比以往任何时候都更加沉迷于预言、占星术、梦境和老太太的故事。”当瘟疫杀死你四分之一的邻居时，你会相信任何能给你带来希望的东西。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Visa 创始人 Dee Hock 曾经说过，“我们生来就有几乎无限的能力去相信事物，因为这些信念对我们来说是有利的，而不是因为它们与真相有遥远的联系。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;想想那些策略与他们的身份紧密相连的投资者，当它停止工作时，他们就无法放手。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;或者是那些如此迫切地想要成为的企业。查理·芒格&lt;a href=&quot;https://jamesclear.com/great-speeches/psychology-of- human-misjudgment-by-charlie-munger&quot;>;曾经说过&lt;/a>;：&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;如果你打开电视，你会发现人类所能诊断出的最明显的罪犯的母亲，他们都认为自己的儿子是无辜的。现实太痛苦而难以忍受，所以你只能扭曲它，直到它可以忍受为止。&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;即使是看似硬科学的东西也属于这一类。法律界有一个叫做吉布森定律的东西，它规定：“对于每个博士学位，都有一个平等且相反的博士学位。”无论你想提出什么论点，你都可以找到一位合格的专家证人，他愿意在宣誓后以每小时 500 美元的价格出庭作证。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人们可以被引导去相信和捍卫几乎任何事情，因为信仰的目标往往不是发现真相 - 它是为了证明过去的行为，或保护你的声誉，或在缺乏时提供希望，或最大化你的收入，或向其他人表明你属于这个部落。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所以，这是你相信自己所做的事情的原因之一：信念的吸引力可能会掩盖其真实性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;信念往往形成的其他几个原因：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;过去事件的记忆被过滤。你保留有意义的东西，扔掉令人困惑的细节。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在 20 世纪 40 年代末，两位心理学家 — 戈登·奥尔波特 (Gordon Allport) 和利奥·波兹曼 (Leo Postman) — 提出了他们所谓的记忆中的均衡和锐化效应。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事情是这样的：在任何重大事件中——车祸、恐怖袭击、经济衰退、流行病等——你经历和观察到的变量实际上可能有数百万个。你看到人们的情绪，听到不同的意见，读到不同的观点。你不可能记住所有的细节；实在是太多了。因此，在你的回忆中，你会强调一些记忆（锐化），而丢弃另一些记忆（平整）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人们倾向于锐化细节，以构成一个好故事并适合他们现有的观点，并平整那些令人困惑、痛苦或与预先存在的信念相矛盾的细节。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所以这里我们有一个信念生成系统：你认为真实的东西在很大程度上基于你所经历的事情，你会记住你的经历中那些能够构成好故事、证实刻板印象并将其他经历之间的点联系起来的部分。 .&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;想想 2008 年金融危机有多么复杂。数十亿人同时做出复杂、情绪化的决定。没有人能够追踪一切。因此，事后看来，人们倾向于相信对他们来说有意义的简单叙述——美联储毁了经济，救助不公平，财富被摧毁。所有这些都可能是真实的并且被一个人相信，但被另一个经历过相同经济但记得不同细节的人反对。也许美联储拯救了经济，救助是最好的选择，也是千载难逢的买入机会。取决于你记得什么。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;危险的是，基于经验的信念似乎是基于证据的。但是，当我们对复杂世界的观察不知所措时，我们会挑选最有吸引力的证据来安抚我们简单、热爱故事的头脑。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;欺骗自己相信谎言比承认错误要容易得多。改变你的想法比应有的情况更罕见，这导致我们坚持错误的信念。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;物理学家马克斯·泰格马克在《这会让你更聪明》一书中写道：&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;科学生活方式的核心是在面对与你的观点不一致的信息时改变你的想法，避免智力惰性，但我们中的许多人称赞那些顽固坚持自己观点的领导者是“坚强的”。伟大的物理学家理查德·费曼将“对专家的不信任”誉为科学的基石，但从众心理和对权威人物的迷信却普遍存在。逻辑构成了科学推理的基础，但一厢情愿的想法、非理性的恐惧和其他认知偏见常常主导决策。&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;你可以同意其中写的每一个字，但仍然很难改变你的想法——或者认真对待那些改变主意的人——原因有两个。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第一，当你改变主意时，你会觉得你为建立以前的信念而付出的所有艰苦努力都被浪费了。即使是现实带来的一点痛苦也足以说服你坚持原来的信念。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第二，当你改变主意，从一种信念转向另一种信念时，可能很难认真对待新信念 - 改变信念证明新信念可能是短暂的，尤其是在其他人眼中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;两者都认识到一个重要的事实：信念不仅仅与我们所知道的有关；它还与我们所知道的有关。它们是社会信号，提供有关我们如何建立信仰、对自己智力的信心以及向他人传递可靠事实的能力的线索。奇怪的是，这些信号可能是违反直觉的：我们应该想要一个愿意改变主意的专家，但我们真正想要的是一个足够自信、永远不必这样做的人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;很多时候我们对真相不感兴趣 - 我们感兴趣的是消除不确定性，而事实本身就让我们相信与现实无关的事情。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 21 Jun 2023 13:58:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/why-you- believe-the-things-you-do/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/why-you- believe-the-things-you-do/</guid></item><item><title>对橡子的恐惧</title><description>&lt;p>;我是寓言的忠实粉丝。无论是《蚂蚁和蚱蜢》、《狼来了》还是《龟兔赛跑》，每部作品都很棒，因为它们简洁、有趣，最重要的是，它们永远具有相关性。也就是说，最近几周我的办公桌上出现了一个寓言，我发现它与我们目前生活的世界和市场特别相关——“小鸡”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于那些不熟悉小鸡故事的人来说，它是这样的。&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;小鸡在树林里散步，被一颗从树上掉下来的橡子击中。小鸡确信这是天塌下来的征兆，于是从树林里冲出来警告国王。&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;在去见国王的路上，她遇到了几个朋友，他们也是鸟，名字有 Henny Penny、Goosey Loosey、Ducky Lucky、Turkey Lurkey 等。当她沿途遇到每个人时，小鸡警告他们天要塌下来了，并且她有第一手证据。&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;因此，这些鸟加入了小鸡，一起走向国王。很快，一大群人相信天要塌下来了。&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;在路上，他们遇到了 Foxy Loxy（当然是一只狐狸），后者问他们为什么这么着急。小鸡解释说天要塌下来了，他们正在去告诉国王的路上。狡猾的洛克西提出带他们去城堡，在那里他们会找到国王，鸟儿们同意陪伴他。然而，狡猾的狐狸没有把他们带到城堡，而是带到了他的巢穴，而这些鸟儿再也没有活着见过。&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;教训？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;恐惧不是强加给我们的东西。相反，它是我们强加给自己的东西。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;怎么会这样？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因为恐惧是我们面对某事（通常是威胁）时的反应。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这就提出了一个问题——害怕某事是一个问题吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;简而言之，不是。恐惧本身并不一定是坏事。事实上，适度的恐惧实际上是一件&lt;em>;好事&lt;/em>;，因为它让我们更加了解周围的环境，并在必要时保持谨慎。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，不合理的恐惧是一个问题，因为它使我们容易受到世界上“Foxy Loxy”的影响。那些旨在利用恐惧来谋取个人利益的人。那些出售会加剧恐惧的建议、产品和服务的人。那些想要它的人动不动就把它放大。媒体是明显的罪魁祸首，但还有无数其他人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/Screenshot%202023-06-28%20at%2011.52.19%20AM.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot 2023-06-28 at 11.52.19 AM.png&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;原因如下重要的问题是，虽然小鸡将一颗橡子视为天塌下来的迹象，但今天的大多数人，尤其是投资者，似乎将每一个“橡子”（即负面头条新闻）视为经济和/或市场必然崩溃的明确迹象。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;仅考虑一下过去十年。从 Covid-19 到虚假信息、加密货币和 FTX 欺诈、伊朗、中国、俄罗斯、气候变化、科技泡沫 2.0、供应链短缺、全球化、硅谷银行倒闭、办公室空缺和利率上升（仅举几例）都被视为对金融和/或地缘政治稳定的危险威胁。然而，失业率仍接近历史低点，股市也接近历史高点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此，这就引出了一个问题：如果我们今天抬头仰望天空，下一个掉落的橡子是什么？接下来要担心的事情？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;很明显——人工智能（“AI”）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;仅上周末，我在各种报纸上读到了两打以上的文章，强调了人工智能的风险，它将如何瓦解美国劳动力，导致贫富差距进一步扩大，破坏经济稳定，甚至导致核浩劫。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;哇哦。谈论小鸡。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是我们应该害怕这个橡子吗？这最终可能是天塌下来的&lt;em>;真实&lt;/em>;迹象吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;历史告诉我们，答案显然是否定的。也就是说，人工智能可能会对经济部门和市场产生截然不同的影响。了解如何是不惧怕它到来的第一步。这里只是一些最重要的例子。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;教育&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;还记得你在中学时必须写的关于罗马帝国的历史报告吗？或者高中经典作文？还是关于第二次世界大战的大学毕业论文？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;虽然这些是测试我们复述信息能力的好方法，但在测试我们对信息的理解程度方面却完全失败了。他们没有教我们如何在不同学科、不同时期或不同环境之间进行比较。换句话说，它们并没有让我们思考。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;好消息是，人工智能有潜力使未来的学生能够远远超越这些反胃练习。人工智能不仅可以简单地报道罗马帝国、苏格拉底和柏拉图，或者第二次世界大战，还可以为这些学生提供机会，将每个人的经验教训应用到自己的生活和周围的世界中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;就更广泛的教育而言，这个消息可能会更加光明，因为《经济学人》最近报道人工智能正在做“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/united-states/2023/06/15/how-chatgpt-could-help”之类的事情-teachers-and-lower-the-cost-of-college&quot;>;帮助教师编写不同阅读水平甚至不同语言的教案和作业单。&lt;/a>;”换句话说，它正在使用相同数量的“人力”实现更专业的教学。如果是这样，这难道不是提高生产力的定义吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;正如计算器取代了手动运行数学方程的需要一样，人工智能有潜力执行学生已经习惯做的大部分无意识的反省，使他们能够解放出来进行真正的思考和创造力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;医疗保健&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前，诊断和治疗身体疾病都与概率和试验有关。错误方法。有胃痛吗？第一步通常是改变饮食。会不会有更严重的事情？当然可以，但医生总是先从最高概率开始，这是理所当然的。如果症状消退，则一切准备就绪。如果他们不这样做，你的医生可能会转向下一个最高的可能性。也许他们会开抗生素或其他处方药。还是没有好一点？接下来将是 CT 扫描或 MRI，但这可能需要几个月的时间。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那么人工智能会如何改变这种情况呢？展望未来，医生可以访问您的个人基因组成，将您的症状与家族史进行交叉对照，并与其他经历过类似症状和具有相似家族史/遗传学的患者进行检查。这会改变概率图吗？疗程怎么样？响应时间怎么样？我猜它会，而且很可能会以很大的方式。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这只是冰山一角，因为人工智能还可能会彻底改变无数其他方面，例如研究、设计、创造和管理治疗方法和治疗的方式。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;工业&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;任何在工厂、工厂或装配线上生产产品的公司都应该从人工智能中受益匪浅，因为人工智能应该使他们能够简化运营、节省能源（从而降低成本）、增加吞吐量并提高整体效率。这是一个非常明显的最终结果。你越了解自己的运营，你就能越好地经营你的业务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;财务&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;由于我无法比 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2023-06-01/ai-bots-are-coming-to-finance&quot;>;彭博社的 Matt Levine&lt;/a>; 更好地表达这一点，我将向您展示他上周写的有关人工智能的文章。 Needless to say, I can&#39;t imagine a sector that will experience more booms and busts than finance as a result of AI.&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;“The widespread use of relatively early-stage AI will introduce new ways of making mistakes into finance. Right now there are some classic ways of making mistakes in finance, and they periodically lead to consequences ranging from funny embarrassment through multimillion-dollar trading loss up to systemic financial crises. Many of the most classic mistakes have the broad shape of “overly confident generalizing from limited historical data,” though some are, like, hitting the wrong button. But there are only so many ways to go wrong, and they are all sort of intuitive. But now there are new ways! Weird ways! Oh sure an AI can probably make overly confident generalizations from limited historical data, but perhaps there is room for novelty. Now some banker is going to type into a chat bot “our client wants to hedge the risk of the Turkish election,” and the chatbot will be like “she should sell some Dogecoin call options and use the proceeds to buy a lot of nickel futures,” and the banker will be like “weird okay whatever.” And that trade will go wrong in surprising ways, the client will sue, the client and the banker and the chatbot will all come to court, the judge will ask the chat bot “well why would this trade hedge anything,” and the chatbot will shrug its little imaginary shoulders and be like “bro why are you asking me I&#39;m a chat bot.” Or it will say “actually the Dogecoin/nickel spread was ex ante an excellent proxy for Turkish political risk because” and then emit a series of ones and zeros and emojis and high-pitched noises that you and I and the judge can&#39;t understand but that make perfect sense to the chat bot. New ways to be wrong! It will make life more exciting for financial columnists, for a bit, before we are all replaced by the chat bots.&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Consumer&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Wall Street Journal had an entire section this week dedicated to this topic titled “AI has Madison Avenue Excited — and Worried” that nearly perfectly sums up this sector. In short, there will be plenty of pros and cons.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On one hand, as trends change, preferences adjust, and demographics shift, how is AI or Chat GPT supposed to figure out what the next fad will be, what the next spring&#39;s clothing lineup should look like, or what destinations will be popular when consumers don&#39;t even know until they know? Ever look at clothing styles decade by decade? Good luck to AI bot that attempts to figure that one out. Or what about music? Movies? Cars? Home Design? Check, check, and check.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This said, there will be parts of the consumer sector that will benefit tremendously from AI, specifically those that are focused on the “here and now”, client service, and sales, as opposed to predicting the future. Look no further than a company called &lt;a href=&quot;https://cresta.com/&quot;>;Cresta&lt;/a>;, which uses generative AI to better inform, educate, and assist people in a wide variety of jobs and industries as they engage with potential customers, existing clients, and current colleagues.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are too many other possibilities to mention in this article and, as with most things that depend on human behavior, time will tell how they turn out.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sports&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We&#39;ve seen a version of AI in sports for years in the form of Billy Beane&#39;s “Moneyball”, the Houston Rockets/Golden State Warriors “Three Ball Strategy”, and in how all teams scout players, watch film, and study their opponents. I would imagine this next phase will just hypercharge this phenomenon. Ironically though, I don&#39;t think AI adoption will determine future winners.为什么？ Because it won&#39;t be novel. Everyone will be doing it. Instead, it will more likely just make the entire ecosystem more competitive, which should make it even more challenging to win a title at the highest levels due to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://fs.blog/the-paradox-of-skill/&quot;>;Paradox of Skill&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Geopolitics and Warfare&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This might be the trickiest, and most important, of all.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I wrote a few years ago about a guy named Stanislov Petrov titled “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/we-need-humans-ted-lamade/&quot;>;A Centaur Future&lt;/a>;”. While you may not have heard of him, he might be the most important person of the 20th century.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because he single handedly may have saved the planet and civilization as we know it.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the fall of 1983 Petrov was in charge of Russia&#39;s Oko nuclear early warning system. On September 23rd, the system reported that the United States had launched five nuclear missiles at the Soviet Union. At the time, the Soviets had the second most advanced missile defense technology in the world, so it would have been perfectly logical for Petrov to conclude that the threat was real. Yet, Petrov was skeptical. He concluded that it was much more likely that (a) a US strike would more likely be an “all-out” attack as opposed to just five missiles, (b) the launch detection system was new and potentially faulty, (c) the alert had passed through 30 layers of verification too quickly, and (d) the ground radar failed to pick up corroborating evidence. Despite the potential personal consequences (the end of his career at best or his life at worst), Petrov chose to disobey his orders.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As you may have guessed, Petrov&#39;s intuition proved to be correct. By relying on his instincts and not blindly following the new technology, he likely prevented a major escalation in the Cold War and an unwarranted nuclear event. Had Russia relied solely on the “AI of the day” without a human override, things might have turned out very, very differently.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;So, what does it all mean?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For something that is so confusing and complicated, the answer is likely relatively simple. For industries less dependent on human behavior, AI will likely be a highly beneficial development. However, for those more dependent us and our whims, caution is likely warranted.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This said, the majority of industries will unsurprisingly fall somewhere in the middle, which means they will be better off if they find a way to leverage, but not rely too heavily on these new technologies.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The question is, how might this look?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his best selling book, “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Range-Generalists-Triumph-Specialized-World/dp/0735214506/ref=tmm_pap_swatch_0?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1685734534&amp;amp;sr=1-1&quot;>;Range&lt;/a>;”, author David Epstein profiled a chess match between chess-master Gary Casparov and IBM&#39;s Supercomputer Deep Blue in 1997. After losing to Deep Blue, Casparov responded reticently that,&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“Anything we can do, machines will do it better. If we can codify it and pass it to computers, they will do it better”.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, after studying the match more deeply, Casparov became convinced that something else was at play. In short, he turned to “&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moravec%27s_paradox#:\~:text=Moravec&#39;s%20paradox%20is%20the%20observation,skills%20require%20enormous%20computational%20resources.&quot;>;Moravec&#39;s Paradox&lt;/a>;”, which makes the case that,&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“Machines and humans have opposite strengths and weaknesses. Therefore, the optimal scenario might be one in which the two work in tandem.”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In chess, it boils down to tactics vs. strategy. While tactics are short combinations of moves used to get an immediate advantage, strategy refers to the bigger picture planning needed to win the game. The key is that while machines are tactically flawless, they are much less capable of strategizing because strategy involves creativity.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Casparov determined through a series of chess scenarios that the optimal chess player was not Big Blue or an even more powerful machine. Instead, it came in the form of a human “coaching” multiple computers. The coach would first instruct a computer on what to examine. Then, the coach would synthesize this information in order to form an overall strategy and execute on it. These combo human/computer teams proved to be far superior, earning the nickname “centaurs”.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By taking care of the tactics, computers enabled the humans to do what they do best — strategize.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sounds about right to me.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 21 Jun 2023 02:52:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/fear-of-acorns/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/fear-of-acorns/</guid></item><item><title> The Evolution of Sustainable Materials: Six Trends to Watch</title><description> &lt;p>;Sustainable materials — materials derived from renewable resources instead of fossil fuels — form the foundation of a brighter, healthier future for the planet and all who call it home. They&#39;re also the core focus of our climate fund, &lt;a href=&quot;https://collabfund.com/blog/collab-sos-a-new-fund-and-a-call-to-action/&quot;>;Collab SOS&lt;/a>;, encompassing everything from textiles and bioplastics to green chemicals and construction materials.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the year since we launched this fund, the sector has rapidly evolved to meet the demands of a swiftly changing world. Regulatory tailwinds and buy-in from large corporations have been balanced by higher costs of capital and trepidation among investors. Yet, scientific breakthroughs – including improvements in AI-based modeling and the falling costs of both renewable energy and gene editing – have accelerated progress and unlocked new pathways to scale-up.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Here are some of the top trends we&#39;ve noticed in recent months:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;1. Diversifying Feedstock&lt;/strong>; Companies are forgoing refined feedstocks, such as sugar, and are increasingly diversifying their feedstock choices when producing valuable materials. We are now seeing an uptick in companies using agricultural crop waste, food waste, fabric waste, municipal waste, and CO2 or CH4 gas waste (eg, flue gas from industry combustion or gas from wastewater treatment plants). Not only are these feedstocks often less costly, but these re-engineered workflows can often comparably reduce GHG emissions and land use.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;2. Uniting Biology and Green Chemistry&lt;/strong>; Companies are evolving beyond trying to produce products purely through fermentation. Instead, they harness the molecules that nature provides, optimize production of the best ones using a biological host, then employ chemistry to generate the final target. This approach often reduces the cost of fermentation and downstream processing and exponentially increases the number of possible chemical targets and applications.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;3. Optimizing Downstream Processing Costs&lt;/strong>; In the current environment of steep capital costs, companies are placing a heightened focus on cost optimization. This involves finding abundant and affordable feedstocks and streamlining downstream processes, which are often energy-intensive and yield-limited. By tackling these cost drivers head-on, sustainable material companies can enhance their competitiveness and pave the way for widespread adoption.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;4. Championing Ingredients Over Brands&lt;/strong>; Companies are much more focused on B2B go-to-market strategies, versus creating their own consumer brands. At Collab, we see a lot of value in capturing as much vertical value as possible by building end-to-end processes (or as close as possible). However team skills, especially at the early stage, often align better with creating ingredients versus vertical brands. And this strategy can allow for faster scale-up.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;5. Exploring Tunable Materials&lt;/strong>; Companies no longer offer just one material. Today, they have the ability to adapt materials for specific characteristics. This is often done through the exploration of potential enzyme activities and innovative green chemistry platforms. We have especially seen this in companies producing alternative leather and in those producing fabric treatments such as alternatives to PFAS for water resistance.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;6. Maturing Cell-Free Systems and Applications&lt;/strong>; Cell-free technologies, which allow for biological reactions to occur outside the confines of a living cell, are maturing rapidly. Re-invigorated by reasonably priced, novel and tunable resins that extend the lifetime and stability of enzymes, companies can now apply this technology to producing sustainable materials and chemicals. Once primarily used in pharmaceuticals, these systems now serve broader applications, including the creation of fibers from CO2, recycling hard-to-process plastics, and synthesizing complex chemicals. Cell-free systems permit precise regulation, optimization, and enhanced yields of biosynthetic pathways with the additional capability to create materials with unique, tailored properties.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This sector is undergoing a transformative period, marked by rapid advancements and evolving strategies. The first wave of biomaterials never quite lived up to the hype, but we&#39;re extremely optimistic about the future for this latest group of innovators. The trends outlined above highlight the sector&#39;s determination to innovate and address critical challenges. As investors and advocates for a more sustainable future, we must continue to monitor these trends and collaborate with companies leading the charge in innovation.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 08:23:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/sustainable-materials-six-trends/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/sustainable-materials-six-trends/</guid></item><item><title> Reask: Predicting Extreme Weather In Uncertain Times</title><description> &lt;p>;Extreme weather events are more frequent and severe than ever before.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Climate-driven weather events caused $115B in insured financial losses globally in 2022 — an astonishing 42% higher than the prior 10-year average.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The uncertainty caused by a surge of climate perils — hurricanes, cyclones, flooding, wildfire, and drought — presents a significant problem: if insurers, corporations, and governments can&#39;t forecast damaging climate-related threats, they can&#39;t make sound decisions to protect their assets.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a major problem – and opportunity – for the financial services industry and insurance markets, and the clients they serve.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/unnamed-011cd1.png&quot; alt=&quot;unnamed-011cd1.png&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Existing solutions for climate risk prediction exist, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rms.com/&quot;>;Moody&#39; RMS&lt;/a>;, but most are reliant on historical data. These models extrapolate from “historical loss rates” — the total value of losses over a given period divided by the total amount of exposure during the same period — to attempt to predict the future. But climate change is altering the frequency and intensity of weather events in ways that make historical extrapolation insufficient.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The models that predict future climate change are based on a range of assumptions and uncertainties, and it is difficult to accurately capture all of the complex interactions between the atmosphere, oceans, and land surface.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That&#39;s where &lt;a href=&quot;https://reask.earth/&quot;>;Reask&lt;/a>; comes in.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Led by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/thomasloridan/&quot;>;Thomas Loridan &lt;/a>;and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/jamie-rodney-2b4a2782/&quot;>;Jamie Rodney&lt;/a>;, along with a team of pioneering mathematicians, meteorologists and computer scientists, Reask steers clear of historical loss rate extrapolation in favor of bottoms-up physical weather modeling — the use of mathematical models to predict the weather based on current conditions and physical laws. These models take various atmospheric parameters such as temperature, humidity, wind speed and direction, atmospheric pressure, and others as inputs and apply the principles of physics to simulate the evolution of the weather over time.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reask&#39;s secret sauce is a set of proprietary weather models leveraging AI simulations that assigns risk factors down to the square kilometer.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This approach has several benefits:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Precision&lt;/strong>;: Reask directly calculates highly accurate variables such as wind speed, and captures the full distribution of risk, moving beyond simplistic risk scores and instead allows clients to arrive at a price.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Clarity&lt;/strong>;: Reask always uses physical variables to assess risk. Any output created can be directly related back to known physics of atmospheric systems rather than pure statistics.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Global&lt;/strong>;: The Reask model is inherently global, capturing the physics of the climate, and allows clients a means to assess how climate risk can be diversified and managed within a portfolio of financial assets for the first time ever.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reask&#39;s APIs can be leveraged to empower traditional insurance and re-insurance companies such as Swiss Re, as well as a new era of climate-focused insurers such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://ourkettle.com/&quot;>;Kettle&lt;/a>;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.arbol.io/&quot;>;Arbol&lt;/a>; to underwrite risk more effectively. The data can also be used by firms like &lt;a href=&quot;https://descartesunderwriting.com/&quot;>;Descartes &lt;/a>;to develop parametric insurance products that allow speedy relief to those impacted by damaging weather events.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moreover, the specificity of the models and the global nature of Reask&#39;s predictive capabilities enable a broader set of financial institutions and large asset holders to understand the risk their entire portfolio faces so that they can protect themselves, their employees, and the broader economy against impending catastrophes.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As we approach hurricane season in the United States, we&#39;re excited to see Reask&#39;s solution made available, and we&#39;re thrilled to support Reask, as we co-lead their Seed round with our friends at Mastry Ventures.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You can follow the company&#39;s progress &lt;a href=&quot;https://reask.earth/news/&quot;>;here&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And, if you&#39;re working on ways to combat climate change, we&#39;d like to hear from you!&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 15 Jun 2023 09:15:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/reask-predicting-extreme-weather-in-uncertain-times/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/reask-predicting-extreme-weather-in-uncertain-times/</guid></item><item><title> Compounding Optimism</title><description> &lt;p>;Let me share a little theory I have about optimism, and why progress is so easy to underestimate.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I&#39;ll explain it in four parts.&lt;/p>; &lt;hr />; &lt;p>;A crocodile in Costa Rica &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbsnews.com/news/crocodile-virgin-birth-costa-rica/&quot;>;was found pregnan&lt;/a>;t recently – and she did it all herself, with no help from a male. Her fetus is 99.99% genetically identical to her.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It&#39;s the first documented case of a crocodile reproducing asexually. A few other animals – some birds and snakes – can do it as well, but it&#39;s extremely rare.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There&#39;s a good reason why.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Almost 100 years ago, an evolutionary biologist named Herman Muller came up with a theory that eventually became known as Muller&#39;s Ratchet. It says dangerous mutations tend to pile up when there&#39;s no genetic recombination, which can ultimately lead a species to extinction. In the absence of variety – a male and female mixing genes – dangerous mutations tend to stick around, because there are no new, better, variations to compete the bad stuff out of the gene pool.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It&#39;s why so few species reproduce asexually.&lt;/p>; &lt;hr />; &lt;p>;David Senra of the wonderful &lt;em>;Founders&lt;/em>; podcast &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PI6QcwnfNe8&amp;amp;ab_channel=Acquired&quot;>;recently&lt;/a>; told a story about Steve Jobs:&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;Steve was in his 20s and he goes and meets [Polaroid founder] Edwin Land. And Steve says, “Visiting Edwin Land was like visiting a shrine … he is my hero.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And Jeff Bezos took a lot of ideas from Sam Walton. Both Steve and Jeff took a lot of ideas from Sony.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You always find these people where you&#39;re like, “Oh, I thought this was a Steve Jobs idea.” No, no. It&#39;s an [Sony founder] Akio Morita idea, or an Edwin Land idea.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Watch the presentations that Steve Jobs gives where he says, “We&#39;re building at the intersection of technology and liberal arts.” Edwin Land said those exact words!&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You&#39;re never going to find anybody who gets to the top of the profession without studying the people that came before them and learning from them and admiring them.&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;This is so true.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thomas Edison took a lot of ideas from Michael Faraday.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bill Gates took ideas from a computer inventor named Henry Edwards Roberts.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Warren Buffett learned from Ben Graham and Phil Fisher.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Edwin Land himself was massively influenced by a Harvard physics professor named George Wheelwright, who &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2001/03/03/business/gw-wheelwright-iii-97-dies-co-founder-of-polaroid.html&quot;>;became a Polaroid co-founder&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The question is: Did George Wheelwright know that he would influence Edwin Land, who would then influence Steve Jobs, who would then design a phone that 2.5 billion people would use?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Did Michael Faraday, who died in 1867, know that his ideas would directly influence the light bulb, which effectively led to the creation of everything from the modern power grid to nightlife?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Did Ben Graham know that his 1950s finance class would lead to 45,000 trekking to Omaha every year to hear his student speak?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course not. It&#39;s so hard to know what an idea, or an invention, or a philosophy, will influence, and what a person who&#39;s influenced by it will go on to create.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Visa Founder Dee Hock says, “A book is far more than what the author wrote; it is everything you can imagine and read into it as well.” An author might write something that&#39;s dull or obvious, but it could inspire a reader to go do something incredible.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ideas compound.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Inventions compound.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Education compounds.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A trivial thing can grow into a massive thing, and faster than most people realize.&lt;/p>; &lt;hr />; &lt;p>;Science writer Matt Ridley says most innovation happens when several different ideas “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ted.com/talks/matt_ridley_when_ideas_have_sex&quot;>;have sex&lt;/a>;.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most new ideas and inventions are pretty bland on their own. But when you mix several of them together, you can get magic. Plastic is great. Electronics are neat. Metal is special. But mix them together in the right way and you get an iPhone, which is pure magic.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It&#39;s ideas combining, joining, and merging, that create the modern world.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And it&#39;s the opposite process of what our crocodile friend recently pulled off.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ridley explains in his book &lt;em>;The Rational Optimist&lt;/em>; about the benefits of recombination:&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;A mutation that occurs in one creature can join forces with a mutation that occurs in another. If microbes had not begun swapping genes a few billion years ago, and animals had not continued doing so through sex, all the genes that make eyes could never have got together in one animal; nor the genes to make legs or nerves or brains. Each mutation would have remained isolated in its own lineage, unable to discover the joys of synergy.&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;Ridley once explained this further:&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;I&#39;m not interested in the debate about whether some groups have higher IQs than other groups. It&#39;s completely irrelevant. What&#39;s relevant to a society is how well people are communicating their ideas, and how well they&#39;re cooperating, not how clever the individuals are.&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;Small ideas mixing and compounding into big ones – that&#39;s what really drives the world.&lt;/p>; &lt;hr />; &lt;p>;I think part of the reason pessimism is so much easier and more common than optimism is that compound growth is not intuitive.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It&#39;s hard to imagine, say, our incomes doubling over the next few generations. That seems like such a massive leap, like we&#39;d have to boil the ocean to get it done. But doubling the average income over 30 years works out to about 2.3% growth per year. It&#39;s not crazy at all. It&#39;s actually quite achievable. What made it seem so ambitious to begin with is that compound growth is easy to underestimate.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you look at the end result of a long period of compounding, it&#39;s astounding. But all it took to get it done was little bits of incremental growth strung together for a long time.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;All progress is like that.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Technological progress is easy to underestimate because it&#39;s so counterintuitive to see how, for example, the philosophies of a guy who invented Polaroid film would go on to inspire the iPhone. Or how an 18th-century physicist would write a notebook that would set the foundations for a modern electrical system.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you view progress as being driven by the genius of individuals, of course it&#39;s hard to imagine a future where things are dramatically better, because no individual is orders of magnitudes smarter than average.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But when you view it as one person coming up with a small idea, another person copying that idea and tweaking it a little, another taking that insight and manipulating it a bit, another yet taking that product and combining it with something else – incremental, tiny bits, little ideas mixing, joining, blending, mutating, and compounding together – it&#39;s suddenly much more conceivable.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 13 Jun 2023 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/compounding-optimism/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/compounding-optimism/</guid></item><item><title> Brazil at Silicon Valley</title><description> &lt;p>;This has been a very difficult year for global tech companies and entrepreneurial ecosystems. However, Brazil at Silicon Valley managed to shed light on the opportunity for innovation in Brazil and the commitment of those building and investing in the country. Latin America continues to emerge as a vibrant landscape of innovation, and Brazil is quickly establishing itself as the epicenter.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Simon Rodriguez &lt;a href=&quot;https://technopoly.substack.com/p/is-brazil-losing-its-lead&quot;>;outlined this sentiment&lt;/a>; as “Ask anyone and Brazil is X years ahead of Spanish-speaking LatAm, where X depends on the nationality of the responder”.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbvaspark.com/contenido/en/news/land-of-unicorns-and-fintech-empire-this-is-sao-paulo-the-largest-innovation-ecosystem-in-latin-america/&quot;>;BBVA reports&lt;/a>;, “São Paulo&#39;s entrepreneurial ecosystem is valued at $108 billion. In comparison, &lt;a href=&quot;https://openinnovation.bbva.com/es/noticias/en-el-zocalo-del-emprendimiento-el-bum-emprendedor-y-fintech-de-ciudad-de-mexico/&quot;>;Mexico&lt;/a>; City&#39;s (the second-largest in Latin America) is valued at $22 billion.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moreover, São Paulo holds the 4th place in the Global Fintech ranking. In a region where “cash is king,” Brazil is leading the charge towards digital payments. Brazil&#39;s Central Bank launched the country&#39;s instant payment system PIX in 2020, which already boasts more than 130m registered users (60% of Brazil&#39;s population).&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To explore Brazil&#39;s technological progress, students from Stanford and Berkeley hold an incredible annual event called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brazilatsiliconvalley.com/&quot;>;Brazil at Silicon Valley&lt;/a>; (BSV).&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the name suggests, the aim is to bridge the gap between Brazil and Silicon Valley. This year, BSV was attended by a diverse crowd of over 600 founders, investors, technologists, and policymakers. My unofficial estimate is that at least 550 attendees undertook the long journey from Brazil — a minimum of two flights spanning at least 15 hours.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Let&#39;s just say that my portuñol came in handy.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the Agtech session: &lt;em>;How innovations in food systems can help solve the climate crisis&lt;/em>;, a BSV staff member used a voice-to-text function to generate the Chat-GPT summary minutes after the session was over. &lt;em>;Naturally&lt;/em>;, the summary was sent around via Whatsapp.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This year&#39;s BSV illuminated several key investment themes:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;● &lt;strong>;Verticalized Software&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;+ Fintech&lt;/strong>;: There are endless opportunities to create and scale local software solutions. Brazil has benefitted from supportive policies and the role of its Central Bank in implementing the digital payment system PIX. Angela Strange, a Partner at a16z, emphasized her view that every company will be a fintech company, as financial services will be a horizontal platform. She cited &lt;a href=&quot;https://fu.do/es/&quot;>;Fudo&lt;/a>;*, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uber.com/&quot;>;Uber&lt;/a>;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lyft.com/&quot;>;Lyft&lt;/a>;*, among others as noteworthy examples. We also think &lt;a href=&quot;https://kanastra.com.br/&quot;>;Kanastra&lt;/a>;* is a great example of an exciting fintech infrastructure play.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;● &lt;strong>;Agtech + Climate:&lt;/strong>; Agribusiness represents almost 30% of Brazil&#39;s GDP, 40% of the country&#39;s exports, and 20% of the labor force. Brazil is well-positioned to lead climate change initiatives, both in terms of technological innovation and adapting existing agricultural practices. Investors are looking for nature-based solutions, hardware and software plays, and sound business models that are not overly reliant on government subsidies (eg pass the &lt;a href=&quot;https://collabfund.com/blog/the-villain-test/&quot;>;Villain Test&lt;/a>;). Companies highlighted included &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.plenty.ag/&quot;>;Plenty&lt;/a>;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bcdbio.com/&quot;>;BCD Bioscience&lt;/a>;*, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.strellabiotech.com/&quot;>;Strella Biotech&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;● &lt;strong>;AI:&lt;/strong>; Two key messages resonated throughout the event: 1) we don&#39;t know what we don&#39;t know, and 2) the transformative potential of AI, which will affect almost every aspect of our lives. Alexandr Wang and Peter Norvig called for a careful rollout of AI technology and thoughtful consideration of its global impact. Optimism and enthusiasm for technology were spread by Vinod Khosla of Khosla Ventures and Julio Vasconcellos of Atlantico. They referenced &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@vkhosla/reinventing-societal-infrastructure-with-technology-f71e0d4f2355&quot;>;Reinventing Societal Infrastructure with Technology&lt;/a>;). Check out how &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mercadodiferente.com.br/&quot;>;Diferente&lt;/a>;* is &lt;a href=&quot;https://exame.com/bussola/diferente-lanca-ia-que-cria-receitas-com-itens-da-cesta-de-organicos/&quot;>;using AI &lt;/a>;for inventory management and recipe recommendations.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;● &lt;strong>;The Fundraising Market&lt;/strong>;: A clear slowdown in the market is being felt across the board, with rounds taking longer to close, valuations compressing, and regional exit liquidity shortages. However, these conditions also make it a great time to build as we&#39;ve seen teams be laser-focused on unit economics, capital efficiency, and nailing down PMF. McKinsey launched the &lt;a href=&quot;https://latamdigitalreport.mckinsey.com/&quot;>;2023 Latin American Digital Report&lt;/a>; during the event.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One thing that was not mentioned during the conference – politics.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a Venezuelan, I found it refreshing to see Brazilians come together and discuss secular trends, opportunities to innovate, and what is going right with the country&#39;s policies. After all, technological development is a rising tide that lifts all boats.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the week following BSV, Rio hosted &lt;a href=&quot;https://rio.websummit.com/&quot;>;Web Summit&lt;/a>; – a tech event that drew more than 20,000 attendees. Numerous key stakeholders have since gathered in NYC for events hosted by Itau, BTG, and Bank of America. I was lucky to attend Itau&#39;s Women Leaders in NY honoring &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ingridsilvaballet.com/&quot;>;Ingrid Silva&lt;/a>;. While an uptick in events doesn&#39;t necessarily equal a surge in innovation, it undeniably illustrates the escalating interest in Brazil as a premier global hub for tech development.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For great content about local and international tech events related to the Brazil entrepreneurial ecosystem, check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://substack.com/profile/38241540-julia-de-luca&quot;>;Julia de Luca&lt;/a>; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://abreu.substack.com/&quot;>;Lucas Abreu&lt;/a>;&#39;s newsletters.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And make plans now to join us at BSV next year, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.latitud.com/en/vamoslatamsummit&quot;>;Vamos Latam Summit&lt;/a>; in São Paulo, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brazilclimatesummit.com/&quot;>;Brazil Climate Summit&lt;/a>; in NYC.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With tons of admiration from a very Venezuelan VC.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Luisa&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;*Denotes Collab Portfolio Company&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 05 Jun 2023 16:46:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/brazil-at-silicon-valley/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/brazil-at-silicon-valley/</guid></item></channel></rss>