<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>合作基金</title><description>Collab Fund 是企业家推动世界前进的主要资金来源。</description><link/> https://collabfund.com<atom:link href="https://collabfund.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 11:14:59 -0400</pubDate><lastbuilddate> 2023 年 10 月 31 日，星期二 11:14:59 -0400</lastbuilddate><generator>站点叶</generator><item><title>我最近读过的聪明的东西</title><description>&lt;p>;“在我们知道自己错了之前，错误的感觉就像是正确的一样。” – David McRaney&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我只是一组镜子，反映了其他人对我的期望。” – 罗洛·梅&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“基本上，当你到了我这个年纪，你会真正衡量你生活中的成功与否，看你想要爱你的人中有多少人真正爱你。我认识一些很有钱的人，他们会得到见证晚宴，并会得到以他们的名字命名的医院翼楼。但事实是世界上没有人爱他们。如果你到了我这个年纪，却没人看好你，我不管你的银行存款有多大，你的生活就是一场灾难。” – 沃伦·巴菲特&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“如果你对一个主题的看法可以从你对另一个主题的看法中预测出来，那么你可能已经被一种意识形态所束缚。当你真正独立思考时，你的结论将是不可预测的。” – 凯文·凯利&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“当我写完书评时，我经常会对自己说，‘好了！现在没有人必须读这本书了。我已经为他们把它简化了。如果作者自己做这项工作，我们的情况会更好。” – 阿诺德·金&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“生活不是一个需要解决的问题。这是一个需要经历的悖论。你可以相信一件事，也可以相信它的反面。” – 德里克·西弗斯&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“道德是你在事后感觉良好，不道德是你在事后感觉糟糕。” – 欧内斯特·海明威（我认为他在理想上是错误的，但在现实上是正确的）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“获得世界上最差医疗保健的人是非常贫穷的人和非常富有的人。富人可以向医生提出任何疯狂的要求。” –（我忘了我在哪里听到的这句话。它指的是100年前的医疗保健。千真万确。）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“邪恶通常在打开门并让它进来的人没有意识到的情况下进入世界。大多数作恶的人并不认为自己所做的事是恶事。邪恶主要存在于旁观者的眼中，尤其是在受害者的眼中。” – Roy Baumeister&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“人们怀念的不是过去的样子，而是过去本来可以的样子。”斯维特兰娜·博伊姆&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“乍看之下，怀旧是对一个地方的向往，但实际上它是对另一个时间的向往——我们的童年时光，我们梦想的缓慢节奏。” – Svetlana Boym&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“怀旧是没有罪恶感的历史。” – Svetlana Boym&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;纳西姆·塔勒布 (Nassim Taleb) 曾经写道，出版商总是试图推动作者撰写针对最近新闻事件的特定主题。 “不，不;恰恰相反，”他写道。 “如果你想在未来被阅读，请确保你在过去也被阅读过。我们不知道未来会发生什么，但我们对过去有一些了解……我推测二十年前相关的书籍（当然前提是今天相关）二十年后会很有趣”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我努力不嘲笑人类的行为，不为它们哭泣，不恨它们，而是理解它们。” – 巴鲁克·斯宾诺莎&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们存在的一个奇怪特征是，我们来自一个非常擅长促进生命但更擅长消灭生命的星球。” – Bill Bryson 论进化&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“在生活中，只要有可能，就优化独立性而不是付费。如果你有独立性，并且你对你的输出负责，而不是你的输入——那就是梦想。” – Naval&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“被恶魔驱使的人会做事很糟糕。” – 沃尔特·艾萨克森 (Walter Isaacson) 描述埃隆·马斯克&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“创造力的最高形式是在一系列限制条件下即兴创作。” ——克里斯托弗·诺兰&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“一位父亲希望能像他的孩子们一样非凡，在他们的天真中想象他的样子，这样他们就永远不会对他失望。也许有些父亲做到了这一点。” – 大卫·冯·德雷勒&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;查理·芒格职业成功公式：&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li>; &lt;p>;不要出售任何你自己不会买的东西。&lt;/p>; &lt;/ li>; &lt;li>; &lt;p>;不要为任何你不尊重和钦佩的人工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;/li>; &lt;li>; &lt;p>;只与你喜欢的人一起工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;/li >; &lt;/ul>; &lt;p>;关于怀旧的俄罗斯谚语：“过去比未来变得更加不可预测。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“能力是当你能有所收获时你有多优秀。品格就是当你一无所获时你有多优秀。人们会因为你的能力而奖励你。但人们只会因为你的性格而爱你。” – 马克·曼森&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我写下了太多的历史，以至于无法相信它。” – 亨利·亚当斯&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“花了很长时间才取得成功。我想说，回想起来，我很高兴花了这么长时间，因为这很有趣。” – 芒格&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;哈维·费尔斯通：&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;为什么一个人一拿到足够的钱，就建造一座比他需要的大得多的房子？&lt;/p>; >; &lt;p>;我在阿克伦有一所房子，比我最少用的房子大很多倍；我在迈阿密海滩还有另一所房子，它也比我需要的大得多。我想在我死之前我会购买或建造其他的房子，这些房子也会比我需要的大。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我不知道我为什么这样做——房子只是一种负担。但我做到了，有钱的朋友都有大房子。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;也许这是古代封建思想的一些愚蠢的残余，大房子意味着坚固的房子，可以在里面保留一支小军队。保护。在少数情况下，建造一栋大房子只是为了炫耀自己有钱；有时会建造一座大房子，以便进行精彩的娱乐活动。但在大多数情况下，尤其是对于那些自己挣钱的人来说，房子才刚刚建成，建成后，没有人完全知道为什么要开始建造它。无数人把他们的房子建得那么大，以至于他们还不如住在酒店里。&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;“本·格雷厄姆曾经谈论第一类和第二类真理。第一类真理是绝对的。第二类真理因信念而成为真理。如果有足够多的人认为一家公司的股票价值 X，那么它就会变得价值 X，直到有足够多的人不这么认为。” – 巴菲特&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“幸福不是你经历的，而是你经历的。”这是你记得的事情。” – 奥斯卡·黎凡特&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 17:20:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/smart-things-ive-read-lately/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/smart-things-ive-read-lately/</guid></item><item><title>人工智能让地球更凉爽：Phaidra 对抗数据中心排放的使命</title><description>&lt;p>;随着计算需求呈指数级增长，像 Phaidra 这样的人工智能对于遏制排放是必要的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;任何曾经遭受过这种情况的人&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/ pmc/articles/PMC4292129/&quot;>;笔记本电脑燃烧&lt;/a>;可以理解计算能力会产生热量。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;就像您的笔记本电脑一样，数据中心 - 其中包含为&lt;a href=&quot;https: //about.netflix.com/en/news/what-the-latest-research-on-streaming-emissions-tells-us&quot;>;Netflix&lt;/a>; 至 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nasa. gov/centers-and-facilities/nssc/nccips/&quot;>;NASA&lt;/a>; - 也会产生热量，必须缓解这些热量才能保持这些服务器的正常运行。因此，冷却是数据中心环境中最大的能源使用来源之一。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3 id=&quot;the-data-center-energy-crisis&quot;>;数据中心能源危机&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;事实上，到 2021 年，世界各地的数据中心消耗的能源&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.voyagervc.com/news-and-letters/decarbonizing-data&quot;>;与英国大致相同&lt;/ a>; – 大约相当于&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iea.org/energy-system/buildings/data-centres-and-data-transmission-networks&quot;>;全球用电量的1-2%&lt;/ a>;。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;考虑到即将到来的计算海啸：人工智能，能源消耗预计只会加速。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种繁荣将被设定为&lt;a href=&quot;https: //www.mckinsey.com/industries/technology-media-and-te communications/our-insights/investing-in-the-rising-data-center-economy&quot;>;两倍或三倍&lt;/a>;数据中心。就上下文而言，这&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_countries_by_electricity_conspiration&quot;>;意味着&lt;/a>;数据中心将比世界上除美国以外的任何国家承担更多的电力需求美国和中国。&lt;/p>; &lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/energyforecast.r1.png&quot; alt=&quot;数据中心能源使用趋势和效率图表策略”/>;来源：&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.akcp.com/blog/the-real-amount-of-energy-a-data-center-use/&quot;>;AKCP&lt;/a>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;数据中心和分布式计算系统已经消耗了世界总发电量的很大一部分。如果没有技术创新，这种能源需求和相关的温室气体排放可能会大幅增加。数据中心处于独特的能源困境中，它既是积极变革的催化剂，也是排放恶化的潜在因素。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;幸运的是，人工智能有能力治愈这一潜在能源危机，也有能力解决这一潜在能源危机的根源。通过提高数据中心的性能来抵消数据中心不断增长的能源需求。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这就是我们最近主导投资 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.phaidra.ai/&quot;>; 的原因Phaidra&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3 id=&quot;phaidras-ai-solution&quot;>;Phaidra 的人工智能解决方案&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Phaidra – 由 AlphaGo 的先驱之一、Katie 的 Veda Pannershevlvam（CTO）创立霍夫曼（总裁兼首席运营官）领导了特灵与 Deepmind 的合作，高吉姆（首席执行官）在 Deepmind 构建了框架，通过 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.deepmind 减少了谷歌数据中心的能源使用.com/blog/deepmind-ai-reduces-google-data-centre-cooling-bill-by-40&quot;>;近 40%&lt;/a>; – 正在利用人工智能来优化数据中心和其他关键任务设施的效率.&lt;/p>; &lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/deepmind.r1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Google PUE 逐年下降图表。&quot; />; 来源：&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.deepmind.com/blog/deepmind-ai-reduces-google-data-centre-cooling-bill-by-40&quot;>;Deepmind&lt;/a>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;Phaidra 不仅仅是为人类提供实施建议，他们还使用&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TmPfTpjtdgg&quot;>;强化学习&lt;/a>; - 唯一的机器学习的一个分支，它产生行动，而不仅仅是预测 - 直接控制数据中心冷却和其他功能，同时确保最严格的保障措施得到维护。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Phaidra 与首批财富 100 强试点客户的结果令人震惊。实施一年内，他们能够节省 10-15% 的能源。就背景而言，一家公司估计，能源减少 10% 相当于每个设施每年节省 2-300 万美元的能源。客户不需要任何可持续发展激励措施就能发现 Phaidra 的产品引人注目——经济效益已经足够了（Collab 的 &lt;a href=&quot;https://collabfund.com/blog/the-villain-test/&quot;>;Villain 的一个典型例子工作中进行测试&lt;/a>;）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是一项巨大的技术突破。世界上没有其他公司能够自主控制大型工业设施。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3 id=&quot;how-it-works&quot;>;工作原理&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Phaidra 通过插入设施的现有系统（无需新硬件），通常通过建筑管理系统 (BMS) 或监控和数据采集 (SCADA) 系统。这会将来自传感器的数千个数据点直接输入 Phaidra 的人工智能代理，使 Alfred（团队亲切地称呼它）能够识别并实施（实时）最大化设施性能的行动，包括能源消耗、二氧化碳排放、稳定性、机器性能等。运行时间和许多其他变量。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/Screenshot%202023-10-23%20at%204.59.31%E2%80%AFPM。 png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot 2023-10-23 at 4.59.31 PM.png&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这与当今工业自动化的工作方式截然不同。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;工业设施，例如数据中心依赖于不适应不断变化的条件的硬编码规则（由数千行 IF/THEN 语句组成）。这些明确编程的控制系统迫使物理工厂永久以相同的方式运行（或者直到有人硬编码新规则）——这是一个导致设施退化的次优过程。相比之下，Phaidra 的强化学习系统会随着时间的推移不断学习并变得更好，从而不断提高性能并加快 Phaidra 客户的投资回报率。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3 id=&quot;moving-beyond-data-centers&quot;>;超越数据中心&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;虽然优化数据中心的机会足够大（无论是在经济回报还是潜在的气候影响方面），但 Phaidra 有潜力超越数据中心环境。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;他们的算法是一个通用框架，可以应用于从提高发电厂转换效率到帮助制造设施提高吞吐量的任何事情。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大型工业系统可以实现更多的效率提升。随着计算需求呈指数级增长，像 Phaidra 这样的人工智能对于遏制排放是必要的。 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.phaidra.ai/&quot;>;Phaidra&lt;/a>; 优雅地部署人工智能来优化自身，说明了技术对气候的双重承诺和危险。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 07:55:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/ai-for-a-cooler-earth/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/ai-for-a-cooler-earth/</guid></item><item><title>团队建设</title><description>&lt;p>;胜利是由团队完成的，我现在对协作基金的团队感到非常兴奋。两周前我们在纽约聚会。这是一场混乱。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们迎来了几位跨核心职能部门的新员工，包括投资、运营和我们的平台团队。看到 Collaborative 中的人才团结在一起真是太酷了。这体现了我们所有人都应该兴奋的使命的共鸣，也体现了我为之自豪的支持后起之秀的记录。最重要的是，这些新团队成员带来的广泛经验和观点将使我们能够更好地为我们的创始人和投资者提供未来服务。介绍完毕后，我们深入讨论了基金业绩、如何更好地支持我们不断增长的投资组合以及新兴的兴趣领域。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/a1. png&quot; alt=&quot;a1.png&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们会议的一些亮点包括：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;- 新兴的拉丁美洲创业生态系统&lt;/strong>; - 我们就我们如何最好地帮助这个快速增长地区的创始人进行了富有洞察力的讨论。我们很高兴能够继续发展与当地合作伙伴的关系，获得文化熟练程度，并为创始人提供长期支持。就背景而言，在过去 18 个月中，我们投资了该地区的许多初创公司，包括：&lt;strong>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mercadodiferente.com.br/&quot;>;Diferente&lt;/a >;&lt;/strong>;、&lt;strong>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://kanastra.com.br/en/&quot;>;喀纳斯特拉&lt;/a>;&lt;/strong>;、&lt;strong>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// ruuf.cl/&quot;>;Ruuf Solar&lt;/a>;&lt;/strong>;、&lt;strong>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.soyplenna.com/&quot;>;Plenna&lt;/a>;&lt;/strong>; 和 &lt;strong>; >;&lt;a href=&quot;https://fu.do/es/&quot;>;Fu.do&lt;/a>;&lt;/strong>;。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/ uploads/b1.png&quot; alt=&quot;b1.png&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;- 地热能令人兴奋的潜力&lt;/strong>; - 我们探索了地热技术如何能够实现永远在线、清洁的能源基荷发电。然而，我们也认识到，要实现地热的全部前景，需要有效的政策倡导和愿意支持长期投资的耐心资金。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;- GLP-1 药物如何改变行为&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;- GLP-1 药物如何改变行为&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;- GLP-1 药物如何改变行为我们对未来进行了一次发人深省的讨论，未来这些类型的药物不仅可以治疗糖尿病，还可能更广泛地影响饮食和生活方式的选择。精准医疗的未来能力看起来既极其复杂，又充满希望。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在我们的战略会议结束后，我们参观了&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.royalpalmsbrooklyn.com/&quot;>;皇家棕榈沙狐球俱乐部&lt; /a>; - 一个很棒的地方（带来&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/948151585/bring-shuffleboard-back-to-brooklyn-on-its-100th-a&quot;>;生活&lt; /a>; 部分由 Collab Fund 投资组合公司 Kickstarter 提供），并享受了一些不错的老游戏和美味的食物。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/c1.png&quot; alt=&quot;c1.png&quot; />;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;这次聚会使我们的目标更加明确，并对我们所有杰出的同事表示赞赏。在一个似乎每天都在加速变化的世界中，像这样定期聚集在一起制定战略并调整引人注目的机会对于我们继续推动风险投资走向未来绝对至关重要。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;前进！&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 08:59:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/teambuilding/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/teambuilding/</guid></item><item><title>致富的几条法则</title><description>&lt;p>;全球10位最富有的人中有13人离婚。前十名中的七人至少离婚过一次。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;相关性不是因果关系，而且样本量很小。但是，在一个生活被很多人羡慕的群体中，在一个对幸福如此重要的话题上，一个比全国平均水平差得多的统计数据很有趣，不是吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有一个致富的方式有数百万种，其中大多数涉及利用特定的利基市场和一次性机会，更不用说运气了。关于如何致富的普遍规则很难找到。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是赔钱，或者在有钱的时候失去幸福，或者成为金钱的奴隶——这些故事往往有共同点。它们非常常见，您可以将其称为法律。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;衡量财富很容易。你只要数一下就可以了。衡量财富的一些负面影响要困难得多，也更加微妙。它们是如此微妙且难以衡量，以至于许多人甚至不相信它们的存在。财富的&lt;em>;缺点&lt;/em>;？这怎么可能？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;让我提出，谈论财富的负面影响是荒谬的，这也是为什么财富并不能让人们像他们想象的那样幸福的部分原因。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当金钱的好处如此明显，但缺点又如此微妙时，你没有预料到的缺点可能比你预期的好处更令人震惊。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，我想要更多的钱。几乎每个人都这样做，尽管出于不同的原因。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这不是一份反财富清单——只是一系列容易被忽视的微妙缺点，而且如此常见，你不妨称它们为唯一真正的法则致富。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;1.生活中大部分让你快乐的事情与金钱无关，意识到一旦你有钱可能是一个痛苦的承认。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;威尔·史密斯在他的传记中写道，当他很穷的时候&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一旦他变得富有，这种乐观情绪就消失了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他有”郁闷直到你的梦想成真。一旦你的梦想成真，你意识到你的感觉和以前一样，你就会感到绝望。&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;幸福很复杂，但如果你把它简化成一个充满爱的家庭这样的事情、健康、友谊、八小时睡眠、平衡的孩子，以及成为比你自己更大的事情的一部分，你就会意识到金钱的作用是多么有限。并不是说它没有作用；而是它没有作用。只是比你想象的要小。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这样想：你愿意每年赚 10 万美元，有一个爱你的配偶、钦佩你的孩子、好朋友、身体健康、问心无愧吗？ ，或者赚了 1,000,000 美元却什么都没有？这是很明显的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，你可以贫穷而痛苦，也可以富有而快乐。但只有富人知道这种关系有多么脆弱。赚钱可能并不能改善你的婚姻，它不能让你的朋友更喜欢你，也不能让你更满足。因此，曾经对金钱可以为你做的令人安慰的乐观情绪，现在被金钱不能为你做的严酷现实所取代。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有时，梦想是感觉良好的，一旦你实现了它，梦想消失了，你实际上变得沮丧。 Malcolm Forbes：当我们成功时，我们已经拥有了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;2.你所认为的对自己成功的钦佩实际上可能是嫉妒。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;说唱歌手德雷克曾经说过，“人们更喜欢你在为某件事而努力的时候，而不是当你拥有它的时候。”&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;很难判断这种转变何时发生，富人通常认为自己受到钦佩，但实际上却受到嫉妒。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作者罗伯特·格林 (Robert Greene) 曾经写道： &lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;永远不要愚蠢地相信你通过炫耀使你超越他人的品质来激起钦佩。通过让别人意识到自己的劣势，你只会激起不愉快的钦佩或嫉妒，这会侵蚀他们，直到他们以你无法预见的方式削弱你。&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;这尤其重要当你致富的原因是通过某种形式宣传你的成功，让其他人愿意帮助和支持你时，情况确实如此。当钦佩变成嫉妒时，支持就会减少，人们对你的错误的容忍度就会减少。如果一位无名记者写了一本书间接地为萨姆·班克曼-弗里德辩护，没有人会在意——他们实际上可能会祝贺作者。但自从迈克尔·刘易斯做到了，干草叉就出现了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;梭罗说，“嫉妒是所有区别都必须缴纳的税。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;3。你越富有，当你犯错、疯狂、刻薄或健忘时，周围的人就越不可能告诉你。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;马特·达蒙 (Matt Damon) 说，“你在社交和情感上阻碍了别人的发展。”你成名的那一刻。你对世界的体验永远不会一样。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于那些变得富有的人来说，同样的情况可能也是如此，而且更为普遍。没有人会以同样的方式对待你。最糟糕的是你可能根本不知道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;艺术家达米安·赫斯特 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.idler.co.uk/article/interview-damien-hirst/&quot;>;曾经说过&lt;/a>;：&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;他们都爱你。银行爱你，会计师也爱你，因为他们拿走了你的钱。每年你都会有越来越多的人。一个人拿走 10%，然后另一个人拿走 10%，另一个人拿走 10%，这就是一场盛大的聚会。给你透支的人也是你最好的朋友，他们对你微笑，告诉你你很了不起，所以你就继续这样做。&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;有时人们是故意利用你的，从你身上榨取一些好处。其他时候，他们不应该认真对待你。泡沫的一个大问题是财富和智慧之间的反射性关联，所以一堆疯狂的想法因为一个暂时富有的人说出来而被认真对待。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;巴菲特曾经解释过：&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;当我二十一岁时，我最擅长提供财务建议，但人们不听我的。我本可以站起来说出最精彩的话，但不会受到太多关注。现在可以说出世界上最愚蠢的事情，相当多的人会认为其中有一些伟大的隐藏意义或其他东西。&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;4。有时让你成功的是担忧和焦虑，当你富有时你就无法摆脱它。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我认为很多人真正想要从金钱中得到的是能够停止的能力想着钱。有了足够的钱，他们就可以不再思考这个问题，而专注于其他事情。这是一种奇怪的关系：他们沉迷于赚钱，希望有一天他们可以完全忽视它。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种痴迷是由压力和焦虑助长的。它通常表现为职业抱负、积极投资和 A 型动机。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然后，一旦他们变得富有，他们就会意识到自己无法摆脱这种压力。这已经在他们的身份中根深蒂固。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他们每周工作 80 小时，因为他们希望最终根本不需要工作。但是，一旦他们有足够的钱退休，他们就无法削减开支，因为他们不知道除了工作之外还能做生活中的其他事情。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我采访过的很多理财规划师都说：他们最大的挑战之一是让客户在退休后花钱。即使是适当的、保守的金额。节俭和储蓄成为某些人身份的重要组成部分，以至于他们永远无法改变态度。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我认为对某些人来说这实际上很好。看着金钱复合给他们带来的快乐比花钱时更多。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但那些最终目标是停止思考金钱的人却陷入了困境。拒绝承认自己已经实现了目标可能与从一开始就没有实现目标一样糟糕。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;5.管理财富和孩子没有简单的方法。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;查理·芒格的一位富有的朋友曾经问查理·芒格，给他的孩子留下一大笔钱是否会毁掉他们的动力和抱负。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; p>; &lt;p>;“当然会的，”查理说。 “但你还是必须这么做。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“为什么？”朋友问。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“因为如果你不给他们钱，他们就会恨你，”查理说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;就像芒格的很多建议一样，我认为这种互动旨在令人难忘。这可能有 80% 是正确的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但总的来说，他是对的。对于富人来说，这是两个选择：通过继承来毁掉他们的野心，或者冒着某种形式的冲突的风险，剥夺他们的安逸生活。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沃伦·巴菲特曾经说过，他经常听到富人谈论财富是多么危险。福利社会正在造就一代依赖食品券和失业救济金的食客。但他说，“这些人给他们的孩子留下了终生可用的食品券等等”。 “他们没有福利官员，而是信托基金官员。他们没有食品券，而是支付股息的股票和债券。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然也有例外。但大多数例外——继承金钱的富家子弟并不会影响他们的野心——是因为孩子很特别，而不是因为父母一定做出了明智的决定。即使18岁的比尔盖茨继承了10亿美元，也不会阻止他的野心。史蒂夫·乔布斯和埃隆·马斯克也是如此。马克·扎克伯格 (Mark Zuckerberg) 22 岁时有人向他提供 10 亿美元现金收购 Facebook，但他没有眨眼，甚至没有考虑过。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但这些都是稀有鸟。大多数人都需要害怕无法成功。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我的朋友 Chris Davis &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3GTpG8ePCaw&amp;amp;ab_channel=TheCompound&quot;>;在一个富裕的家庭长大&lt;/a>; - 他的祖父是传奇投资家谢尔比·戴维斯 (Shelby Davis)，他将 5 万美元变成了近 10 亿美元 - 在他年轻的时候，他被告知他不会看到其中的一分钱，因为他的家人没有想要剥夺他独立自主的机会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;克里斯开玩笑说：“他们本来可以剥夺我&lt;em>;一点点&lt;/em>;。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是从来都不容易。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;6。快速的财富是脆弱的财富。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我喜欢这样的想法：你创造财富的速度就是你失去财富的速度的半衰期。一年内你的钱翻倍？当您以同样的速度失去一半时，请不要感到惊讶。闪电式扩张？闪电战失败了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;快速而脆弱的财富会发生两件事。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一是来得容易的钱往往也容易花掉。当钱来得快的时候，把钱花在无意义的事情上的情感成本就很低。只有当某件事对你来说很珍贵时，你才会小心翼翼。花掉你没有投入太多时间或精力来赚钱的快钱感觉就像是一夜情：冲动且容易后悔。老钱想要避税，新钱想要一辆兰博基尼。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一个是，财富创造得越​​快，运气带来的机会也就越快恢复。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;将这两者放在一起，每当你看到快速财富激增时（2021 年的加密货币就是一个很好的例子），你就知道它的结局将会很糟糕，因为运气会转化为风险，炫耀性消费会转化为不起眼的生活方式债务。&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;7.声誉具有双向动力，因为人们希望与成功者交往，避免失败者。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;你越成功，就越多的人愿意与你交往 - 这很好。&lt;/p>; >; &lt;p>;但这反过来也同样有效。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;职业生涯早期的人可能会搞砸，但很快就会恢复过来，进入下一家公司。一个成功的个人或公司的每一个缺陷都会在新闻中大肆宣扬，充斥着他们网络的八卦频道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;雷曼兄弟 2008 年的困境成为全国新闻头条；一家小型社区银行可能已经陷入了束手无策的境地，几乎没有任何灵魂的意识。 、商贩——想与它联系在一起。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这就像俗话说的，“猴子爬得越高，你就越能看到它的屁股。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong >;8.预期的上升速度可能快于收入的上升速度，因此较高的收入会使预期失控。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;财富是相对的。奢华是相对的。两者都只是你所拥有的和其他人所拥有的之间的比较。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我多次看到的一个怪癖是，一些最富有的人最容易出现失控的期望，因为他们变得非常了解其他富人的生活方式。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1907 年，作家威廉·道森 (William Dawson) 写到了财富感与你习惯的生活之间的关系：&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;A一个习惯于安逸生活的受过教育的人，如果被迫住在人口稠密、肮脏的公寓的一间单间里，并不得不靠微薄而又不稳定的工资维持生计，他将遭受难以言表的折磨。他会因为那些快乐的事情的记忆而受到折磨，我们被告知这是“悲伤之冠”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是，一个不知道其他生活状况的人不会意识到它的痛苦。他没有比较的标准。一个会让一个有教养的人产生自杀念头的环境，不会让他产生太多的不满。因此，穷人的幸福感比我们想象的要多得多。&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;为了阐明他的观点：道森本人相当成功，按照他那个时代的标准，他习惯于简单的手段。 But Dawson, who died in 1928, spent most of his life without electricity or air conditioning. He never had antibiotics, Advil, or a Polio vaccine. He never experienced reasonably accurate weather forecasts, or an interstate highway.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An average American today sent back in time to experience Dawson&#39;s life would suffer the same “tortures unspeakable” he wrote about. But he didn&#39;t have modern times to compare his life to, so it felt luxurious to him.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Everything good in life is just &lt;a href=&quot;https://collabfund.com/blog/expectations-and-reality/&quot;>;the gap between expectations and reality&lt;/a>;, and when your main frame of reference are other rich people trying to impress each other, that gap can close quickly.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;9. No one is going to remember you in 100 years.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So you might as well focus on what&#39;s going to make you happy now, instead of what money might buy you in the future.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a Scottish proverb: Be happy while you are living, for you are a long time dead.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 11:38:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/a-few-laws-of-getting-rich/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/a-few-laws-of-getting-rich/</guid></item><item><title> The Thin Line Between Bold and Reckless</title><description> &lt;p>;Cornelius Vanderbilt had just finished a series of business deals to expand his railroad empire.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One of his business advisors leaned in to tell Vanderbilt that every transaction he agreed to broke the law.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“My God, John,” &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2DymfK7&quot;>;said&lt;/a>; Vanderbilt, “You don&#39;t suppose you can run a railroad in accordance with the statutes of the State of New York, do you?”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My first thought when reading this was: “That attitude is why he was so successful.” Laws didn&#39;t accommodate railroads during Vanderbilt&#39;s day. So he said “to hell with it” and went ahead anyway. Vanderbilt was wildly successful, so it&#39;s tempting to view his law-flouting – which was notorious and vital to his success – as sage wisdom. That scrappy visionary let nothing get in his way!&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But how dangerous is that analysis? No sane person would recommend flagrant crime as an entrepreneurial trait. You can easily imagine Vanderbilt&#39;s story turning out much different – an outlaw whose young company collapsed under court order.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So we have a problem here.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;People could praise Vanderbilt for flouting the law with as much passion as they criticize Enron for doing the same. John D. Rockefeller is similar: His frequent circumventing of the law – a judge once called his company “no better than a common thief” – is often portrayed by historians as cunning business smarts. Maybe it was. But when does the narrative shift from, “You didn&#39;t let outdated laws get in the way of innovation,” to “You committed a crime?”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It&#39;s hard to know. I think we only judge the process by its outcome. Which is dangerous.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The hardest thing about studying businesses and investors is that many traits that fueled their success could have just as easily triggered failure. But we rarely think about it that way when learning from specific outcomes.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Those eager to learn from others tend to look at the tails. What did the big winners do right? What did the big losers do wrong? It&#39;s often hard to find an actionable takeaway from either because winners and losers often pursued similar risky strategies, with outcomes tilted ever so slightly by chance. My point is that big success requires bucking conventional wisdom, but conventional wisdom is usually right and worth following. We&#39;re left with outcomes where winners are praised more than they should be, losers criticized more than they deserve.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There&#39;s more to this than breaking laws.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The majority of Benjamin Graham&#39;s investing success &lt;a href=&quot;http://jasonzweig.com/was-benjamin-graham-skillful-or-lucky/&quot;>;is due to&lt;/a>; owning shares of Geico. Both his initial purchase, and subsequently holding the stock at high valuations, broke nearly every rule that Graham himself laid out in his famous texts. What are we supposed to learn from that?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We think Mark Zuckerberg is a genius for turning down a big offer to sell his company. But people criticize Groupon and Yahoo! with as much passion for turning down their big buyout offers. What is the lesson for entrepreneurs here?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Uber took no prisoners as it disrupted the entrenched taxi market. But the line between rooting for a scrappy startup and “#DeleteUber” turned out to be a hair thin. Which case study will be taught in business schools?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Countless fortunes (and failures) owe their outcome to leverage.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The best (and worst) managers drive their employees as hard as they can.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The customer is always right” and “customers don&#39;t know what they want” are both accepted business wisdom.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The line between “inspiringly bold” and “foolishly reckless” can be a millimeter thick and only visible with hindsight. But it&#39;s easy to view the process that led to successful outcomes as something to emulate, and the process that led to failures as something to avoid.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I don&#39;t think there&#39;s much we can do about this. It&#39;s one of those things that just &lt;em>;is&lt;/em>;. Risk is unfair and unforgiving.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But a few things are worth thinking about.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Focus less on case studies and more on broad patterns&lt;/strong>;. Case studies can be dangerous because we study extreme examples, and extreme examples are often the least applicable to other situations, given their complexity. You&#39;ll get closer to something actionable by looking for broad patterns of things like how people respond to surprises, how fragile competitive advantages can be, how quickly people/businesses/economies evolve, and what makes people happy. This is also why &lt;a href=&quot;https://microcapclub.com/2018/01/morgan-housel-industries-teach-us-investing/&quot;>;multidisciplinary learning is so important&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Accept that strategies expire&lt;/strong>;. The irony of history is that it&#39;s mostly the study of things changing, often used as a guide for what to do next. The only thing more dangerous than underestimating how risky someone else&#39;s strategy was is not realizing that the entire strategy only worked in a different era. When you accept that things change over time you become less interested in specific strategies used in the past and more interested in broad topics, like how people discovered the strategies to begin with.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;There&#39;s more to learn from people who endured risk than those who seemingly conquered it&lt;/strong>;. If success requires taking risk that could easily turn into failure, and the line between the two is nearly invisible in real time, I want to learn from people who accidentally stepped over the line and lived to tell the tale. Companies that survived deep recessions. Investors who survived bear markets. Products that flopped, were redesigned, and then worked. In any risky endeavor, the line between success and failure is thin enough that hardly anyone can find it but never walk over it. So you&#39;ll gain more by learning how to put up with and survive the occasional misstep than attempting to avoid them entirely. This is why &lt;a href=&quot;https://collabfund.com/blog/the-theory-of-maybes/&quot;>;room for error and humility&lt;/a>; are so important.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“What do I care about the law?” Vanderbilt once said. “Ain&#39;t I got the power?”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He did, and it worked. But it&#39;s easy to imagine those being the last words of a story with a very different outcome.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 09:07:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/the-thin-line-between-bold-and-reckless/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/the-thin-line-between-bold-and-reckless/</guid></item><item><title> Recharge, Recycle, Repeat: The Sustainable Secret of the Battery World</title><description> &lt;p>;Something amazing has been happening in the battery world: battery recycling rates have been steadily rising thanks to smart industry initiatives and consumer awareness.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Take the lead-acid batteries that power our cars for starters. The industry reports a 99% recycling rate for these batteries in the US - 2x the recycling rate of aluminum cans. According to Recycling Today, that makes lead car batteries the single &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.recyclingtoday.com/news/bci-study-claims-lead-batteries-most-recycled-consumer-product-in-united-states/&quot;>;most recycled consumer product&lt;/a>;. That&#39;s right - about 160 million lead batteries are collected and recycled each year, keeping more than 2.5 million tons of lead and plastic from clogging up landfills.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/Fig1_RecycledProducts.r2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Chart of top recycled products in the United States, with lead-acid batteries at the top at 99%&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It wasn&#39;t always this way. Just a few decades ago, barely half of lead batteries were being recycled. But through coordinated efforts between battery makers, recyclers, and governments, the infrastructure and incentives emerged to make lead battery recycling not just viable, but the norm. It took patience. It took investment. But the industry transformed battery recycling from an afterthought into a shining example of the circular economy.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As we look forward to a future with more and more lithium-ion batteries (LiB) powering everything from our phones to the latest electric vehicles, the lead battery&#39;s success story gives reason for optimism even while current LiB recycling rates languish around 5-15%.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As electric vehicle adoption grows in the coming decades, LiB waste is expected to exceed 20 million tons per year by 2040. This seems daunting, but it also represents a huge opportunity if we can ramp up recycling efforts. Many look at the tidal wave of spent batteries and simply see a wall of waste. But the scrapheap of today is the goldmine of tomorrow if we have the patience and ingenuity to extract it.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/Fig2_BatteryRecycling.r2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Chart of the global supply of EV batteries for recycling in kilotons&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recycling any complex product is hard. It takes time to figure out the logistics and economics. Challenges abound, especially when it comes to collecting and transporting used batteries. But we have a template, and the incentives are there to invest in solving the problems. The value to recover in these batteries is immense. But we&#39;ve done it before, and businesses are already working to scale up LiB recycling. This is one of the reasons we&#39;re excited about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.redwoodmaterials.com/news/redwood-series-d/&quot;>;our investment&lt;/a>; in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.redwoodmaterials.com/&quot;>;Redwood Materials&lt;/a>; and infrastructure they have today to recycle EV and other types of batteries, extracting and re-entering valuable materials back into the battery supply chain. This Series D raise of more than $1B was on the heels of Redwood Materials &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rgj.com/story/news/money/business/2023/02/09/redwood-materials-gets-2-billion-doe-loan-for-mega-battery-facility-near-reno/69886953007/&quot;>;$2B loan from the DOE&lt;/a>;, giving the company ample capital to continue investing in scaling up capacity.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/RedwoodMaterialsFacility.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Aerial view of a Redwood Materials recycling facility.&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This won&#39;t happen overnight. We need to build the infrastructure and scale up processes. Automakers, battery producers, and recyclers will need to collaborate across a complex value chain. Persistence and problem-solving are required.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at the humble lead battery for inspiration may seem archaic. And you might not guess it from looking, but the iconic lead battery is a marvel of recyclability by design. Its three main components - lead, plastic, acid - are engineered to be recycled over and over in closed-loop perfection.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is recycling not as an afterthought, but as the core principle. Lead batteries aren&#39;t discarded, they&#39;re reborn. &lt;strong>;The typical new lead battery is formed from 80% recycled material. No loss of performance, just the cycle continuing. Remarkably, 83% of the lead these batteries need is sourced right here in North America, not from distant mines.&lt;/strong>; The plastic casings also find new life. All of it circulating in near-perfect loops.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Over decades, lead batteries have woven a network of manufacturing, collection sites, and recyclers across the country, with &lt;strong>;over 300,000 locations&lt;/strong>; accepting used batteries. It&#39;s an ecosystem designed to keep lead circulating. This didn&#39;t happen overnight. Industry groups brought stakeholders together to slowly build smart systems and instill responsible battery management. No hype, just persistence.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The benefits of recycling go beyond reducing waste. &lt;strong>;Recycled lead requires 70% less energy to produce than mining and smelting new lead ore. Less energy means less carbon emissions.&lt;/strong>; Recycling completes the loop. Lead batteries have shown a path forward and, according to research by McKinsey &amp;amp; Company, there&#39;s hope that LiB can follow a similar path.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Replicating the lead recycling pipeline for LIBs will not be straightforward. Unfortunately, the process of recycling an LIB is inherently trickier than it is for a lead battery. Lead is the only metal in a lead acid battery, and it can be separated from the rest of the battery materials with a simple process that yields high purity ingots. Compare this to an LIB, where the valuable metals are numerous and varied and exist in chemical mixtures that generally require more sophisticated separation methods.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lead car batteries are a recycling success story, but the even more ubiquitous single-use alkaline batteries that power our flashlights and TV remotes have followed a less inspiring path. Recycling rates for these batteries remain quite low, buoyed only by regulations that incentivize otherwise-noneconomic practices (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1878535223006020&quot;>;source&lt;/a>;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/sustainable-business/2016/apr/14/drawer-full-of-them-battery-recycling-waste-eu&quot;>;source&lt;/a>;). A key problem lies in the fact that the metals that make up an alkaline battery – mainly iron, zinc, and manganese – are so darn cheap.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Luckily for LIBs, the lithium, nickel, and cobalt that make up the bulk of material costs are quite valuable. This, combined with the massive and growing LIB market, gives us hope that LIB recycling can become profitable at scale.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Driven by this prize and the goal of increasing EV sustainability, startups like Redwood Materials, are addressing the technological challenges of separation. Processes like theirs are able to recover up to 95% of battery materials for reuse at falling costs. That&#39;s valuable metal pulled back from the brink to offset the need for costly new mining.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/Fig3_CarbonFootprint.r2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Chart showing recycled batteries using recycled materials released 28% less emissions&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It will take some time before recycled LIB materials will be able to steal significant market share from mined minerals. The problem is that EV adoption is simply growing too fast for new battery demand to be matched by a supply of old batteries – From 2021 to 2022, the share of new car purchases that were EVs increased from 8.7% to 14% globally and from 4.5% to 7.7% in the US (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iea.org/data-and-statistics/data-tools/global-ev-data-explorer&quot;>;source&lt;/a>;). As far as problems go, this is a good one to have, and it should certainly not discourage activity in the LIB recycling space. Estimates are that recycling will be able to satisfy about 7% of lithium and 11% of cobalt and nickel demand in 2030 (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0921344922003317&quot;>;source&lt;/a>;), and about double that a decade later.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most exciting thing is that we are just now nearing a critical mass where the volume of LIBs ending their service life can justify investment in building recycling gigafactories. By 2025, we should have enough recyclable battery material to manufacture &amp;gt;100GWh of new LIBs (source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mckinsey.com/industries/automotive-and-assembly/our-insights/battery-recycling-takes-the-drivers-seat&quot;>;McKinsey&lt;/a>;). And thanks to the Inflation Reduction Act of 2022, battery recycling is getting a big boost thanks to a clause in the legislation titled the “Advanced Manufacturing Production Credit”, which grants 10 years&#39; worth of tax credits for the domestic manufacturing of battery cells and modules. Under the provision, batteries recycled in the US qualify for subsidies, regardless of their origin.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Importantly, the prospect of a dual-stream market for these battery materials may redound to the benefit of recyclers. If recyclers are able to achieve lower costs (including regulatory incentives to promote the greener practice) but they are not able to supply the entire industry, the price that they can demand may reflect the higher costs of mined material, leading to higher profits. And increasing the value of an end-of-life LIB may reduce total cost of ownership for an EV, further growing the EV market.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Importantly, the monetary profit generated per ton of battery material could approach approximately $600 by as early as 2025 according to a recent McKinsey &amp;amp; Company study. Going forward, we expect the value creation potential to grow to similar levels to the primary metals industry, which is around 30 percent depending on price developments.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/Fig4_MonetaryValue.r1.png&quot; alt=&quot;The monetary value generated per ton of battery recycling material.&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to better recycling techniques and infrastructure, there&#39;s significant opportunities in creating new kinds of batteries that are not only optimized for particular use cases but are also longer lasting and safer. For example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.byterat.io/&quot;>;Byterat&lt;/a>; provides an end-to-end cloud platform for battery research and engineering. In turn this helps the industry build better, longer lasting batteries. Similarly, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zitara.com/&quot;>;Zitara&lt;/a>; offers powerful battery management software to help better understand, manage, and maximize batteries. By extending battery life, we can reduce the amount of batteries entering recycling in the first place.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recycling this coming wave of LiB is no small challenge. But we&#39;ve faced this crossroads before and transformed problems into progress through patient investment. If we apply those lessons, battery recycling could quietly blossom into a pillar of the circular economy, just when we need it most.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The incentives align for recycling to become the norm, not the exception. But it takes vision to see value in discarded batteries and perseverance to extract it. If we maintain that mindset, LiB recycling has the potential to be a quiet triumph that supports sustainability when it&#39;s needed most. The opportunity is in our hands if we have the patience.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most things that matter take patience and persistence. Battery recycling is no exception. But if we apply the mindset that transformed lead battery recycling, we can do it again for LiB and other technologies.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Often the most important progress goes unnoticed precisely because it becomes so widely adopted that we take it for granted. We forget how much effort went into making recycling not just viable but normal.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Battery recycling likely won&#39;t make headlines. But it&#39;s a quiet triumph, and an encouraging reminder of our ability to build smart circular systems if we put our minds to it.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/recharge-recycle-repeat-the-sustainable-secret-of-the-battery-world/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/recharge-recycle-repeat-the-sustainable-secret-of-the-battery-world/</guid></item><item><title> The Tide Is Going Out</title><description> &lt;p>;Like many Americans, when I was a child, my family used to take a week-long vacation in July or August. Unlike many families, we weren&#39;t the “beach-going type”. We joke that it was because my younger brother hated the feeling of hot sand on his feet, but it was largely due to my parents wanting us to experience something different each summer. This said, three decades later, the trip that ironically gets remembered and talked about the most was the one that had the most things “go wrong”. It isn&#39;t even close.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1992, my family decided it would be fun to visit Nova Scotia. Since my brother and I had not been out of the country, my parents thought it would be a good opportunity to head north of the border. As a result, we piled into our car in early August and hit I-95 north. What followed was a trip filled with record setting heat, a massive backup on the George Washington Bridge, several missed exits, a work emergency that forced my father to fly back half way up the east coast, and a hotel that didn&#39;t have air conditioning due to the fact that this part of Canada rarely saw temperatures above the low 80s, just to name a few of the “hiccups” we encountered. However, these all paled in comparison to us almost getting trapped on an island in the middle of the Bay of Fundy.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While you have likely never heard of it, the Bay of Fundy has the largest tidal range in the world with a range of 16 meters versus an average range worldwide of 3.3 meters. In a single 12-hour tidal cycle, about 100 billion tons of water flow in and out of the bay, which is &lt;em>;twice as much as the combined total flow of all the rivers of the world over the same period&lt;/em>;. As a result, at low tide you can even drive your car across its bottom to various islands. The key, however, is that you have to carefully watch the clock because if you don&#39;t get back in time, you will be stuck on the island for the night.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You can see where this is going.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After my father rejoined us in Nova Scotia, he was determined to drive across the Bay of Fundy, so we headed out to explore one of the islands the next day. Despite my initial skepticism, it was actually a pretty cool experience. We saw some people walking across, while others were just hanging out in it. To our surprise, we were the only cars crossing when we did, but there were plenty of cars in the parking lot once we got to the island. I didn&#39;t think anything of it at the time, but this would make a lot more sense in a few short hours.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/Screenshot%202023-09-29%20at%2010.19.57%20AM.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot 2023-09-29 at 10.19.57 AM.png&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After parking, we started to explore. There wasn&#39;t a ton to see near the parking lot, so we ended up straying a bit further from the car than we had planned. Eventually, my father said it was time to head back knowing that the tide was going to come back in soon. The trouble was that there weren&#39;t any cars left in the lot when we got back. They had all crossed back over. He hadn&#39;t realized that you needed to head back well in advance of the tide coming in. You couldn&#39;t just sneak back across right before the water did. Thankfully though, we made it back to our car just in time and crossed back over the Bay of Fundy.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, why do I bring up the Bay of Fundy and our trip to Nova Scotia?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, I have always found it interesting that the family vacation which involved the most problems is the one that comes up most often to this day. Most importantly, we do not talk about it in a negative light. In fact, when one of us mentions it, it largely elicits laughs and positive memories – how we adjusted to the heat, how we found the best bacon cheeseburger in Canada, how our drives on the golf course were much longer given it was so firm and burned out from the lack of rain, how my mom traversed the Maine National Forest at night by herself, and of course, how we almost got stuck on an island in the middle of the Bay of Fundy. Makes you wonder, today as people endlessly “pursue perfect” — the perfect family vacation, the perfect athletic experience, the perfect house, the perfect life, are we missing the point? Instead of “searching for perfect”, should we instead be searching for unique experiences and embracing whatever this pursuit brings?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, it feels like the economy might be experiencing the early stages of a “Bay of Fundy” moment. Much like the tidal cycle in Nova Scotia, which sees the tide go in and out every 12-hours, the economy has been in a very advantageous tidal period for more than 12-&lt;em>;years&lt;/em>; given how long interest rates hovered near historic lows. Yet, with the Fed having hiked rates more quickly than in any period since the early 1980&#39;s, the economic tide is clearly shifting. So far, we have just seen the earliest signs.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most obvious?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The yield curve is the most inverted it&#39;s been in two decades, gasoline prices above $4 are squeezing consumers, leading economic indicators have been trending lower for 17 straight months, office occupancy is cratering as leases roll, instability in the banking sector is rising as balance sheets fall under water as a result of higher rates, credit is expensive at best and unavailable at worst, housing affordability is at an all-time low, and corporate bankruptcies are rising, just to name a few.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The less obvious?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the wake of the financial crisis fifteen years ago, congress enacted legislation to strengthen and safeguard the financial system. More specifically, in order to prevent another crisis, regulators restricted banks&#39; ability to overextend themselves again through the Dodd-Frank bill. Unsurprisingly, this caused many banks to curb lending, focus on fewer business channels, and take less risk more broadly. As is typically the case, in trying to solve the past crisis, the government may have sown the seeds for the next one.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Regulation simply shifted the risks to a different part of the economy. In this case, when Dodd-Frank forced most banks to pull back on lending, &lt;em>;plenty&lt;/em>; of people and/or funds stood ready to fill the gap. Unsurprisingly, this has largely come from the less regulated part of the market, namely in the form of the private markets. With rates at historic lows, these new lenders provided capital to nearly anyone who asked for it.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The good news?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It led to an increase in sources of capital and new business formation.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The bad news?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Capital inevitability funded many more businesses and opportunities than were needed, or warranted. It also led to the creation of countless funds, many of which are led by people who have never invested through a crisis. Looking ahead, this could be a problematic combination.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So where does this leave us?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If I had to guess, we are likely in a similar situation to the one my family found ourselves in when we started making our way back to our car in the middle of the Bay of Fundy. In this case though, while a few cars have already left the island (see any private equity firms that raised large funds, funds that made large asset sales in 2021-2022, or companies that obtained long-term cheap debt), many more haven&#39;t.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, what is in store for those “still on the island”? More specifically, businesses that have great concepts but are fundamentally unprofitable businesses, venture funds that deployed too much capital at high valuations, and lenders that thought rates were going to remain low forever? I suspect many will find themselves stranded without access to capital and other important resources; only instead of it being for one night, it will likely be for several years. Some will survive long enough to eventually get off the island, but many more will not.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While this will likely still take time to unfold in the private markets, it appears to already be well underway in the public markets with the average small-cap stock in the Russell 2000 down more than 33% from its 52-week high.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the meantime, for those who managed to get off the island in time or passed on visiting the island altogether (ie, those who took less risk, did not get overextended, and/or have plenty of cash on hand), it might make sense to spend time trying to make a distinction between those that will eventually get off and those that will not, because when those that get off do, they will likely be available for &lt;em>;very&lt;/em>; attractive prices.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 13:14:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/the-tide-is-going-out/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/the-tide-is-going-out/</guid></item><item><title> The Written Word</title><description> &lt;p>;A few thoughts I have about writing:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Writing is an art, and art is subjective&lt;/strong>;. Novelist William Maughan said there are three rules to good writing. “Unfortunately no one knows what they are.” I actually think there&#39;s one: write the kind of stuff you like to read. Writing for yourself is fun, and it shows. Writing for others is work, and it shows.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Good writing is a performance&lt;/strong>;. Mark Twain used to read aloud his family and watch their reactions. If he saw them getting bored, he&#39;d cut that part out. If he saw them getting excited, he&#39;d double down on that section. People don&#39;t remember what you wrote as much as they remember how they felt when they read it.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;A good story is like leverage for ideas&lt;/strong>;. Stories leverage ideas the same way debt leverages assets. A idea on its own might be boring, but if you tell a good story about someone interacting with that idea, you can get people to nod their heads and pay attention.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;People don&#39;t remember books, blogs, or articles&lt;/strong>;. They remember sentences. That should be your goal: a collection of memorable sentences. One good line is infinitely more powerful than a few clumsy paragraphs.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Most good writing is a byproduct of good reading&lt;/strong>;. You&#39;ll never meet a good writer who doesn&#39;t spend most of their time reading. Not some. &lt;em>;Most&lt;/em>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Writing is an efficiency game&lt;/strong>;. Whoever says the most stuff in the fewest words wins.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;But efficient doesn&#39;t necessarily mean brief&lt;/strong>;. There are 900-page books where every word adds value. Efficient just means every line is a delight to read.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Don&#39;t try to build up to your point&lt;/strong>;. It&#39;s the biggest cause of rambling, and it&#39;s where you&#39;ll lose readers. The beginning of a story should be as pleasurable to read as the big idea that comes later.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;The best books I&#39;ve read have short chapters&lt;/strong>;. Even if they are long books, they break things into quick sections that keep you moving. It keeps the author succinct and makes the reader feel like they&#39;re progressing.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Big words mask little thoughts&lt;/strong>;. They&#39;re an attempt to fool the reader into thinking you&#39;re smart when you have nothing smart to say.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Don&#39;t overthink it. Just start writing&lt;/strong>;. Great musicians find their music in jam sessions – unstructured, no planning, just seeing what happens. I think good writing is the same. If you think about it too much, you&#39;ll be stuck. Start with one brave sentence and see where it goes.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 26 Sep 2023 16:23:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/the-written-word/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/the-written-word/</guid></item><item><title> A Few Things I&#39;m Pretty Sure About</title><description> &lt;p>;You don&#39;t have to know exactly what the future holds to know that some people will handle it better than others.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Money can bring happiness but it also brings complexity, and complexity can quickly lead to unhappiness.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It&#39;s easy to mistake getting attention for being right or being admired, especially on social media.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most valuable personal finance asset is not needing to impress anyone.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A bigger problem than price inflation is expectations inflation: A constant increase in what you need to be satisfied.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The strongest-held beliefs are usually on topics with the most uncertainty. No one is as passionate about geometry as they are about religion.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have no interest in anything that&#39;s not sustainable. The key to success in so many areas of life is endurance and longevity.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The proper financial mindset is to be scared enough to save for the short run and brave enough to invest for the long run.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Projection is one of the most powerful forces, so be careful around those who tell you how honest and trustworthy they are.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Any amount of intelligence can be overridden by: ego, insecurity, immorality, bad incentives, or impatience, usually in that order.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There&#39;s a big difference between how something should work in theory vs. how it actually works in the real world, when technical facts meet human emotions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;People only communicate perhaps 1% of what&#39;s going through their head, so the world is probably 100x crazier and messier than it looks. Related: It is easier to spot other people&#39;s mistakes than your own, because we judge others based solely on their actions, but when judging ourselves we have an internal dialogue that justifies our mistakes and bad decisions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Everyone hates a spoiled child and knows that child is socially ruined, but they themselves want easy money. Do you see the irony? Money you didn&#39;t earn or work hard for quickly becomes a social liability.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The four most dangerous financial traits are: FOMO, an addiction to the appearance of certainty when none exists, impatience, and laziness.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most fields have only a few laws. Lots of theories, hunches, observations, ideas, trends, and rules. But laws – things that are always true, all the time – are rare.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Woodrow Wilson said government “is accountable to Darwin, not to Newton.” It&#39;s a useful idea. Everything is accountable to one of the two, and you have to know whether something adapts and changes over time or perpetually stays the same.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some of my best work was easy to write, and the worst stuff I&#39;ve ever written was agonizing to write. I think it&#39;s similar in most fields. If an idea is good, the work flows easily. Writers&#39; block – or its equivalent in other jobs – usually means the idea is wrong.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You only know someone well if you can correctly predict how they will react in stressful situations.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It&#39;s common to think that people admire you for your success, but what you might actually be fostering is envy, which will come back to haunt you.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I love Brent Beshore&#39;s observation that, “I am 100% happy to watch you get really rich doing something that I have no interest in doing.” It&#39;s not always a competition.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not caring about temporary things, and obsessing over permanent things, is underrated.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 14:55:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/a-few-things-im-pretty-sure-about-0923/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/a-few-things-im-pretty-sure-about-0923/</guid></item><item><title> Three Questions for Netflix Co-Founder Marc Randolph</title><description> &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://marcrandolph.com/&quot;>;Marc Randolph&lt;/a>; is the co-founder and first CEO of Netflix. We recently asked him three questions about business and life.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;What aren&#39;t people talking about enough?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Discussions about mental health in the workplace, including burnout, stress, and the need for a healthier work-life balance, are still not as common as they should be.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And we need to start, because the situation is getting worse. Slack is constantly calling for our attention. Cell phones make us available and responsive at all hours. And the recent (and pronounced) shift to working from home has further blurred the line between work and personal time.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We all joke about Gen Z&#39;s insistence on “having a life” but I must confess that they have it right. I shouldn&#39;t be surprised that my most popular social media posts – by an order of magnitude - are not the ones about startup tactics, but instead are the ones about finding a better work life balance, digital sabbaths, establishing boundaries between office and home, and similar subjects.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These topics matter. Endless product sprints, rivers of text messages, and dashboards full of productivity metrics all push, push, and push us to behave in unsustainable ways.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Something must change, and as business leaders this is on us. It&#39;s not enough to simply pay lip service to the &lt;em>;idea&lt;/em>; that balance is important. Since culture is observational, not aspirational, we need to model the behavior we want to see.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have often written about the fact that for years – including the years I was building Netflix – I left home promptly at 5:00 every Tuesday for a date night with my wife. If there was a crisis, we were going to wrap it up by 5:00. If you desperately need to talk to me, we can talk on the way to the car.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And while this behavior may have saved my sanity (and my marriage), the real benefit is that the rest of the company could see that I meant it when I told them that I expected them to carve out time for themselves.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Is this easy? No. But is it essential?是的。 Because when all is said and done, the only people who are going to remember all those nights and weekends you spent at the office are your children.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;What have you changed your mind about lately?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Don&#39;t get me started.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A few years ago, I decided I would try to change my mind about something at least once a month – and that turned out to be way too easy.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I started with politics – we are a polarized nation and I&#39;ve got plenty of opinions about why the other side&#39;s policies are so awful. But if the US is split close to 50/50 on most of these issues, I can&#39;t possibly believe that 160 million people are dead wrong. Or stupid. Or misguided.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I needed to approach my beliefs the way I did when I was debating in high school. I had to prepare myself to be able to articulate and defend a certain side of an argument, but I had to do so without knowing until right before the debate which side I would need to argue for.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The more I did this, the more I realized how shallow so many of my opinions were, and that this way of thinking could not only be applied to big topics like educational reform, homelessness, gun control, immigration, environmental policies, criminal justice, and racial equality, but to smaller and equally heated topics like – to name a recent one - password sharing on Netflix. (I&#39;m not joking about the password sharing thing – It&#39;s gotten so I&#39;m scared to wade into my TikTok comments).&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It&#39;s been liberating, because I no longer spend my time building the case for why I&#39;m right. I now spend most of my cycles trying to figure out why they think &lt;em>;they&lt;/em>; are.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It has changed my perspective on almost every topic I&#39;ve looked at. But what has surprised me most about the exercise is that in almost every instance, changing my mind didn&#39;t mean flipping from one side to the other, but simply meant moving closer to the center. It meant acknowledging that these were complicated and nuanced answers that didn&#39;t have &lt;em>;any&lt;/em>; right answer. Or more frequently, would require partially unsatisfactory outcomes for both sides to agree on, accept, and move on.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I&#39;ve still got a way to go. I&#39;m still trying to work out exactly why people are so vehemently opposed to the password sharing crackdown . 。 。 but I promise I&#39;m working on it.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;What&#39;s a piece of commonly accepted advice you think is wrong?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“There&#39;s no such thing as a bad idea.” That&#39;s got to be the worst advice ever. Because I&#39;ve learned that the opposite is true. &lt;em>;All&lt;/em>; ideas are bad. In fact, there&#39;s no such thing as a &lt;em>;good&lt;/em>; idea.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And it&#39;s not just wrong . 。 。 it&#39;s dangerous. Because by assuming that all ideas are good, it encourages hundreds of hours of wasted effort studying the problem, writing plans, putting together task forces, etc. – all without any feedback from the real world about whether it&#39;s actually a good idea or not.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Our job as entrepreneurs is to take those (bad) ideas and figure out a quick, cheap and easy way to find out why they are bad. That&#39;s the only way to begin the process of testing and iteration that – if we&#39;re lucky – will eventually bring us to something that works.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I can&#39;t think of a single successful company that has become successful doing their original idea. Instead, that idea was only a starting point. They took that original idea; figured out some cheap, quick, and easy way to try it; watched what happened; and then tried something else. And probably did that for years.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At Netflix it took us more than 18 months, and hundreds of failed experiments to finally land on the business model that was a good idea. And they are still experimenting.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 12 Sep 2023 12:21:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/three-questions-for-netflix-co-founder-marc-randolph/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/three-questions-for-netflix-co-founder-marc-randolph/</guid></item></channel></rss>