<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>合作基金</title><description>Collab Fund 是企业家推动世界前进的主要资金来源。</description><link/> https://collabfund.com<atom:link href="https://collabfund.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 12:49:46 -0400</pubDate><lastbuilddate> 2023 年 10 月 2 日星期一 12:49:46 -0400</lastbuilddate><generator>站点叶</generator><item><title>充电、回收、重复：电池世界的可持续发展秘密</title><description>&lt;p>;电池世界正在发生一些令人惊奇的事情：由于智能行业举措和消费者意识，电池回收率一直在稳步上升。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;首先以为我们的汽车提供动力的铅酸电池为例。据行业报告，这些电池在美国的回收率为 99%，是铝罐回收率的 2 倍。据《今日回收》报道，这使得铅汽车电池成为单一&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.recyclingtoday.com/news/bci-study-claims-lead-batteries-most-recycled-consumer-product-in-united -states/&quot;>;大多数回收消费品&lt;/a>;。没错 - 每年大约收集和回收 1.6 亿个铅电池，从而避免超过 250 万吨铅和塑料堵塞垃圾填埋场。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/ uploads/Fig1_RecycledProducts.r2.png&quot; alt=&quot;美国顶级回收产品图表，其中铅酸电池位居榜首，占 99%&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;情况并非总是如此。就在几十年前，只有一半的铅电池被回收。但通过电池制造商、回收商和政府之间的协调努力，基础设施和激励措施的出现使铅电池回收不仅可行，而且成为常态。这需要耐心。这需要投资。但该行业将电池回收从事后的想法转变为循环经济的光辉典范。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随着我们期待未来，越来越多的锂离子电池 (LiB) 为从手机到汽车的一切设备提供动力。尽管目前的锂电池回收率低至 5-15% 左右，但铅电池的成功故事仍令人乐观。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随着电动汽车在未来几十年的普及，锂电池的浪费预计将超过 20到 2040 年每年将减少 100 万吨。这似乎令人畏惧，但如果我们能够加大回收力度，这也代表着一个巨大的机遇。许多人看到废电池的浪潮，只看到一堵废物墙。但如果我们有耐心和聪明才智来开采，今天的废品堆就是明天的金矿。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/Fig2_BatteryRecycling.r2.png&quot; alt =&quot;全球可回收电动汽车电池供应量图表（以千吨为单位）&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;回收任何复杂的产品都很困难。弄清楚物流和经济需要时间。挑战比比皆是，尤其是在收集和运输废旧电池方面。但我们有一个模板，并且有动力投资解决问题。这些电池的回收价值是巨大的。但我们以前就这样做过，企业已经在努力扩大锂电池的回收规模。这是我们对&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.redwoodmaterials.com/news/redwood-series-d/&quot;>;我们的投资&lt;/a>;感到兴奋的原因之一：&lt;a href=&quot;https: //www.redwoodmaterials.com/&quot;>;Redwood Materials&lt;/a>; 和他们目前拥有的基础设施，用于回收电动汽车和其他类型的电池，提取有价值的材料并将其重新输入电池供应链。此次 D 轮融资超过 10 亿美元，紧随 Redwood Materials &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rgj.com/story/news/money/business/2023/02/09/redwood-materials-gets -2-billion-doe-loan-for-mega-battery-facility-near-reno/69886953007/&quot;>;美国能源部提供的 20 亿美元贷款&lt;/a>;，为公司提供了充足的资金来继续投资扩大产能。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/RedwoodMaterialsFacility.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;红木材料回收设施的鸟瞰图。&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这不会在一夜之间发生。我们需要建设基础设施并扩大流程。汽车制造商、电池生产商和回收商需要在复杂的价值链上进行合作。需要坚持不懈并解决问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从不起眼的铅电池中寻找灵感似乎已经过时了。您可能不会从外表上猜到，但标志性的铅电池在设计上堪称可回收性的奇迹。它的三种主要成分——铅、塑料、酸——经过精心设计，可以在闭环完美中反复回收。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这不是事后的想法，而是核心原则。铅电池不会被丢弃，而是会重生。 &lt;strong>;典型的新型铅电池由 80% 的回收材料制成。没有性能损失，只是循环继续。值得注意的是，这些电池所需的铅 83% 都来自北美，而不是来自遥远的矿山。&lt;/strong>;塑料外壳也获得了新的生命。所有这些都在近乎完美的循环中循环。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;几十年来，铅电池已经在全国范围内编织了一个由制造、收集地点和回收商组成的网络，&lt;strong>;超过 300,000 个地点&lt;/strong>;接受铅电池用过的电池。这是一个旨在保持铅流通的生态系统。这不是一夜之间发生的。行业团体将利益相关者聚集在一起，慢慢构建智能系统并灌输负责任的电池管理。没有炒作，只有坚持。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;回收的好处不仅仅是减少浪费。 &lt;strong>;生产再生铅所需的能源比开采和冶炼新铅矿石少 70%。更少的能源意味着更少的碳排放。&lt;/strong>;回收完成了循环。根据麦肯锡公司的研究，铅电池已经显示出一条前进的道路。公司希望锂电池能够走类似的道路。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;复制锂电池的铅回收管道并不简单。不幸的是，回收锂离子电池的过程本质上比回收铅电池更加棘手。铅是铅酸电池中唯一的金属，可以通过简单的工艺将其与其他电池材料分离，从而产生高纯度的铅锭。与锂离子电池相比，其中有价值的金属数量众多、种类繁多，并且存在于化学混合物中，通常需要更复杂的分离方法。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;铅汽车电池是回收的成功案例，但更普遍的单一电池使用碱性电池为我们的手电筒和电视遥控器供电已经走了一条不太鼓舞人心的道路。这些电池的回收率仍然很低，只有通过激励非经济行为的法规才能提高（&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1878535223006020&quot;>;来源&lt;/a>;， &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/sustainable-business/2016/apr/14/drawer-full-of-them-battery-recycling-waste-eu&quot;>;来源&lt;/a>;）。一个关键问题在于构成碱性电池的金属（主要是铁、锌和锰）非常便宜。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于锂离子电池来说幸运的是，制造碱性电池的金属有锂、镍和钴。起来大头的材料成本是相当值钱的。再加上庞大且不断增长的锂离子电池市场，让我们希望锂离子电池回收能够大规模盈利。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在这一奖项和提高电动汽车可持续性目标的推动下，像 Redwood Materials 这样的初创公司正在解决以下问题：分离的技术挑战。像他们这样的工艺能够回收高达 95% 的电池材料，以降低成本进行再利用。这是从边缘拉回来的有价值的金属，以抵消昂贵的新采矿的需要。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/Fig3_CarbonFootprint.r2.png&quot; alt=&quot;图表显示使用回收材料的回收电池可减少 28% 的排放量”/>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;回收的锂离子电池材料要从开采的矿物中夺取重要的市场份额还需要一段时间。问题在于，电动汽车的采用增长太快，新电池的需求无法与旧电池的供应相匹配——从 2021 年到 2022 年，电动汽车在全球新车购买量中所占的比例从 8.7% 增加到 14%，从 4.5% 增加到美国的 % 至 7.7%（&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iea.org/data-and-statistics/data-tools/global-ev-data-explorer&quot;>;来源&lt;/a>;）。就问题而言，这是一件好事，而且它当然不应该阻碍锂离子电池回收领域的活动。据估计，到 2030 年，回收将能够满足约 7% 的锂需求以及 11% 的钴和镍需求（&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0921344922003317&quot;>;来源&lt;/a>;），十年后大约是这个数字的两倍。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最令人兴奋的是，我们现在正接近一个临界点，即结束使用寿命的锂离子电池的数量可以证明对建筑回收的投资是合理的超级工厂。到 2025 年，我们应该有足够的可回收电池材料来制造超过 100GWh 的新型锂离子电池（来源：&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mckinsey.com/industries/automotive-and-assemble/our-insights/battery-回收占据主导地位>;麦肯锡&lt;/a>;）。得益于 2022 年《通货膨胀减少法案》，电池回收利用立法中名为“先进制造生产信贷”的条款得到了大力推动，该条款为国内电池制造和电池制造提供了 10 年的税收抵免。模块。根据该规定，在美国回收的电池，无论其来源如何，都有资格获得补贴。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;重要的是，这些电池材料的双流市场前景可能有利于回收商的利益。如果回收商能够实现更低的成本（包括促进绿色实践的监管激励措施），但他们无法供应整个行业，那么他们可以要求的价格可能会反映开采材料的更高成本，从而带来更高的利润。提高报废锂离子电池的价值可能会降低电动汽车的总拥有成本，从而进一步扩大电动汽车市场。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;重要的是，每吨电池材料产生的货币利润可能接近约 600 美元根据麦肯锡最近的一份报告，最早将于 2025 年实现这一目标。公司学习。展望未来，我们预计价值创造潜力将增长至与初级金属行业类似的水平，约为 30%，具体取决于价格发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/ uploads/Fig4_MonetaryValue.r1.png&quot; alt=&quot;每吨电池回收材料产生的货币价值。&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了更好的回收技术和基础设施之外，在创造新型电池方面也存在重大机遇，这些电池不仅针对特定用例进行了优化，而且更耐用、更安全。例如，&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.byterat.io/&quot;>;Byterat&lt;/a>; 为电池研究和工程提供了端到端的云平台。反过来，这有助于该行业制造更好、更耐用的电池。同样，&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zitara.com/&quot;>;Zitara&lt;/a>; 提供强大的电池管理软件，帮助更好地了解、管理和最大化电池。通过延长电池寿命，我们可以首先减少进入回收的电池数量。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;回收即将到来的锂电池浪潮是一个不小的挑战。但我们以前也曾面临过这个十字路口，并通过耐心投入将问题转化为进步。如果我们应用这些经验教训，电池回收可能会在我们最需要的时候悄然发展成为循环经济的支柱。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;激励措施使回收成为常态，而不是例外。但需要有远见才能看到废弃电池的价值，并需要坚持不懈地提取它。如果我们保持这种心态，锂电池回收就有可能悄然取得胜利，在最需要的时候支持可持续发展。如果我们有耐心，机会就在我们手中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大多数重要的事情都需要耐心和坚持。电池回收也不例外。但如果我们运用改变铅电池回收的思维方式，我们就可以在锂电池和其他技术上再次做到这一点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最重要的进步往往被忽视，正是因为它被如此广泛地采用，以至于我们认为这是理所当然的。我们忘记了为使回收不仅可行而且正常而付出了多少努力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;电池回收可能不会成为头条新闻。但这是一次无声的胜利，并且令人鼓舞地提醒我们，如果我们下定决心，我们有能力构建智能循环系统。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/recharge-recycle-repeat-the-sustainable-secret-of-the-battery-world/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/recharge-recycle-repeat-the-sustainable-secret-of-the-battery-world/</guid></item><item><title>潮水即将退去</title><description>&lt;p>;像许多美国人一样，当我还是个孩子的时候，我的家人常常在七月或八月度过为期一周的假期。与许多家庭不同，我们不是“海滩类型”。我们开玩笑说，这是因为我的弟弟讨厌脚上热沙的感觉，但这很大程度上是因为我的父母希望我们每个夏天都能体验不同的东西。这就是说，三十年后，讽刺的是，那次被人们记住和谈论最多的旅行却是“出错”最多的那次旅行。距离还很远。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1992 年，我的家人认为去新斯科舍省会很有趣。由于我和哥哥没有出过国，父母认为这是一个北上边境的好机会。结果，我们在八月初挤进车里，沿着 95 号州际公路向北行驶。接下来是一次充满创纪录高温的旅行，乔治华盛顿大桥上的大规模备份，几次错过出口，工作紧急情况迫使我父亲飞回东海岸的一半，以及一家没有空气的酒店由于加拿大这一地区的气温很少超过 80 度，仅举几个我们遇到的“问题”。然而，与我们几乎被困在芬迪湾中部的一座岛屿相比，这些都显得黯然失色。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;虽然您可能从未听说过，但芬迪湾拥有全球最大的潮差。全球范围为 16 米，而全球平均范围为 3.3 米。在单个12小时的潮汐周期中，进出海湾的水量约为1000亿吨，是同期世界所有河流总流量的两倍。 >;。因此，在退潮时，您甚至可以驾驶汽车穿过底部前往各个岛屿。不过，关键是你必须仔细观察时钟，因为如果你不及时返回，你就会被困在岛上过夜。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;你可以看到事情的走向。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;父亲在新斯科舍省与我们会合后，他决定开车穿越芬迪湾，所以第二天我们就出发去探索其中一个岛屿。尽管我最初对此表示怀疑，但这实际上是一次非常酷的体验。我们看到一些人走过，而另一些人只是在里面闲逛。令我们惊讶的是，我们是唯一过路的汽车，但是当我们到达岛上时，停车场里已经有很多汽车了。当时我并没有多想，但在短短几个小时内这会变得更有意义。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/Screenshot% 202023-09-29%20at%2010.19.57%20AM.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot 2023-09-29 at 10.19.57 AM.png&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;停车后，我们开始探索。停车场附近没什么可看的，所以我们最终偏离了汽车，比我们计划的要远一些。最终，我父亲说是时候回去了，因为他知道潮水很快就会回来。问题是我们回来时停车场已经没有车了。他们都穿越回来了。他没有意识到你需要在潮水到来之前提前返回。你不能在水涨之前偷偷溜回去。不过值得庆幸的是，我们及时回到了车上，穿越了芬迪湾。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那么，我为什么要提起芬迪湾和我们的新斯科舍省之旅呢？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; >; &lt;p>;首先，我一直觉得很有趣的是，涉及最多问题的家庭度假是迄今为止最常出现的一个。最重要的是，我们不会从负面角度谈论它。事实上，当我们中的一个人提到它时，它很大程度上会引起笑声和积极的回忆——我们如何适应炎热，我们如何找到加拿大最好的培根芝士汉堡，我们如何在高尔夫球场上开球更长时间，因为它是如此坚硬因缺雨而疲惫不堪，我妈妈如何在夜间独自穿越缅因国家森林，当然，还有我们如何差点被困在芬迪湾中部的一个岛上。让你想知道，在人们不断“追求完美”的今天——完美的家庭度假、完美的运动体验、完美的房子、完美的生活，我们是否错过了重点？我们不应该“追求完美”，而应该寻找独特的体验并拥抱这种追求带来的一切吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其次，感觉经济可能正在经历“芬迪湾”的早期阶段片刻。就像新斯科舍省的潮汐周期一样，潮汐每 12 小时进退一次，考虑到利率的持续时间，经济在超过 12 年的时间里一直处于非常有利的潮汐期徘徊在历史低位附近。然而，随着美联储加息速度比 1980 年代初以来的任何时期都快，经济潮流正在明显发生变化。到目前为止，我们刚刚看到了最早的迹象。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最明显的？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;收益率曲线是二十年来最倒挂的，汽油价格高于 4 美元正在挤压消费者，主要经济指标已连续 17 个月呈下降趋势，办公室入住率随着租期的延长而大幅下降，银行业的不稳定随着资产负债表因利率上升而陷入困境而加剧，信贷充其量是昂贵的，而在最坏的情况下是无法获得的，住房负担能力处于历史最低水平，企业破产率不断上升，仅举几例。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不太明显的？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;十五年前金融危机之后，国会颁布立法以加强和维护金融体系。更具体地说，为了防止另一场危机，监管机构通过多德弗兰克法案限制了银行再次过度扩张的能力。毫不奇怪，这导致许多银行限制放贷，专注于更少的业务渠道，并更广泛地承担更少的风险。正如通常的情况一样，在试图解决过去的危机时，政府可能已经为下一场危机播下了种子。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;监管只是将风险转移到了经济的不同部分。在这种情况下，当多德弗兰克法案迫使大多数银行缩减贷款时，大量人员和/或资金已准备好填补缺口。毫不奇怪，这主要来自市场中监管较少的部分，即以私人市场的形式。由于利率处于历史低位，这些新贷款人几乎向所有需要的人提供了资金。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;好消息？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这导致了资本来源的增加和新业务的形成.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;坏消息？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;资本不可避免地资助了比需要或保证的更多的企业和机会。它还导致了无数基金的创建，其中许多基金是由从未经历过危机投资的人领导的。展望未来，这可能是一个有问题的组合。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那么这会给我们带来什么影响？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果我不得不猜测的话，我们很可能处于与我家人发现的情况类似的情况当我们开始返回芬迪湾中部的汽车时，我们自己就陷入了困境。不过，在这种情况下，虽然有一些汽车已经离开了这个岛（看看任何筹集大量资金的私募股权公司、在 2021-2022 年进行大量资产出售的基金，或者获得长期廉价债务的公司），但更多的汽车避难所&#39;t。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那么，对于那些“仍在岛上”的人来说，接下来会发生什么呢？更具体地说，那些拥有伟大概念但根本上无利可图的企业、在高估值下部署过多资本的风险基金以及认为利率将永远保持在低位的贷款人？我怀疑许多人会发现自己陷入困境，无法获得资金和其他重要资源；只是不是一晚，而是可能好几年。有些人会生存足够长的时间，最终离开这个岛，但更多的人不会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;虽然这可能仍需要时间在私人市场上展开，但它似乎已经在公开市场上顺利进行罗素 2000 指数的小盘股平均价格较 52 周高点下跌了 33% 以上。完全离开岛屿（即那些承担风险较小、没有过度扩张和/或手头有大量现金的人），花时间尝试区分那些最终会离开的人和那些会离开的人可能是有意义的不会，因为当那些下车的人下车时，他们可能会以非常有吸引力的价格获得。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 13:14:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/the-tide-is-going-out/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/the-tide-is-going-out/</guid></item><item><title>书面文字</title><description>&lt;p>;我对写作的一些想法：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;写作是一门艺术，而艺术是主观的&lt;/strong>;。小说家威廉·莫恩说过，优秀的写作需要遵循三个规则。 “不幸的是没有人知道它们是什么。”我实际上认为有一个：写你喜欢读的东西。为自己写作是很有趣的，这一点也表明了这一点。为他人写作是一种工作，这表明了这一点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;好的写作是一种表演&lt;/strong>;。马克吐温曾经大声朗读他的家人并观察他们的反应。如果他看到他们感到无聊，他就会把那部分剪掉。如果他看到他们变得兴奋，他就会在该部分加倍努力。人们记住的不是你写的内容，而是他们读到的感受。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;一个好的故事就像思想的杠杆&lt;/strong>;。故事利用思想，就像债务利用资产一样。一个想法本身可能很无聊，但如果你讲述一个关于某人与该想法互动的好故事，你可以让人们点头并注意。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;人们不记得书籍、博客或文章&lt;/strong>;。他们记住句子。这应该是你的目标：收集令人难忘的句子。一句好的台词比几段笨拙的段落更有力量。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;大多数好的写作都是良好阅读的副产品&lt;/strong>;。你永远不会遇到一个不把大部分时间花在阅读上的好作家。不是一些。 &lt;em>;大多数&lt;/em>;。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;写作是一种效率游戏&lt;/strong>;。谁用最少的字数说出最多的内容，谁就获胜。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;但高效并不一定意味着简短&lt;/strong>;。有900页的书，每一个字都增值。高效只是意味着每一行都读起来令人愉悦。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;不要试图阐述你的观点&lt;/strong>;。这是造成漫无目的的最大原因，也是你失去读者的地方。故事的开头应该和后面出现的大想法一样读起来令人愉快。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;我读过的最好的书都有简短的章节&lt;/strong>;。即使它们是很长的书，它们也会将内容分成快速的部分，让您不断前进。它使作者保持简洁，让读者感觉自己正在进步。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;大话掩盖小想法&lt;/strong>;。他们试图欺骗读者，让他们认为你很聪明，而你却没有什么聪明的话可说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;不要想太多。开始写作吧&lt;/strong>;。伟大的音乐家在即兴演奏中找到他们的音乐——无组织、没有计划，只是看看会发生什么。我认为好的写作也是一样的。如果你想太多，你就会陷入困境。从一句勇敢的句子开始，看看它会走向何方。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 26 Sep 2023 16:23:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/the-writing-word/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/the-writing-word/</guid></item><item><title>有几件事我很确定</title><description>&lt;p>;你不必确切地知道未来会发生什么，就知道有些人会比其他人更好地处理它。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;金钱可以带来幸福，但也会带来复杂性，而复杂性很快就会导致不快乐。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人们很容易将获得关注误认为是正确的或受到钦佩，尤其是在社交媒体上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最有价值的个人财务资产是不需要给任何人留下深刻的印象。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; >; &lt;p>;比价格通胀更大的问题是预期通胀：你需要满足的东西不断增加。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最强烈的信念通常是最不确定的主题。没有人像对宗教那样对几何充满热情。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我对任何不可持续的事物都不感兴趣。在生活的许多领域取得成功的关键是耐力和长寿。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;正确的财务心态是足够害怕短期储蓄并足够勇敢进行长期投资。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; >; &lt;p>;投射是最强大的力量之一，所以要小心那些告诉你他们多么诚实和值得信赖的人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;任何智力都可能被以下因素所压倒：自我、不安全感、不道德、不良激励或不耐烦通常按此顺序排列。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当技术事实与人类情感相遇时，理论上的工作方式与现实世界中的实际工作方式之间存在很大差异。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; >; &lt;p>;人们只能传达他们头脑中想法的 1%，所以这个世界可能比看上去的疯狂和混乱 100 倍。相关：发现别人的错误比发现自己的错误更容易，因为我们仅根据他人的行为来判断他人，但在判断自己时，我们会进行内部对话，为我们的错误和错误决定辩护。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;每个人都讨厌一个被宠坏的孩子，知道孩子在社会上被毁了，但他们自己想要轻松赚钱。你看到讽刺了吗？不是你挣来的或不是努力工作的钱很快就会成为一种社会责任。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;四种最危险的财务特征是：FOMO（错失恐惧症）、沉迷于表面上的确定性（实际上根本不存在）、不耐烦和懒惰。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;大多数领域只有少数法律。许多理论、预感、观察、想法、趋势和规则。但法律——始终正确的事物——很少见。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;伍德罗·威尔逊说政府“对达尔文负责，而不是对牛顿负责。”这是一个有用的想法。一切都对两者之一负责，你必须知道某些东西是否会随着时间的推移而适应和变化，还是永远保持不变。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我最好的一些作品很容易写，而我最糟糕的作品则很容易写。我曾经写过，写起来很痛苦。我认为在大多数领域都是相似的。如果想法好，工作就会很顺利。作家的障碍——或者其他工作中的类似情况——通常意味着这个想法是错误的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;只有当你能够正确预测一个人在压力情况下的反应时，你才能充分了解他。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人们普遍认为人们钦佩你的成功，但你实际上可能在培养嫉妒，而嫉妒会反过来困扰你。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我喜欢布伦特·贝肖尔的观察，“我 100% 快乐”看着你做一些我不感兴趣的事情而变得非常富有。”这并不总是一场竞争。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不关心暂时的事情，而沉迷于永久的事情，是被低估的。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 14:55:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/a-few-things-im-pretty-sure-about-0923/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/a-few-things-im-pretty-sure-about-0923/</guid></item><item><title>问 Netflix 联合创始人马克·兰道夫的三个问题</title><description>&lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://marcrandolph.com/&quot;>;Marc Randolph&lt;/a>; 是 Netflix 的联合创始人兼首任首席执行官。我们最近问了他三个关于商业和生活的问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;人们谈论的还不够多吗？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;关于工作场所心理健康的讨论，包括倦怠、压力以及对更健康的工作与生活平衡的需求仍然没有应有的普遍。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们需要开始，因为情况正在变得更糟。 Slack 不断地引起我们的关注。手机让我们可以随时联系并做出响应。最近（并且明显）转向在家工作进一步模糊了工作和个人时间之间的界限。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们都开玩笑说 Z 世代坚持“拥有自己的生活”，但我必须承认，他们已经对的。我不应该感到惊讶的是，我最受欢迎的社交媒体帖子（按数量级计算）不是关于创业策略的帖子，而是关于寻找更好的工作生活平衡、数字安息日、建立办公室和家庭之间界限的帖子以及类似的主题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些主题很重要。无休无止的产品冲刺、海量的短信和充满生产力指标的仪表板都在不断地推动我们以不可持续的方式行事。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;必须做出一些改变，作为企业领导者，这一切都在我们的肩上。仅仅口头上承认平衡很重要的想法是不够的。由于文化是观察性的，而不是渴望性的，因此我们需要对我们希望看到的行为进行建模。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我经常写到这样一个事实：多年来（包括我创建 Netflix 的那些年），我很快就离开了家。每周二 5:00 与我的妻子约会之夜。如果出现危机，我们将在 5:00 之前结束。如果你迫切需要和我说话，我们可以在上车的路上说话。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;虽然这种行为可能挽救了我的理智（和我的婚姻），但真正的好处是，其余的事情当我告诉他们我希望他们为自己腾出时间时，公司可以看出我是认真的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这容易吗？不，但这有必要吗？是的。因为归根结底，唯一能记住你在办公室度过的那些夜晚和周末的人就是你的孩子。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;你最近改变了主意吗？&lt; /strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;别让我开始。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;几年前，我决定每月至少尝试一次改变对某件事的想法 - 结果证明太容易了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我从政治开始——我们是一个两极分化的国家，对于为什么对方的政策如此糟糕，我有很多看法。但如果美国在大多数问题上的分歧接近 50/50，我就不可能相信 1.6 亿人是完全错误的。或者愚蠢。或者被误导了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我需要像高中辩论时那样对待我的信仰。我必须做好准备，以便能够阐明并捍卫论点的某一方面，但我必须这样做，直到辩论之前我才知道我需要为哪一方辩护。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我这样做了，我越意识到我的许多观点是多么肤浅，而且这种思维方式不仅可以应用于教育改革、无家可归、枪支管制、移民、环境政策、刑事司法和种族等大话题。平等，但也涉及较小且同样热门的话题，例如最近的一个话题——Netflix 上的密码共享。 (I&#39;m not joking about the password sharing thing – It&#39;s gotten so I&#39;m scared to wade into my TikTok comments).&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It&#39;s been liberating, because I no longer spend my time building the case for why I&#39;m right. I now spend most of my cycles trying to figure out why they think &lt;em>;they&lt;/em>; are.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It has changed my perspective on almost every topic I&#39;ve looked at. But what has surprised me most about the exercise is that in almost every instance, changing my mind didn&#39;t mean flipping from one side to the other, but simply meant moving closer to the center. It meant acknowledging that these were complicated and nuanced answers that didn&#39;t have &lt;em>;any&lt;/em>; right answer. Or more frequently, would require partially unsatisfactory outcomes for both sides to agree on, accept, and move on.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I&#39;ve still got a way to go. I&#39;m still trying to work out exactly why people are so vehemently opposed to the password sharing crackdown . 。 。 but I promise I&#39;m working on it.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;What&#39;s a piece of commonly accepted advice you think is wrong?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“There&#39;s no such thing as a bad idea.” That&#39;s got to be the worst advice ever. Because I&#39;ve learned that the opposite is true. &lt;em>;All&lt;/em>; ideas are bad. In fact, there&#39;s no such thing as a &lt;em>;good&lt;/em>; idea.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And it&#39;s not just wrong . 。 。 it&#39;s dangerous. Because by assuming that all ideas are good, it encourages hundreds of hours of wasted effort studying the problem, writing plans, putting together task forces, etc. – all without any feedback from the real world about whether it&#39;s actually a good idea or not.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Our job as entrepreneurs is to take those (bad) ideas and figure out a quick, cheap and easy way to find out why they are bad. That&#39;s the only way to begin the process of testing and iteration that – if we&#39;re lucky – will eventually bring us to something that works.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I can&#39;t think of a single successful company that has become successful doing their original idea. Instead, that idea was only a starting point. They took that original idea; figured out some cheap, quick, and easy way to try it; watched what happened; and then tried something else. And probably did that for years.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At Netflix it took us more than 18 months, and hundreds of failed experiments to finally land on the business model that was a good idea. And they are still experimenting.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 12 Sep 2023 12:21:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/three-questions-for-netflix-co-founder-marc-randolph/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/three-questions-for-netflix-co-founder-marc-randolph/</guid></item><item><title> Respect and Admiration</title><description> &lt;p>;I like the idea of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.berkshirehathaway.com/letters/2022ltr.pdf&quot;>;reverse obituary&lt;/a>;: Write down what you want your obituary to say, then figure out how to live up to it.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Everyone&#39;s will be different, but I suspect most people would want their obituary to say: You were respected. You were admired. You were helpful. You were a good parent, and good spouse, a caring friend. You were an asset to your community. You made a contribution to your industry. You were wise, funny, and smart.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now realize what&#39;s not in there.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Virtually no one in this exercise would think about their obituary mentioning how much horsepower their car has, how many square feet their home is, or how much they spent on jewelry and clothes.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I like nice things. I have some fancy things. But I&#39;m always struck by the contrast here of what people want vs. what they aspire to.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just after my son was born I &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fool.com/investing/general/2015/10/13/financial-advice-for-my-new-son.aspx&quot;>;wrote a few things&lt;/a>; I thought he&#39;d find helpful as an adult. One of them was:&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;You might think you want an expensive car, a fancy watch, and a huge house. But I&#39;m telling you, you don&#39;t. What you want is respect and admiration from other people, and you think having expensive stuff will bring it. It almost never does – especially from the people you want to respect and admire you.&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;Eight years later I still believe this to be true, and I might even double down.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Let me first distinguish nice stuff from fancy stuff. Someone once noted that a high-end Toyota is a better car than an entry-level BMW, because the nice Toyota is filled with things that make driving more pleasant, while the entry-level BMW is mostly just status and bragging rights. Using money to buy nice stuff is great. Fancy stuff is a different animal.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This isn&#39;t universal, but there are cases when people&#39;s desire to show off fancy stuff is because it&#39;s their only, desperate, way to gain some sense of respect and admiration. They don&#39;t have any wisdom, intelligence, humor, empathy, or capacity for love to gain people&#39;s respect. So they rely on the only remaining, and least effective, lever: Look at my car, beep beep, vroom vroom.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Former football player Chad Johnson &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ShannonSharpe/status/1620223077702586370?s=20&amp;amp;t=iqXe7T24ijApj57thXkneA&quot;>;once explained&lt;/a>; why some people think he&#39;s cheap: There&#39;s no need to show off your material wealth when your name is so big that people already respect and admire you for your talents alone:&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;If you can get to a point in your career where your name becomes bigger than anything you can purchase, there&#39;s your value.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is nothing I can buy that is bigger than my name alone. So it made no sense [to buy jewelry]. &lt;em>;I&#39;m me&lt;/em>;. It&#39;s pointless.&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;My guess is that if your favorite comedian, or actor, or athlete turned out to be broke, you wouldn&#39;t care. It wouldn&#39;t impact how much you admire them, because you admire them for talents that money can&#39;t buy.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even when Amazon was huge and successful, Jeff Bezos &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tc0a28KrWKo&amp;amp;ab_channel=Way&quot;>;used to drive a&lt;/a>; Honda Accord. Today he has a $500 million yacht. Is he respected and admired more for it? Not in the slightest. He could ride a Huffy bike and people would consider him the greatest entrepreneur of our era, because he is. Steve Jobs &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cultofmac.com/125861/steve-jobss-quest-for-perfection-could-make-even-buying-a-sofa-into-a-decade-long-ordeal/&quot;>;didn&#39;t have any furniture&lt;/a>;. It didn&#39;t matter. He&#39;s a genius. He&#39;s Steve Jobs. Material stuff makes no difference when you&#39;re respected and admired for internal traits.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The same is probably true for the people you admire most. I love and admire my parents, and let me tell you it&#39;s not because of their clothes. Isn&#39;t there so much to learn from that? Shouldn&#39;t gaining respect and admiration through what you do instead of what you own be the goal?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Once you see people being respected and admired for reasons that have nothing to do with the stuff they own, you begin to wonder why you have such a strong desire for those possessions. I tend to view material desire as a loose proxy for the inverse of what else you have to offer the world. The higher my desire for fancy stuff, the less real value I have to offer.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I think if you keep it in mind, a lot of higher priorities come into view.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 06 Sep 2023 12:02:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/respect-and-admiration/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/respect-and-admiration/</guid></item><item><title> Intelligent vs. Smart</title><description> &lt;p>;Here&#39;s an important distinction to make in life.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some people are intelligent but don&#39;t have a lick of smarts. Their ability to succeed in the world might surprise you on the downside.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Others lack intelligence but gush smarts. Their potential will surprise you on the upside.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On rare occasions you meet people who are both intelligent and smart. They run laps around everyone.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I&#39;d define intelligence vs. smart like this: Intelligent people understand technical details, smart people understand emotional details.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Or maybe:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Intelligence&lt;/strong>;: Good memory, logic, math skills, test-taking ability, rule-following.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Smart&lt;/strong>;: High degree of empathy, bullshit detection, organization, communication skills, persuasion, social awareness, understanding the consequences of your actions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Both are important. But there&#39;s a critical difference in how each is valued.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Schools are good at teaching and measuring intelligence, so that&#39;s what people tend to value and aspire to. But in almost any field, smarts is what gets rewarded long term.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You cannot measure empathy like you can SAT scores, so it&#39;s not surprising that one is given more weight on resumes. But who is more likely to succeed in life – a person whose main skill is memorizing formulas, or someone who can instantly relate to the emotions of coworkers, customers, spouses, and friends?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It&#39;s so obvious.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And it&#39;s why the world is filled with intelligent jerks who have gone nowhere, and middling students who struggled through calculus but go on to live successful, happy lives. The most important decision most people will ever make is whether, when, and whom to marry. But that&#39;s never taught in schools – how could it be? You can&#39;t distill it down to a formula, or a one-size-fits-all answer. It&#39;s a decision that requires lots of smarts and very little intelligence.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The core here is realizing that people are not spreadsheets. They are emotional, hormonal, misinformed, status-seeking, insecure creatures trying their best to make it through the day. So if you have to choose between understanding how the world &lt;em>;should&lt;/em>; work in theory vs. how it &lt;em>;actually&lt;/em>; works in practice, lean towards the latter. It&#39;s like historian Will Durant once said: “Logic is an invention of man and may be ignored by the universe.” That is so smart.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Here&#39;s an extreme example.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;George Soros says that whenever he sees a bubble, he rushes in to buy it.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you&#39;re an intelligent person, that might seem crazy. Why would you purposefully want to buy an overvalued investment?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But if you&#39;re a smart person, maybe it makes sense.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You know that bubbles are likely to grow larger and last longer than most people imagine. You understand what&#39;s going through people&#39;s minds, and you know investors will keep frantically buying for some time not because the numbers make sense, but because their neighbor got rich and they&#39;ll spiral down a black hole of jealousy and bad decisions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“That&#39;s not irrational,” says Soros. (But please don&#39;t try this; you&#39;re probably not as smart as Soros).&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Derek Thompson of the Atlantic makes a beautiful point that baseball has become boring over the last 20 years. Why? Because every team got intelligent: they moneyballed their strategy by mining data to figure out how to get the most strikeouts. If you want to win games, that was the intelligent thing to do! But it made the game boring. It took away part of the soul, part of the fun. Now the game is in a crisis of falling interest and attendance. It took smarts to see that coming.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Here are a few other “smart” traits that are hard to measure.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Accepting that people who have lived different lives than you want different things and will see the world differently. What looks like debates are often just people with different lived experiences talking over each other.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Henry Ford said, “If there is any one secret of success it lies in the ability to get the other person&#39;s point of view and see things from their angle as well as your own.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The purely intelligent person will find this hard to grasp, because if you think there is one right answer to every problem, you insist on banging through more debate until the other side agrees with you.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It takes smarts to accept that for most problems in the world, the “right” answer is the one that best promotes your individual wellbeing &lt;em>;and&lt;/em>; fits your experience of how the world works. And since everyone has different needs and experiences, the only way to move forward and get things done is to tolerate and work with some views even when you disagree with them.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The outcome, if you can pull this off, is the skill of getting along with people you disagree with. It is indispensable.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;An awareness that being nice doesn&#39;t mean being weak – it&#39;s actually a selfish strategy for gaining cooperation over time.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The hedge fund Long Term Capital Management was collapsing in 1998, threatening to take down all of Wall Street in its wake.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In response, 14 Wall Street banks stepped in to collectively bail the fund out and halt the panic.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every big bank participated in the bailout – except Bear Stearns, whose CEO Jimmy Cayne allegedly responded, “No fucking way,” to the request.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ten years later, Bear Stearns itself teetered on the edge. And guess how many other Wall Street banks were willing to lend Jimmy Cayne a hand?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Charlie Munger once pointed out that Benjamin Franklin didn&#39;t say honesty is the best morals – he said it&#39;s the best &lt;em>;policy&lt;/em>;. It&#39;s what&#39;s going to &lt;em>;help&lt;/em>; &lt;em>;you, and put you in the best position, earning you the most money&lt;/em>;, in the long run.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There&#39;s a corollary there with kindness.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are two reasons to be kind to everyone. One is moral, the other is selfish. Morally, you should do it because you&#39;re empathetic. Selfishly, you should do it because it&#39;s easy to underestimate how many people you may eventually rely on to help you, and you&#39;ll only gain their cooperation if you remain in their good graces.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Multi-disciplinary thinking&lt;/strong>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I serve on the board of directors of Markel. Someone recently asked me what I&#39;ve learned from Markel&#39;s CEO Tom Gayner – truly one of the most accomplished investors of recent decades.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My response is that no matter what we&#39;re talking about, Tom has a perfect analogy from something totally unrelated.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If we&#39;re talking about insurance reserves, Tom will say something like, “You know, this reminds me of that scene from the &lt;em>;Sound of Music&lt;/em>; …”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If we&#39;re talking about market valuations, Tom might say, “It&#39;s kind of like Winston Churchill used to say …”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In each case, the analogy gets right to the heart of the topic at hand.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is more than mere entertaining chat. I think Tom is a good investor because he understands how the world works – connecting dots between various fields – which is so much broader than just understanding finance. People who understand finance might be intelligent, but understanding how the world works requires smarts.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Too many intelligent people become siloed in their field, oblivious to how interconnected the world is.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;True independent thinking.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kevin Kelly has this great idea that you&#39;re only thinking independently if your views on certain topics can&#39;t be predicted from your views on other topics.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many views can be predicted, because true independent thinking is so rare.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tell me your views on immigration and I can probably guess your views on abortion.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tell me who you voted for president and I can probably guess whether you think today&#39;s economy is strong or weak.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When your views on certain topics can be predicted from unrelated statements, there&#39;s a good chance you&#39;ve outsourced part of your thinking to tribal affiliations.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;True independent thinking is rare because most people would rather be comfortable than right, and there is comfort in knowing you are a good-standing member of your tribe. Thinking independently also doesn&#39;t mean you&#39;re right, because the crowd is usually pretty close to accurate. Going against the tribe can also be interpreted as arrogance – suddenly you might look like Jimmy Cayne.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But poet Rudyard Kipling writes, “If you can talk with crowds and keep your virtue, Or walk with Kings, nor lose the common touch,” you&#39;re on your way to greatness. One way to test that is whether there are people who you agree with on some topics but not others. If there is someone whose views you agree with on every topic, be careful. If there is someone whose views you disagree with on every topic, be even more careful.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I think my own dog – who is such a good girl – is crazy half the time, so I shudder when people can&#39;t find any faults in their favorite politician or investing guru.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Recognizing that the best story wins.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not the best answer. Not the accurate answer. Not the answer people need to hear. The winner is just whoever gets people to pay attention and nod their heads in agreement.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you&#39;re merely intelligent, you might focus all of your effort on finding precise truth. If you&#39;re smart, you&#39;ll focus just as much effort on delivering an effective message around that truth, realizing that the most powerful truth does no good if you can&#39;t get people to pay attention to it.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A doctor once told me there&#39;s a difference between an expert in medicine and an expert in healthcare.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An expert in medicine knows all the right answers out of the textbook. They can diagnose with precision and are up to date on all the latest treatments.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An expert in healthcare understands that medicine from the patient&#39;s view is intimidating, confusing, expensive, and time-consuming. Nothing you diagnose or prescribe matters until you&#39;ve addressed that reality with patients, because even a perfect solution makes no difference to the patient who doesn&#39;t follow it.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It&#39;s similar in investing. Hedge fund manager Kyle Bass summed this up well, saying: “It&#39;s easy to maintain conviction. It&#39;s harder to maintain investors.” The most successful investors tend to be expert communicators, because you have to compel your investors to stick with you during inevitable times of underperformance. Buffett. Sequoia. Even Vanguard; they are so skilled – intentionally so – at delivering an effective message beyond the numbers.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Warren Buffett – amazing writer.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Charlie Munger – amazing writer.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Seth Klarman – amazing writer.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;John Bogle – amazing writer.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Joel Greenblatt – amazing writer.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Howard Marks – amazing writer.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I don&#39;t think this is a coincidence. These investors&#39; ability to write let them effectively tell their story, set expectations, and reassure investors. That made their investors more likely to stick around when times got rocky.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It&#39;s hard to teach that. Storytelling is a soft, emotional skill. It&#39;s not found in intelligence. It&#39;s found in smarts.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 22 Aug 2023 12:49:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/intelligent-vs-smart/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/intelligent-vs-smart/</guid></item><item><title> A Few Stories About Big Decisions</title><description> &lt;p>;In 1964, Warren Buffett owned shares in an old industry company with fading prospects.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The company&#39;s CEO viewed Buffett&#39;s purchase as a threat to his job security, and offered to buy the shares back at a premium. Buffett was eager to sell, tired of watching the business struggle.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The two struck a deal: The company would buy all of Buffett&#39;s stock at $11 1/2 per share.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Buffett received a letter shortly after formalizing the deal. The company would still buy all of his stock, but at $11 3/8 per share.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It really burned me up,” Buffett recalled. “You know, this guy was trying to chisel an eighth of a point from having, in effect, shaken my hand saying this was the deal.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Buffett confronted the CEO, who argued there was never a deal to begin with. That made him even more incensed.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So rather than selling, Buffett began buying as much of the stock as he could.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He eventually purchased more than a third of the company.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Biographer Alice Schroeder writes that, above all, Buffett&#39;s motivation for buying more of the company&#39;s stock was to stick it to the CEO who tried to screw him out of twelve cents per share.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The company – Berkshire Hathaway – became Buffett&#39;s masterpiece.&lt;/p>; &lt;hr />; &lt;p>;A similar story: In 1955, recent college graduate Morris Chang was offered two jobs: One at Ford for a salary of $479 a month, and one at electrical company Sylvania for $480 a month.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ford seemed like the better opportunity, but Chang asked the recruiters to match his Sylvania offer – a mere &lt;em>;$1 a month&lt;/em>; more.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ford declined. So Chang took the job at Sylvania, where he learned about – and became an expert in – the growing field of transistors and microchips.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chang eventually founded Taiwan Semiconductor, which today is worth almost half a trillion dollars and produces 60% of the world&#39;s chips.&lt;/p>; &lt;hr />; &lt;p>;Henry Ford knew the automobile would change the world. The rest of the world wasn&#39;t so sure. In the early 1900s, cars looked like noisy toys for rich people.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But toys are fun, so the one thing the public was crazy about was car racing.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ford had no interest in race cars – his vision was to build a cheap, quality car for the masses.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But knowing that he needed to win over both investors and the public, he built the best race car in the world, and in 1902 it beat the reigning champion.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“That was my first race, and it brought advertising of the only kind that people cared to read,” Ford wrote. He became known nationwide.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The attention was enough to raise money from investors, and Ford Motor Company was formed eight months later.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Everything is sales.&lt;/p>; &lt;hr />; &lt;p>;Actress Gloria Swanson turned down a $1 million movie contract in 1927.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The studio was stunned, and asked why she balked.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I would have been the second or third person in movie history to sign a million-dollar contract, but I was the very first to turn one down,” she said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That remark made headlines and helped her become even more famous, which, I assume, was the point.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It&#39;s the most extreme example of the career advice, “Don&#39;t try to be the best. Be the only.”&lt;/p>; &lt;hr />; &lt;p>;As the late author Christopher Hitchens battled esophageal cancer, the brutal side effects of chemotherapy seemed like, as Dr. Peter Attia wrote, “fair trade for a few more years of useful life.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But as Hitchens neared the end, he wrote:&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;I lay for days on end, trying in vain to postpone the moment when I would have to swallow. Every time I did swallow, a hellish tide of pain would flow up my throat, culminating in what felt like a mule kick in the small of my back. … And then I had an unprompted rogue thought: If I had been told about all this in advance, would I have opted for the treatment?&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;hr />; &lt;p>;JFK and Jackie Kennedy didn&#39;t have a great relationship. In 1955, two years after their marriage, Jack told his father, Joe Kennedy, he wanted a divorce.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Joe responded: “You&#39;re out of your mind. You&#39;re going to be president someday. This would ruin everything. Divorce is impossible.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jack reiterated that he and Jackie weren&#39;t happy.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;His father shot back: “Can&#39;t you get it into your head that it&#39;s not important what you really are? The only important thing is what people think you are!”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The marriage endured.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;Everything is sales.&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;hr />; &lt;p>;Sugar, milk, and eggs were all rationed during World War II. Many food companies adapted to use different, often lower-quality, ingredients to get by.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;See&#39;s Candy was so obsessed with quality that it refused to lower its standards. One holiday season it closed down and put signs in its store that read, “Sold out. Buy war bonds for Christmas.”&lt;/p>; &lt;hr />; &lt;p>;America&#39;s decision to invade Northern Africa in November 1942 was extremely unpopular, even among President Roosevelt&#39;s closest advisors. By almost every account, the troops weren&#39;t ready, the planning was rushed, and the missions too ambitious. The top generals saw no downside to waiting a few more months. Dwight Eisenhower, then a general, predicted that Roosevelt&#39;s hasty order to invade would become “the blackest day in history.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The invasion worked. But looking back after the war, the president&#39;s advisors wondered why he was in such a hurry.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One explanation was that the American people were antsy for something – anything – to happen after Pearl Harbor and Germany&#39;s declaration of war. Roosevelt&#39;s own son wrote him a letter saying he and his fellow soldiers were sitting around and “not having any fun … just waiting our turn.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Scratching those itches may have superseded military strategy.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;George Marshall, then Army chief of staff, said after the war: “The leader in a democracy has to keep the people entertained. That may sound like the wrong word, but it conveys the thought.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most decisions aren&#39;t made on a spreadsheet, where you just add up the numbers and a rational answer pops out. There&#39;s a human element that&#39;s hard to quantify, hard to explain, and can seem detached from the original goal, yet carries the most influence.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 09 Aug 2023 12:15:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/a-few-stories-about-big-decisions/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/a-few-stories-about-big-decisions/</guid></item><item><title> The End of the Incandescent Light Bulb: A Failure of Technology and Markets</title><description> &lt;p>;The Biden administration recently enforced a ban on the sale of traditional incandescent light bulbs, completing a years-long phase out rooted in 2007 legislation.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While more energy efficient LED bulbs will save consumers money on utility bills and reduce carbon emissions, in some ways this transition represents a failure of technology and markets.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Incandescent bulbs have villainous qualities from a sustainability standpoint, wasting large amounts of energy as heat. However, they provide warmer, more attractive light that is easier on the eyes. Fluorescent and early LED bulbs never measured up in terms of quality and appeal for consumers.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Markets failed to spur innovations that resolved this dilemma – a better lightbulb aligning sustainability and desirability. So now government regulation became the lever to force change, taking away consumer choice.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/unnamed-fd7d8f.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;unnamed-fd7d8f.jpg&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Critics will see this as unwarranted government overreach into personal freedoms and decisions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are areas like large-scale clean energy projects where government involvement is warranted given capital requirements. But the inability of businesses to create a universally appealing energy efficient lightbulb represents a failure of technology and the free market.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Rather than heavy-handed regulation, solutions that better align business incentives with sustainability are needed.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Perhaps carbon pricing or rebates for energy efficient bulbs would have organically spurred the desired innovations. The free market has succeeded in driving innovations that align business incentives and consumer desires in other domains, such as carpooling and ridesharing. Companies like Uber, Lyft and Waze have created platforms that reduce traffic, pollution and parking demand while allowing the companies to profit from fees and advertising revenue generated through the apps.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Through a combination of technology improvements (ie. GPS) and savvy marketing, carpooling and ride-sharing is not seen as a sacrifice for consumers, or mandated by the government, but rather a superior product that makes life easier. Similar win-win solutions should have emerged organically for lightbulbs without needing a government ban.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This missed opportunity highlights the need for creative solutions that don&#39;t rely solely on government sticks to drive change.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The transition to more sustainable products should feel like an upgrade for consumers, not a sacrifice.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More work is required to better align consumer desires, business interests and societal needs. True innovations marry all three.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 07 Aug 2023 18:20:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/the-end-of-the-incandescent-light-bulb-a-failure-of-technology-and-markets/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/the-end-of-the-incandescent-light-bulb-a-failure-of-technology-and-markets/</guid></item><item><title> How to Read: Lots of Inputs and a Strong Filter</title><description> &lt;p>;My reading strategy is to start as many books as I can but finish few of them.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Years ago I heard Charlie Munger say “Most books I don&#39;t read past the first chapter. I&#39;m not burdened by bad books,” and it stuck with me.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reading is a chore if you insist on finishing every book you begin, because the majority of books are either a) adequately summarized in the introduction, b) not for you, or c) not for anyone.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Slogging through to the last page of these books – a habit likely formed early in school – can turn reading into the equivalent of a 10-hour work meeting where nothing gets done and everyone is bored. And once you see reading through that lens, your willingness to pick up another book wanes.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Which, of course, is tragic. “The man who doesn&#39;t read good books has no advantage over the man who can&#39;t read them,” said Mark Twain.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every smart person I know is a voracious reader who also says “every smart person I know is a voracious reader.” There are so few exceptions to this rule it&#39;s astounding. College tuition at $25,000 a year comes out to roughly $100 per lecture. Good books – sometimes written by the same professor – can be purchased for fifteen bucks and can offer multiple times as much life-changing insight.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The conflict between these two – most books don&#39;t need to be read to the end, but some books can change your life – means you need two things to get a lot out of reading: &lt;strong>;Lots of inputs and a strong filter&lt;/strong>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you only pick up books you know with certainty you&#39;re going to like you&#39;ll confine yourself to reading the same authors on the same topics. It gives fresh oxygen to confirmation bias and limits your ability to connect the dots between different fields and different cultures. It&#39;s better to have a low bar in what books you&#39;re willing to try, and even the faintest tickle of interest should be enough to make the cut. Kindle samples are free, so excuses are minimal.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Once you&#39;ve flooded your desk with inputs, you have to bring out the filter.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It should be ruthless, taking no prisoners and offering no mercy. Similar to dating, a book you&#39;re not into after 10 minutes of attention has little chance of a happy ending. Slam it shut and move on. You&#39;re not a failure if you quit a book after three pages anymore than if you reject the proposition of a 10-hour date with someone you just met who annoys you. Lots of fish in the sea.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This applies to more than reading books. It&#39;s true for all kinds of data, research, conversation, and learning. Without flooding your brain with inputs you&#39;ll be stuck in the tiny world of what you&#39;ve personally experienced. But without a strong filter you&#39;ll be overwhelmed with choice and paralyzed by inaction.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A good reading filter is more art than science. You&#39;ll have to find one that works for you. The bigger point is that the highest odds of finding the right piece of information comes from inundating yourself with information but very quickly being able to say, “that ain&#39;t it.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 03 Aug 2023 07:57:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/how-to-read-lots-of-inputs-and-a-strong-filter/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/how-to-read-lots-of-inputs-and-a-strong-filter/</guid></item></channel></rss>