<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>合作基金</title><description>Collab Fund 是企业家推动世界前进的主要资金来源。</description><link/> https://collabfund.com<atom:link href="https://collabfund.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 14:45:30 -0400</pubDate><lastbuilddate> 2023 年 6 月 28 日星期三 14:45:30 -0400</lastbuilddate><generator>站点叶</generator><item><title>几个问题</title><description>&lt;p>;我钦佩谁的生活却暗自悲惨？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我相信什么是真实的，只是因为相信它使我在我的部落中享有良好的声誉？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我目前的哪一个如果我由不同的父母抚养长大，价值观会有所不同吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我最相信但证据最少的东西是什么？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;谁有正确的答案，但我因为他们沟通不好而被忽视？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;谁充满了野心，但我因为他们沟通良好而关注？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我认为什么是野心（一个好的沟通者）？特质），但实际上是嫉妒（可怕的嫉妒）？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我自己有时对别人做的事情让我恼火吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我的怀旧有多少是错误的或不完整的记忆过去？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在你的职业中，无论你变得多么聪明，有什么是不可能知道的？大卫·多伊奇说：“要注意预测和预言之间的区别。预言旨在了解无法得知的事情。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我担心的这件事实际上是一个问题，还是我在寻找需要担心的问题，因为它们让我感觉自己处于掌控之中？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; >; &lt;p>;在我的领域中，我认为什么是法则（始终有效），但实际上只是一条规则（有时有效）？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我认为什么是普遍真理，但实际上只是我自己文化所特有的规范？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;什么是上一代人的真实情况，但现在不再如此，谁还坚持这个古老的事实？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;什么是部分真实的，但我如此绝对地相信它，并如此认真地对待它，以至于我把它变成了一种危险的信念？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;今天我的生活中是否有一些事情进展顺利，让我回顾起来并希望自己拥有在我领先的时候退出？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我的生活中是否有一些事情我认为我“充满热情”或“专注”，但实际上我只是沉迷于它？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我是否会花更多的时间来捍卫我已经知道的东西，而不是尝试学习新的东西？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我生活中是否有一些人我认为是善良和富有同情心的，但他们实际上只是太害羞而不敢告诉我残酷的事实？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果 Instagram 是对人们生活的诚实反映，而不是精心策划的精彩片段，它会是什么样子？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我是否尽可能友善，而不仅仅是我需要有多好？&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 14:24:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/a-few-questions/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/a-few-questions/</guid></item><item><title>为什么你相信你所做的事情</title><description>&lt;p>;我记得几年前读过一篇文章，讲述也门的一位父亲因饥饿失去了一个儿子，结果又让另一个孩子患上了重病。绝望之下，他向部落长老求助，长老们推荐了一种民间疗法：将一根燃烧的棍子插入病童的胸口以排出疾病。父亲同意了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当被问及这个可怕的过程时，父亲&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2018/10/26/world/middleeast/saudi-arabia- war-yemen.html&quot;>;说：&lt;/a>;“人们说把他烧在体内就没事了。当你没有钱，你儿子病了，你就会相信任何事情。”&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&lt;em>;当你没有钱，而你的儿子病了，你就会相信任何事情。&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是一个非常有力的声明，它的某些版本适用于每个人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是一个普遍的现实：你相信什么是真实的，取决于你希望它是真实的程度。某件事越能帮助你应对不确定性，你相信它是真的的门槛就越低。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;永远都是这样。丹尼尔·笛福 (Daniel Defoe) 在 1722 年描述伦敦大瘟疫时写道：“人们比以往任何时候都更加沉迷于预言、占星术、梦境和老太太的故事。”当瘟疫杀死了四分之一的邻居时，你会相信任何能给你带来希望的东西。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Visa 创始人 Dee Hock 曾经说过：“我们生来就拥有几乎无限的相信事物的能力，因为这些信念对我们持有来说是有利的，而不是因为它们与事实有一点关系。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;想想那些策略与他们的身份如此紧密相关的投资者，当它不再起作用时，他们就无法放手.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;或者是企业如此迫切地想要做好，却忽视了所有不好的方面。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;查理·芒格 &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamesclear.com/great-查理芒格的演讲/人类误判心理学&quot;>;曾经说过&lt;/a>;：&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;如果你打开电视，你会发现最明显的罪犯的母亲那个人能诊断出来，他们都认为他们的儿子是无辜的。现实太痛苦而难以忍受，所以你只能扭曲它，直到它可以忍受为止。&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;即使是看似硬科学的东西也属于这一类。法律界有一个叫做吉布森定律的东西，它规定：“对于每个博士学位，都有一个平等且相反的博士学位。”无论你想提出什么论点，你都可以找到一位合格的专家证人，他愿意在宣誓后以每小时 500 美元的价格出庭作证。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人们可以被引导去相信并捍卫几乎任何事情，因为信仰的目标通常不是发现真相，而是为了证明过去的行为是合理的，或者保护你的声誉，或者在缺乏希望时提供希望，或者最大化你的收入，或者向其他人表明你属于这个部落。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此，您相信自己所做的事情有一个原因：信念的吸引力可能会掩盖其真实性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;信念往往形成的其他几个原因：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;过去事件的记忆被过滤。你保留有意义的内容，扔掉令人困惑的细节。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;20 世纪 40 年代末，两位心理学家——戈登·奥尔波特 (Gordon Allport) 和利奥·波兹曼 (Leo Postman)——提出了他们所谓的“记忆中的平整和锐化效应”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事情是这样的：在任何重大事件中——车祸、恐怖袭击、经济衰退、流行病等——你经历和观察到的变量实际上可能有数百万个。你看到人们的情绪，听到不同的意见，读到不同的观点。你不可能记住所有的细节；实在是太多了。因此，在你的回忆中，你会强调一些记忆（锐化）并丢弃其他记忆（平整）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人们倾向于锐化那些构成一个好故事并符合他们现有观点的细节，并平整那些令人困惑、痛苦的细节。 ，或与预先存在的信念相矛盾。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此，我们有一个信念生成系统：你认为正确的东西在很大程度上基于你所经历的事情，并且你记得你的经历中的哪些部分使好故事，证实刻板印象，并将其他经历之间的点联系起来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;想想 2008 年金融危机有多么复杂。数十亿人同时做出复杂、情绪化的决定。没有人能够追踪一切。因此，事后看来，人们倾向于相信对他们来说有意义的简单叙述——美联储毁了经济，救助不公平，财富被摧毁。所有这些都可能是真实的并且被一个人相信，但被另一个经历过相同经济但记得不同细节的人反对。也许美联储拯救了经济，救助是最好的选择，也是千载难逢的买入机会。取决于你记得什么。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;危险的是，基于经验的信念似乎是基于证据的。但是，当我们对复杂世界的观察不知所措时，我们会挑选最有吸引力的证据来安抚我们简单、热爱故事的头脑。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;欺骗自己相信要容易得多说谎胜过承认错误。改变你的想法比应有的情况更罕见，这导致我们坚持错误的信念。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;物理学家 Max Tegmark 在《这会让你变得更聪明》一书中写道：&lt; /p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;科学生活方式的核心是在面对与自己观点不符的信息时改变想法，避免智力惯性，但我们很多人却称赞那些顽固坚持自己观点的领导者“坚强”。 ”伟大的物理学家理查德·费曼将“对专家的不信任”誉为科学的基石，但从众心理和对权威人物的迷信却普遍存在。逻辑构成了科学推理的基础，但一厢情愿的想法、非理性的恐惧和其他认知偏见常常主导决策。&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;你可以同意那里写的每一个字，但仍然很难改变你的想法 –或者认真对待那些这样做的人——原因有两个。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第一，当你改变主意时，你会觉得你为建立以前的信念而付出的所有艰苦努力都被浪费了。即使是现实带来的一点痛苦也足以说服你坚持原来的信念。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第二，当你改变主意，从一种信念转向另一种信念时，可能很难接受新的信念认真对待信仰——改变信仰证明新的信仰可能是短暂的，尤其是在其他人眼中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;两者都认识到一个重要的事实：信仰不仅与我们所知道的有关，而且与我们所知道的有关。它们是社会信号，提供有关我们如何建立信仰、对自己智力的信心以及向他人传递可靠事实的能力的线索。奇怪的是，这些信号可能是违反直觉的：我们应该想要一个愿意改变主意的专家，但我们真正想要的是一个足够自信、永远不必这样做的人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;很多时候，我们“对真相不感兴趣——我们感兴趣的是消除不确定性，而这一事实本身就让我们相信与现实无关的事情。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 21 Jun 2023 13:58:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/why-you- believe-the-things-you-do/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/why-you- believe-the-things-you-do/</guid></item><item><title>可持续材料的演变：值得关注的六大趋势</title><description>&lt;p>;可持续材料——源自可再生资源而不是化石燃料的材料——为地球和所有以地球为家园的人们打造更光明、更健康的未来奠定了基础。它们也是我们气候基金的核心关注点，&lt;a href=&quot;https://collabfund.com/blog/collab-sos-a-new-fund-and-a-call-to-action/&quot;>;协作SOS&lt;/a>;，涵盖从纺织品和生物塑料到绿色化学品和建筑材料的所有领域。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自我们推出该基金以来，该行业迅速发展，以满足快速变化的世界的需求。监管顺风和大公司的买入已被资本成本上升和投资者的恐慌所抵消。然而，科学突破——包括基于人工智能的建模的改进以及可再生能源和基因编辑成本的下降——加速了进展并开辟了扩大规模的新途径。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以下是一些主要趋势近几个月我们注意到：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;1.原料多样化公司正在放弃糖等精炼原料，并在生产有价值的材料时日益多样化其原料选择。现在，我们发现越来越多的公司使用农作物废弃物、食品废弃物、织物废弃物、城市废弃物以及二氧化碳或甲烷气体废弃物（例如工业燃烧产生的烟气或废水处理厂产生的气体）。这些原料不仅成本通常较低，而且这些重新设计的工作流程通常可以相对减少温室气体排放和土地使用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;2.结合生物学和绿色化学公司正在不断发展，不再尝试纯粹通过发酵生产产品。相反，他们利用大自然提供的分子，利用生物宿主优化最佳分子的生产，然后利用化学来产生最终目标。这种方法通常会降低发酵和下游加工的成本，并成倍增加可能的化学目标和应用的数量。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;3.优化下游加工成本&lt;/strong>; 在当前资本成本高昂的环境下，企业更加注重成本优化。这涉及寻找丰富且负担得起的原料并简化下游流程，这些流程通常是能源密集型且产量有限的。通过正面解决这些成本驱动因素，可持续材料公司可以增强竞争力并为广泛采用铺平道路。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;4.倡导成分胜过品牌&lt;/strong>; 公司更注重 B2B 进入市场策略，而不是创建自己的消费品牌。在 Collab，我们看到通过构建端到端流程（或尽可能接近）来捕获尽可能多的垂直价值具有很大的价值。然而，与垂直品牌相比，团队技能，尤其是在早期阶段，通常更适合创造原料。而且这种策略可以实现更快的扩展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;5.探索可调材料公司不再只提供一种材料。如今，他们有能力根据特定特性调整材料。这通常是通过探索潜在的酶活性和创新的绿色化学平台来完成的。我们在生产替代皮革和生产织物处理剂（例如用于防水的 PFAS 替代品）的公司中尤其看到了这一点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;6.成熟的无细胞系统和应用&lt;/strong>; 无细胞技术正在迅速成熟，这种技术允许生物反应在活细胞的范围之外发生。通过价格合理、新颖且可调节的树脂来延长酶的寿命和稳定性，公司现在可以将该技术应用于生产可持续材料和化学品。这些系统曾经主要用于制药，现在服务于更广泛的应用，包括利用二氧化碳制造纤维、回收难以加工的塑料以及合成复杂的化学品。无细胞系统允许精确调节、优化和提高生物合成途径的产量，并具有创造具有独特、定制特性的材料的额外能力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该领域正在经历一个变革时期，其特点是快速进步和不断发展策略。第一波生物材料从未完全达到炒作的效果，但我们对这群最新创新者的未来非常乐观。上述趋势凸显了该行业创新和应对关键挑战的决心。作为更可持续未来的投资者和倡导者，我们必须继续监控这些趋势并与引领创新的公司合作。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 08:23:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/sustainable-materials-six-trends/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/sustainable-materials-six-trends/</guid></item><item><title>题目：预测不确定时期的极端天气</title><description>&lt;p>;极端天气事件比以往任何时候都更加频繁和严重。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022 年，气候驱动的天气事件在全球范围内造成了 115B 美元的保险财务损失，比之前 10 年的平均水平高出惊人的 42% .&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;气候灾害（飓风、气旋、洪水、野火和干旱）激增带来的不确定性带来了一个重大问题：如果保险公司、企业和政府无法预测与气候相关的破坏性威胁，他们无法做出明智的决策来保护自己的资产。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于金融服务行业和保险市场以及他们所服务的客户来说，这是一个重大问题，也是机遇。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/unnamed-011cd1.png&quot; alt=&quot;unnamed-011cd1.png&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现有的气候风险预测解决方案，例如&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rms.com/&quot;>;穆迪 RMS&lt;/a>;，但大多数都依赖于历史数据。这些模型根据“历史损失率”（给定时期内的损失总价值除以同一时期的风险总额）进行推断，试图预测未来。但气候变化正在改变天气事件的频率和强度，使得历史推断不足。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;预测未来气候变化的模型基于一系列假设和不确定性，很难准确预测捕捉大气、海洋和陆地表面之间所有复杂的相互作用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这就是 &lt;a href=&quot;https://reask.earth/&quot;>;Reask&lt;/a>; 的用武之地。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这就是 &lt;a href=&quot;https://reask.earth/&quot;>;Reask&lt;/a>; 的用武之地。 p>; &lt;p>;由 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/thomasloridan/&quot;>;Thomas Loridan &lt;/a>; 和 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/ 领导in/jamie-rodney-2b4a2782/&quot;>;Jamie Rodney&lt;/a>; 以及由先驱数学家、气象学家和计算机科学家组成的团队，Reask 避开了历史损失率外推法，转而采用自下而上的物理天气模型——使用根据当前条件和物理定律预测天气的数学模型。这些模型以温度、湿度、风速和风向、大气压力等各种大气参数作为输入，并应用物理学原理来模拟天气随时间的演变。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reask 的秘密武器是一组利用人工智能模拟的专有天气模型，可将风险因素分配到平方公里。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种方法有几个好处：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;精度&lt;/strong>;：Reask直接计算风速等高度准确的变量，并捕获风险的完整分布，超越简单化的风险评分，而是让客户得出价格。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;清晰度&lt;/strong>;：Reask始终使用物理变量来评估风险。创建的任何输出都可以直接与已知的大气系统物理现象相关，而不是纯粹的统计数据。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;全球&lt;/strong>;：Reask 模型本质上是全球性的，捕捉了气候的物理现象，并且首次为客户提供了一种评估如何在金融资产投资组合中分散和管理气候风险的方法。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reask 的 API 可用于为 Swiss 等传统保险和再保险公司提供支持Re，以及新时代专注于气候的保险公司，例如 &lt;a href=&quot;https://ourkettle.com/&quot;>;Kettle&lt;/a>; 和 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.arbol。 io/&quot;>;Arbol&lt;/a>; 更有效地承保风险。 &lt;a href=&quot;https://descartesunderwriting.com/&quot;>;笛卡尔&lt;/a>;等公司还可以使用这些数据来开发参数保险产品，以便为受破坏性天气事件影响的人们提供快速救济。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，模型的特殊性和 Reask 预测能力的全球性使更广泛的金融机构和大型资产持有者能够了解其整个投资组合面临的风险，以便他们能够保护自己、员工和更广泛的人。经济应对即将到来的灾难。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随着美国飓风季节的临近，我们很高兴看到 Reask 的解决方案可用，并且我们很高兴能够支持 Reask，因为我们共同领导了他们的种子轮融资与我们在 Mastry Ventures 的朋友一起。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;您可以&lt;a href=&quot;https://reask.earth/news/&quot;>;此处&lt;/a>;关注公司的进展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而且，如果您正在研究应对气候变化的方法，我们希望收到您的来信！&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 15 Jun 2023 09:15:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/reask-predicting-extreme-weather-in-uncertain-times/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/reask-predicting-extreme-weather-in-uncertain-times/</guid></item><item><title>复合乐观情绪</title><description>&lt;p>;让我分享一些关于乐观的理论，以及为什么进展如此容易被低估。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我将分四个部分进行解释。&lt;/p>; &lt;hr />; &lt;p>;哥斯达黎加的一条鳄鱼&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbsnews.com/news/crocodile-virgin-birth-costa-rica/&quot;>;最近被发现怀孕了&lt;/a>;——这一切都是她自己做的，没有男性的帮助。她的胎儿与她的基因有 99.99% 相同。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是第一个有记录的鳄鱼无性繁殖的案例。其他一些动物（一些鸟类和蛇）也能做到这一点，但极其罕见。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是有充分理由的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大约 100 年前，一位名叫赫尔曼·穆勒提出了一个最终被称为“穆勒棘轮”的理论。报告称，当没有基因重组时，危险的突变往往会堆积起来，最终可能导致物种灭绝。在缺乏多样性的情况下——雄性和雌性混合基因——危险的突变往往会持续存在，因为没有新的、更好的变异来与基因库中的坏东西竞争。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这就是为什么如此很少有物种可以无性繁殖。&lt;/p>; &lt;hr />; &lt;p>;精彩&lt;em>;创始人&lt;/em>;播客的大卫·森拉&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PI6QcwnfNe8&amp;amp ;ab_channel=Acquired&quot;>;最近&lt;/a>;讲了一个关于史蒂夫·乔布斯的故事：&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;史蒂夫20多岁，他去见了[宝丽来创始人]埃德温·兰德。史蒂夫说，“拜访埃德温·兰德就像参观神社一样……他是我的英雄。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;杰夫·贝索斯从萨姆·沃尔顿那里汲取了很多想法。史蒂夫和杰夫都从索尼那里汲取了很多想法。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;你总是会发现这些人，“哦，我以为这是史蒂夫·乔布斯的想法。”不，不。这是[索尼创始人]盛田昭夫的想法，或者是埃德温·兰德的想法。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;观看史蒂夫·乔布斯的演讲，他说：“我们正在技术与人文学科的交叉点上进行建设。”埃德温·兰德 (Edwin Land) 说过这句话！&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果不研究前辈，向他们学习并钦佩他们，你永远不会找到任何达到职业顶峰的人。&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;这是千真万确的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;托马斯·爱迪生从迈克尔·法拉第那里汲取了很多想法。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;比尔·盖茨从计算机发明家亨利·爱德华兹·罗伯茨那里汲取了很多想法。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沃伦·巴菲特向本·格雷厄姆和菲尔·费舍尔学习。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;埃德温·兰德本人深受哈佛大学物理学教授乔治·惠尔赖特 (George Wheelwright) 的影响，他 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www .nytimes.com/2001/03/03/business/gw-wheelwright-iii-97-dies-co-Founder-of-polroid.html&quot;>;成为宝丽来联合创始人&lt;/a>;。&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;问题是：乔治·惠尔赖特 (George Wheelwright) 知道他会影响埃德温·兰德 (Edwin Land)，而埃德温·兰德 (Edwin Land) 又会影响史蒂夫·乔布斯 (Steve Jobs)，而史蒂夫·乔布斯 (Steve Jobs) 会设计出一款供 25 亿人使用的手机吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;去世的迈克尔·法拉第 (Michael Faraday) 知道吗？ 1867 年，您知道他的想法将直接影响灯泡，从而有效地创造了从现代电网到夜生活的一切事物吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本·格雷厄姆知道他 1950 年代的金融课程将带来 45,000 名学生吗？每年长途跋涉去奥马哈听他的学生演讲？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然不是。很难知道一个想法、一项发明或一种哲学会影响什么，以及受其影响的人会继续创造什么。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Visa 创始人 Dee Hock 说：“一本书远远超出了作者所写的内容；它是你能想象和读懂的一切。”作者可能会写一些枯燥或明显的东西，但它可以激励读者去做一些令人难以置信的事情。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;想法复合。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;发明复合。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;教育化合物。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一件小事可以成长为一件大事，而且速度比大多数人意识到的要快。&lt;/p>; &lt;hr />; &lt;p>;科学作家马特·里德利说，大多数创新发生在几种不同的想法时“ &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ted.com/talks/matt_ridley_when_ideas_have_sex&quot;>;做爱&lt;/a>;。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大多数新想法和发明本身都相当平淡。但当你将其中的几种混合在一起时，你就能获得魔法。塑料很棒。电子产品很整洁。金属很特别。但以正确的方式将它们混合在一起，你就会得到一部 iPhone，这简直就是魔法。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;正是这些想法的结合、结合和融合，创造了现代世界。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与我们的鳄鱼朋友最近完成的过程相反。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ridley 在他的《理性乐观主义者》一书中解释了重组的好处：&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;一种生物中发生的突变可以与另一种生物中发生的突变联手。如果微生物没有在数十亿年前开始交换基因，而动物也没有通过性行为继续交换基因，那么所有形成眼睛的基因就永远不可能聚集在一只动物身上；也不是制造腿、神经或大脑的基因。每个突变都会在自己的谱系中保持孤立，无法发现协同作用的乐趣。&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;里德利曾经进一步解释过这一点：&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;我不是对某些群体的智商是否高于其他群体的争论感兴趣。这是完全无关的。与社会相关的是人们如何很好地交流他们的想法，以及他们的合作如何，而不是个人有多聪明。&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;小想法混合并复合成大想法 - 这就是真正驱动世界的是什么。&lt;/p>; &lt;hr />; &lt;p>;我认为悲观主义比乐观主义更容易、更普遍的部分原因是复合增长并不直观。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这很难想象一下，比如说，我们的收入在接下来的几代人中翻一番。这似乎是一个巨大的飞跃，就像我们必须煮沸海洋才能完成它。但如果 30 年内平均收入翻一番，每年增长率约为 2.3%。这一点也不疯狂。这实际上是完全可以实现的。它一开始就显得如此雄心勃勃，因为复合增长很容易被低估。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果你看看长期复合的最终结果，你会发现这是令人震惊的。但实现这一目标所需要的只是长期的一点点增量增长。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所有进步都是如此。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;技术进步很容易被低估，因为它是如此之大。例如，一个发明宝丽来胶片的人的哲学如何继续启发 iPhone，这是违反直觉的。或者 18 世纪的物理学家如何编写一本笔记本，为现代电气系统奠定基础。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果您认为进步是由个人天才驱动的，那么当然很难想象未来情况会好很多，因为没有人比平均水平聪明几个数量级。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是当你把它看作一个人提出一个小想法，另一个人复制这个想法并稍微调整它时，另一个人接受了这种洞察力并对其进行了一些操作，另一个人则接受了该产品并将其与其他东西相结合 - 增量的、微小的部分、小想法混合、连接、融合、变异和复合在一起 - 它突然变得更容易想象。&lt;/p >;</description><pubDate> Tue, 13 Jun 2023 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/compounding-optimism/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/compounding-optimism/</guid></item><item><title>巴西硅谷</title><description>&lt;p>;对于全球科技公司和创业生态系统来说，今年是非常困难的一年。然而，硅谷的巴西成功地揭示了巴西的创新机会以及在该国建设和投资的人们的承诺。拉丁美洲继续成为充满活力的创新景观，而巴西正在迅速确立其中心地位。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;西蒙·罗德里格斯 &lt;a href=&quot;https://technopoly.substack.com/p/is- brazil-losing-its-lead&quot;>;将这种观点概括为&lt;/a>;：“问任何人，巴西都比讲西班牙语的拉丁美洲领先 X 年，其中 X 取决于回答者的国籍”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;正如 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbvaspark.com/contenido/en/news/land-of-unicorns-and-fintech-empire-this-is-sao-paulo-the-largest-innovation-ecosystem- in-latin-america/&quot;>;BBVA 报道&lt;/a>;，“圣保罗的创业生态系统价值 1080 亿美元。相比之下，&lt;a href=&quot;https://openinnovation.bbva.com/es/noticias/en-el-zocalo-del-emprendimiento-el-bum-emprendor-y-fintech-de-ciudad-de-mexico/ &quot;>;墨西哥&lt;/a>;城（拉丁美洲第二大城市）的估值为 220 亿美元。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，圣保罗在全球金融科技排名中排名第四。在“现金为王”的地区，巴西正在引领数字支付的潮流。巴西中央银行于 2020 年推出了该国的即时支付系统 PIX，该系统已拥有超过 1.3 亿注册用户（占巴西人口的 60%）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为了探索巴西的技术进步，斯坦福大学和伯克利分校的学生进行了令人难以置信的研究年度活动名为&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brazilatsiliconvalley.com/&quot;>;巴西硅谷&lt;/a>; (BSV)。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;顾名思义，其目的是在硅谷搭建桥梁巴西和硅谷之间的差距。今年，BSV 吸引了超过 600 名创始人、投资者、技术专家和政策制定者等多元化人群。我的非官方估计是，至少有 550 名与会者从巴西出发进行了长途旅行 - 至少有两趟航班，飞行时间至少为 15 小时。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这么说吧，我的 portuñol 派上了用场。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;在农业科技会议期间：&lt;em>;粮食系统的创新如何帮助解决气候危机&lt;/em>;，一名 BSV 工作人员在会议结束几分钟后使用语音转文本功能生成了 Chat-GPT 摘要。 &lt;em>;自然&lt;/em>;，该摘要是通过 Whatsapp 发送的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;今年的 BSV 阐明了几个关键投资主题：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;● &lt;strong>;垂直化软件&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;+ 金融科技&lt;/strong>;：创建和扩展本地软件解决方案有无限的机会。巴西受益于支持性政策以及中央银行在实施数字支付系统 PIX 方面的作用。 a16z合伙人Angela Strange强调，她认为每家公司都将是金融科技公司，因为金融服务将是一个横向平台。她引用了 &lt;a href=&quot;https://fu.do/es/&quot;>;Fudo&lt;/a>;*、&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uber.com/&quot;>;Uber&lt;/a>;、&lt; a href=&quot;https://www.lyft.com/&quot;>;Lyft&lt;/a>;* 等都是值得注意的例子。我们还认为 &lt;a href=&quot;https://kanastra.com.br/&quot;>;Kanastra&lt;/a>;* 是令人兴奋的金融科技基础设施建设的一个很好的例子。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;● &lt;strong>;农业科技 +气候：农业企业几乎占巴西 GDP 的 30%、该国出口的 40% 以及劳动力的 20%。巴西在技术创新和适应现有农业实践方面都处于领先气候变化举措的有利地位。投资者正在寻找基于自然的解决方案、硬件和软件游戏以及不过分依赖政府补贴的良好商业模式（例如通过&lt;a href=&quot;https://collabfund.com/blog/the-villain-test /&quot;>;小人测试&lt;/a>;）。重点关注的公司包括 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.plenty.ag/&quot;>;Plenty&lt;/a>;、&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bcdbio.com/&quot;>;BCD Bioscience&lt;/a>;*和 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.strellabiotech.com/&quot;>;Strella Biotech&lt;/a>;。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;● &lt;strong>;AI：&lt;/strong>;整个活动中引起共鸣的两个关键信息：1）我们不知道我们不知道什么，2）人工智能的变革潜力，它将影响我们生活的几乎各个方面。 Alexandr Wang and Peter Norvig called for a careful rollout of AI technology and thoughtful consideration of its global impact. Optimism and enthusiasm for technology were spread by Vinod Khosla of Khosla Ventures and Julio Vasconcellos of Atlantico. They referenced &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@vkhosla/reinventing-societal-infrastructure-with-technology-f71e0d4f2355&quot;>;Reinventing Societal Infrastructure with Technology&lt;/a>;). Check out how &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mercadodiferente.com.br/&quot;>;Diferente&lt;/a>;* is &lt;a href=&quot;https://exame.com/bussola/diferente-lanca-ia-que-cria-receitas-com-itens-da-cesta-de-organicos/&quot;>;using AI &lt;/a>;for inventory management and recipe recommendations.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;● &lt;strong>;The Fundraising Market&lt;/strong>;: A clear slowdown in the market is being felt across the board, with rounds taking longer to close, valuations compressing, and regional exit liquidity shortages. However, these conditions also make it a great time to build as we&#39;ve seen teams be laser-focused on unit economics, capital efficiency, and nailing down PMF. McKinsey launched the &lt;a href=&quot;https://latamdigitalreport.mckinsey.com/&quot;>;2023 Latin American Digital Report&lt;/a>; during the event.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One thing that was not mentioned during the conference – politics.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a Venezuelan, I found it refreshing to see Brazilians come together and discuss secular trends, opportunities to innovate, and what is going right with the country&#39;s policies. After all, technological development is a rising tide that lifts all boats.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the week following BSV, Rio hosted &lt;a href=&quot;https://rio.websummit.com/&quot;>;Web Summit&lt;/a>; – a tech event that drew more than 20,000 attendees. Numerous key stakeholders have since gathered in NYC for events hosted by Itau, BTG, and Bank of America. I was lucky to attend Itau&#39;s Women Leaders in NY honoring &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ingridsilvaballet.com/&quot;>;Ingrid Silva&lt;/a>;. While an uptick in events doesn&#39;t necessarily equal a surge in innovation, it undeniably illustrates the escalating interest in Brazil as a premier global hub for tech development.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For great content about local and international tech events related to the Brazil entrepreneurial ecosystem, check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://substack.com/profile/38241540-julia-de-luca&quot;>;Julia de Luca&lt;/a>; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://abreu.substack.com/&quot;>;Lucas Abreu&lt;/a>;&#39;s newsletters.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And make plans now to join us at BSV next year, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.latitud.com/en/vamoslatamsummit&quot;>;Vamos Latam Summit&lt;/a>; in São Paulo, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brazilclimatesummit.com/&quot;>;Brazil Climate Summit&lt;/a>; in NYC.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With tons of admiration from a very Venezuelan VC.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Luisa&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;*Denotes Collab Portfolio Company&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 05 Jun 2023 16:46:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/brazil-at-silicon-valley/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/brazil-at-silicon-valley/</guid></item><item><title> Paying Attention</title><description> &lt;p>;Sherlock Holmes says in the book, &lt;em>;The Study of Scarlet&lt;/em>;:&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;I consider that a man&#39;s brain originally is like a little empty attic, and you have to stock it with such furniture as you choose. A fool takes in all the lumber of every sort that he comes across, so that the knowledge which might be useful to him gets crowded out, or at best is jumbled up with a lot of other things so that he has a difficulty in laying his hands.&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;This was written in 1887. Imagine how he&#39;d feel today – phone buzzing in his pocket, social media feeds gushing out useless information.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Deciding what to pay attention to is hard, overlooked, and most important, it&#39;s a negative skill – it&#39;s about what you willfully ignore as much as what you actively seek out.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Francis Crick, who discovered the double helix structure of DNA, was once asked what it takes to win the Nobel Prize. He responded: “Oh it&#39;s very simple. My secret had been I know what to ignore.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Author John Barry writes:&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;Einstein reportedly once said that his own major scientific talent was his ability to look at an enormous number of experiments and journal articles, select the very few that were both correct and important, ignore the rest, and build a theory on the right ones.&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;The best reading strategy I&#39;ve come across is the idea of &lt;a href=&quot;https://collabfund.com/blog/how-to-read-lots-of-inputs-and-a-strong-filter/&quot;>;a wide funnel and tight filter&lt;/a>;. Be willing to read anything that looks even a little interesting, but abandon it quickly and without mercy if it&#39;s not working for you.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Be choosy about what you let into your attic.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A few other things I&#39;ve found helpful in choosing what to pay attention to:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;When reading an article, book, or report, ask, “Will I still care about this in a year?”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Five years? Ten?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most of the time you&#39;ll realize you won&#39;t care about whatever you&#39;re reading in a week. It&#39;s newsy – maybe it&#39;s interesting, but it has an expiration date.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are two types of knowledge: Expiring and permanent.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Expiring knowledge is things like quarterly earnings, election polls, market information, and politics. It catches more attention than it should, for two reasons. One, there&#39;s a lot of it, eager to capture our short attention spans. Two, we chase it down, anxious to squeeze out insight before it loses relevance.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Permanent knowledge tends to be principles and frameworks that help you make sense of expiring information.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I read newspapers and books every day. I can not recall one thing I read in a newspaper from, say, 2011. But I can tell you details about a few great &lt;a href=&quot;https://collabfund.com/blog/23-books-that-changed-my-life/&quot;>;books I read in 2011 &lt;/a>;and how they changed how I think. I&#39;ll remember them forever. I&#39;ll keep reading newspapers. But if I read more books I&#39;d probably develop better filters and frameworks that would help me make better sense of the news.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Asking how long you&#39;ll care about the information you read pushes you to focus on permanent things and care little about temporary things – a great mindset for long-term thinking.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Memorize stories, highlight facts, skip the fluff&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There&#39;s a line I love: People don&#39;t remember books; they remember sentences.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More specifically, they remember stories.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even in the best book you&#39;ve ever read, what do you remember? A couple sentences, a few stories. Those sentences and stories might change your life, but they&#39;re all you&#39;ll take away from a book.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I try to remember that when reading. For nearly every blog post and most non-fiction books: there is no need to devour and focus on every word. If I can remember a few great stories and epic lines, it&#39;s a win.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Too many readers get too bogged down in details they&#39;re never going to remember anyways, when they could have pulled a few memorable lines out of a book and moved onto the next.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Pay close attention when someone you admire disagrees on a topic you&#39;re passionate about.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Charles Darwin, according to Charlie Munger, wasn&#39;t exceptionally bright, but became a first-class scientist because he spent his life trying to prove himself wrong. “One of the great things to learn from Darwin is the value of extreme objectivity,” Munger once said. “He tried to disconfirm his ideas as soon as he got &#39;em. He quickly wrote down in his notebook anything that disconfirmed a much-loved idea.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That is an amazing trick, and for most people the way to disconfirm your own beliefs is paying attention to people who disagree with you.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But that&#39;s hard, because it&#39;s so easy to assume those who disagree with you aren&#39;t as smart or informed as you are. A lot of good ideas are ignored, or intentionally rejected, because they are said by people you don&#39;t admire.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you&#39;re not blessed with perfect empathy, the trick to opening your mind to viewpoints you disagree with is to find people whose views on one topic you respect – that checks the box in your head that says “this person isn&#39;t crazy” – and listen to them about topics you disagree on.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When those two things align – a person you admire disagrees with you about something fundamental – pay close attention. There&#39;s a good chance this is information you&#39;ll want stored in your head.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 31 May 2023 16:28:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/paying-attention/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/paying-attention/</guid></item><item><title> Expectations Debt</title><description> &lt;p>;I live in Seattle, and Amazon is our giant. A third of my neighbors work for the company.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Amazon was on top of the world in 2021 – reputation gleaming, stock price booming – you could feel the pride and prosperity. You could practically smell it.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I once heard that 90% of culture is just “winning,” – when a company is winning, everyone&#39;s happy, rich, being promoted, and they see their work as contributing to something bigger than themselves.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That was Amazon in 2021.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Then Jeff Bezos left, the stock fell 50%, 10,000 employees were laid off, and hundreds of thousands more fear they&#39;re next.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;That&lt;/em>; is now the scent wafting around my neighborhood.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is so clear, so obvious, how the mood has shifted.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So here&#39;s the question: What do you call the top-of-the-world status Amazon had in 2021? Was it a gift? A reward for hard work? The natural swings of capitalism?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yes, all of those.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But there&#39;s another way to look at it: An expectations debt.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Expectations were so high in 2021 that investors and employees had to achieve extraordinary things just to break even. When results were merely good, they felt terrible.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Expectations are like a debt that must be repaid before you get any joy out of what you&#39;re doing.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The hard thing is that every company and every employee wants to have what Amazon had in 2021 – winning, wealth, prestige, reputation. But look at what it led to now, after the expectations debt was repaid.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Was it worth it? Hard to say.&lt;/p>; &lt;hr />; &lt;p>;The Nikkei – the Japanese stock market equivalent of the Dow Jones – recently closed at its highest level since 1990.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are two ways to look at that: As a win, or as an example of one of the worst-performing stock markets of modern times.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But here&#39;s what&#39;s most interesting about the Japanese stock market.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Returns over the last 33 years were terrible.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But returns from 1965 to 1990 were &lt;em>;extraordinary&lt;/em>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Nikkei and the S&amp;amp;P 500 have had very similar returns over the last 57 years.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/Screenshot%202023-05-25%20at%208.02.46%20AM.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot 2023-05-25 at 8.02.46 AM.png&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the Nikkei earned all of those returns during one massive 25-year surge, while the S&amp;amp;P 500 has been comparatively more even.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://collabfund.com/uploads/Screenshot%202023-05-25%20at%2010.21.50%20AM.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot 2023-05-25 at 10.21.50 AM.png&quot; />;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I don&#39;t think it&#39;s fair to say the Japanese stock market stagnated over the last 33 years. What really happened is that 50 years of returns were stuffed into a 25-year period in the late 20th century, and the past three decades of misery has just been repaying that excess.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Here again, high expectations in 1990 were like a debt that had to be repaid before investors could benefit.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No one got a statement for that debt; it didn&#39;t show up on anyone&#39;s balance sheet; no one knew what the interest rate would be. But it was very real debt that anchored investors down, destroyed wealth, and took a third of a century to pay down.&lt;/p>; &lt;hr />; &lt;p>;An asset you don&#39;t deserve can quickly become a liability.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Maybe your portfolio surged during a bubble, your company hit a monster valuation, or you negotiated a salary that exceeds your ability. It feels great at the time. But reality eventually catches up, and demands repayment in equal proportion to your delusions – plus interest.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These debts are easy to ignore because they are often repaid in the form of self-doubt and crushed morale. But they are very real, and when you understand their power you become careful what you wish for.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Companies should want the valuation they deserve, and not a penny more.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Workers should want a salary that matches their skill, and nothing more.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Families should want a lifestyle they can sustain, and nothing higher.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;None of those are about settling or giving up. It&#39;s about avoiding a certain kind of psychological debt that comes due when reality catches up.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There&#39;s a stoic saying: “Misfortune weighs most heavily on those who expect nothing but good fortune.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Expecting nothing but good feels like such a good mindset – you&#39;re optimistic, happy, and winning. But whether you know it or not you&#39;re very likely piling up a hidden debt that must eventually be repaid.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 25 May 2023 11:41:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/expectations-debt/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/expectations-debt/</guid></item><item><title> “Mars is for Quitters” —Sara Ledterman</title><description> &lt;p>;Joining Forces with Harvard University&#39;s Wyss Institute to Create Better Materials for Earth.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The goal of this alliance is to invent and commercialize the next great, worldchanging material – one that&#39;s as cheap, versatile, and high-performance as the last worldchanging discovery, plastic, but without the negative side effects. By leveraging synthetic biology, we plan to fuel sustainable options that surpass even Goretex in their efficacy and commercial success.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Developing new materials that are both better for our planet and better for consumers presents a massive economic and ecological opportunity. Yet, despite the incredible potential, there&#39;s been surprisingly little change in materials over the past several decades. Plastic, metal, wood, glass, and synthetic fibers comprise nearly everything we consume.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason? Fossil fuels. All of these materials rely on hydrocarbons for production and processing, which make them terrible for the environment, but also more accessible, cost effective, and difficult to replace.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While the field is still emerging, there are a few notable companies that have been at the forefront of commercializing sustainable materials using synthetic biology:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ginkgo Bioworks&lt;/strong>;: Ginkgo Bioworks designs and manufactures a variety of products, including flavors, fragrances, and materials.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Solugen&lt;/strong>;: Solugen produces sustainable chemicals, such as hydrogen peroxide and solvents, from plant-based sources. The company&#39;s technology platform uses enzymes and renewable feedstocks to create products that are more sustainable and cost-effective than their traditional petroleum-based counterparts.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zymergen&lt;/strong>;: Zymergen (acquired by Ginkgo) designs and manufactures novel materials, such as adhesives, coatings, and films, that are more sustainable and high-performing than their traditional counterparts.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These companies serve as a preview of the types of opportunities we anticipate emerging in the next decade and beyond. Synthetic biology is a rapidly emerging field that combines biology, engineering, and computer science to design and construct new biological systems. By harnessing the power of living organisms, synthetic biology has the potential to revolutionize the way we produce materials, food, and energy.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That&#39;s why we&#39;re teaming up with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://wyss.harvard.edu/&quot;>;Wyss Institute for Biologically Inspired Engineering at Harvard University&lt;/a>;. Established in 2009, the Wyss Institute is a world class R&amp;amp;D center focused on ground-breaking technologies that emulate nature. Together, we&#39;re excited to announce the launch of the &lt;strong>;Laboratory for Sustainable Materials Research and Innovation&lt;/strong>; to create new intellectual property (IP) and bring novel sustainable materials to the market. Our joint efforts will explore the development of biomimetic materials that replicate the properties of natural substances, as well as bio-based materials derived from renewable resources.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These materials hold the promise of reducing our reliance on fossil fuels, decreasing greenhouse gas emissions, and minimizing waste in production processes. Additionally, these innovations have the potential to create entirely new markets and disrupt existing ones, offering attractive financial returns for investors.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://wyss.harvard.edu/&quot;>;Wyss Institute&lt;/a>; is the perfect home for such an ambitious new lab. The Wyss Institute at Harvard University is a world leader in the field of biologically inspired engineering. By emulating nature&#39;s design principles, the Institute develops innovative solutions for a variety of industries, including healthcare, energy, and manufacturing. With its multidisciplinary approach and state-of-the-art facilities, the Wyss Institute is uniquely positioned to contribute its synthetic biology expertise to the partnership.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The consumer product goods (CPG) and heavy industries sectors are both major contributors to global greenhouse gas emissions and resource depletion. By investing in and commercializing sustainable materials, our partnership with the Wyss Institute aims to drive a paradigm shift in these industries.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We can&#39;t wait to update you on all the exciting technologies that will emerge from this pioneering alliance. Together, we believe Collab and the Wyss Institute will drive a new wave of materials innovation while establishing an exciting new model that accelerates the journey from scientific discovery to market realization by uniting academia and venture capital. This alliance aims to invest in and develop cutting-edge sustainable materials using synthetic biology, with the ultimate goal of generating outstanding financial returns and creating a far-reaching positive environmental impact in consumer product goods and heavy industries.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you&#39;re a visionary researcher, scientist, or entrepreneur pursuing innovative ideas in the realm of biomaterials, please reach out. We&#39;d love to hear from you and explore opportunities to collaborate towards a sustainable future.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;– Sophie and Craig&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;(PS We are excited about space and its potential, but are devoting our time and energy on solving problems for Earth)&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 23 May 2023 08:19:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/mars-is-for-quitters/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/mars-is-for-quitters/</guid></item><item><title> The Spectrum of Financial Dependence and Independence</title><description> &lt;p>;&lt;em>;“I did not intend to get rich. I just wanted to get independent.” – Munger&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Place yourself, your business, and other people you know, on this list.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Level 0: Complete financial dependence on the kindness of strangers who have no vested interest in your success&lt;/strong>;. Panhandling when unable to work, or companies reliant on raising money from first-time investors who don&#39;t care if you fail.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Level 1:&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;Complete financial dependence on people who want you to succeed because they like you and their reputation is attached to your success.&lt;/strong>; Children under age 15 – supported by their parents and generally too young to work – fall into this category. So do companies backed by friends and family who don&#39;t intend on getting their money back.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Level 2: Complete financial dependence on people with a vested interest in your financial outcome&lt;/strong>;. Unprofitable-but-promising businesses backed by investors who could earn a meaningful return on their investments, and are thus likely to keep supporting you.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Level 3: Ability to partially support yourself by&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;adding value for others while still somewhat reliant on external support&lt;/strong>;. Young people who work but rely on their parents to support what they consider basic lifestyle necessities. Or companies that could realistically be profitable if they changed their cost structure, but continue to raise money from investors to fund growth.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Level 4: Ability to fully support yourself by adding value for others, but value that is marginal and easy to replace&lt;/strong>;. This is a common category for both people and businesses. It is grinding and tenuous. It smells like independence, but a boss or customer still owns your day and can dictate your future. Your future relies on their decisions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Level 5:&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;Enough savings to cover run-of-the-mill problems&lt;/strong>;. You can endure hassles that every person or company should expect to experience on a regular basis, without getting wiped out.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Level 6: Enough savings to cover large, unforeseen problems&lt;/strong>;. You still rely on your boss or your customers to get by month to month, but if a crisis struck you&#39;d probably be OK for a reasonable period of time.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Level 7: Retirement savings, education savings, and avoidance of consumer and auto debt&lt;/strong>;. You still rely on bosses and customers, but you can foresee a time when your current savings will open up a new level of independence for you and your family. This is the most realistic goal for most people.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Level 8:&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;The ability to pick a job, or specific customers, that avoids the most egregious examples of bullshit and unnecessary hassle in your life.&lt;/strong>; You still rely on bosses and customers, but have the freedom to say, “No, not you. I&#39;ll find someone else,” when you get too frustrated.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Level 9:&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;Becoming comfortable enough with your social status that you don&#39;t feel the need to flash your peacock feathers with expensive consumer goods whose only value is in signaling&lt;/strong>;. The inability to do this is a hidden form of debt and dependence that exists, and it piles up on people who mistakenly think they&#39;re wealthy enough to be independent.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Level 10: The ability to say no to banks, whose debt you don&#39;t need, including mortgages.&lt;/strong>; Debt can be cheap capital but it keeps you beholden to others, owning a piece of your future decisions and cash-flow needs.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Level 11:&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;Few realistic situations would cause you, your company, or your family to be pushed back below Level 5.&lt;/strong>; You could support yourself for a year or more off your liquid savings. It&#39;s the first true stage of independence. You can now say “No” to almost anyone, with high odds of recovering from the repercussions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Level 12: Interest and dividends cover more than half of your living expenses&lt;/strong>;. Most of this independence is owed to a slim lifestyle, rather than huge assets. You realize that lifestyle desires compound faster than almost any asset.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Level 13: Your assets and their reasonable return expectations will cover basic living expenses for longer than your life expectancy&lt;/strong>;. Congrats. You are no longer reliant on bosses or clients. You can deal with them if you want, and you probably will. But only if you want, when you want, with who you want. Which feels good.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Level 14:&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;Your assets cover above-basic living expenses with assets and their reasonable return expectations&lt;/strong>;. You can define “above-basic” however you want. Varies by person. Remember what Chris Rock says: “If Bill Gates woke up with Oprah&#39;s money he&#39;d jump out the window.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Level 15:&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;Independence lets you do and say what you please, unconcerned with other people disagreeing with you&lt;/strong>;, since you don&#39;t rely on the support or opportunities they could offer.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Level 16:&lt;/strong>; Meaningful philanthropy is the only reasonable way your assets won&#39;t compound faster than you spend.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This, to me, is one of the most important topics in finance. Everyone&#39;s different. But while almost everyone can adapt to their stuff, having control over your time through independence will always feel great when you have it and always be a miserable burden when you don&#39;t.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 16 May 2023 03:49:00 -0400</pubDate><link/> https://collabfund.com/blog/the-spectrum-of-financial-dependence-and-independence/<guid ispermalink="true"> https://collabfund.com/blog/the-spectrum-of-financial-dependence-and-independence/</guid></item></channel></rss>